<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged mp3</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/mp3/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/mp3/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 05:58:59 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>A Wish: The Ability of Playing MP3 CDs/DVDs created by iTunes with Free Software</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>indexed-metadata</category>

	<category>library</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 20:34:09 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&#39;s iTunes has a very cool feature that I would like to have and that I
still have not yet noticed in any of the Linux music players (be them
rhythmbox, amarok, quodlibet, audacious etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feature is the following: Apple&#39;s iTunes player has the possibility of
playing CD-DA, with the information about the tracks (in computer jargon,
metadata) taken from on-line databases like Gracenote&#39;s CDDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software that I use doesn&#39;t have problems with this, at least
regarding audio CDs. They check some free on-line databases (like gnudb.org
or freedb.org, which, by the way, have CDs in their catalog that aren&#39;t
available in the commercial CDDB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the nicest feature that iTunes has is the ability to burn MP3/AAC CDs
taken from playlists composed by the user, neatly organized in a filesystem
structure of the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;artist&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;album&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;song&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also generates an XML file with the contents of the MP3 CD in a way that
makes it playable just like a CD-DA, but with remarkable characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it doesn&#39;t need a connection to the Internet to grab metadata (which is,
of course, stored both in the XML file and in some file&#39;s metadata). This
means that no network connection is necessary to have information about
songs and the XML file acts like a cache to avoid the program reading the
whole CD to show the information in a user-friendly fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MP3 CD is treated like a CD-DA, but with a much longer capacity (say,
12 hours, depending on the bitrate of the songs and their lengths).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the songs don&#39;t have to be imported into playlists and not even queued for
playing. Just selecting the first song to be played is enough for it to
start plaing things (and, of course, it is not always that we want to
import songs to our library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think that this would be a great thing for the GNOME
Desktop (and for others too), since it would increase the interoperability
with other Operating Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only iTunes can create such CDs, but it can also create DVDs containing
MP3/AAC files, which, of course, means that the capacity of such &quot;CDs&quot; is
huge compared to that of usual audio CDs and it is also a convenient way to
carry the discs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience and workflow, it would be really nice to be able to play
such CDs/DVDs with rhythmbox/amarok/quodlibet, as it would represent both a
handy feature and a nice interoperability factor (and convenience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of Free Software players, more formats could be considered, of
course, than just MP3 and Low Complexity AAC. Vorbis, Speex, MP2, AC-3 and
other less-known formats would be possible (well, even Window&#39;s WMA files,
as they are playable by a lot of set-top boxes and car players).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, in addition to playing such CDs/DVDs, those programs could also create
such CDs (say, by passing the responsibility to another program), then
everything would be a dream come true and many other friends of mine would
be one step further from being tied to Mac OS X or Windows and closer to
Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this shows to be an improvement for the Free Software Desktop
environments like GNOME and KDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: The same thing applies to Photo CDs created by iPhoto. It would be
really exciting to have them be recognized by F-Spot or other similar Photo
organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-07-20</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-20/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-20/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T08:58:59Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Just discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com/&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt; (or would it be
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roadrunnerrecords.com/&quot;&gt;Roadrunner Records&lt;/a&gt;?) has
released a version of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watershed_(Opeth_album)&quot;&gt;Watershed with extra tracks and with a DVD documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
They have also released another special version that has
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cKx5zrb0Z_0&quot;&gt;Porcelain Heart&lt;/a&gt;
played with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mellotron&quot;&gt;Mellotron&lt;/a&gt;
(which brings orgasms to all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_rock&quot;&gt;progressive rock&lt;/a&gt;
fans, like myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also got my parents to sit in front of my old, trusty
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duron&quot;&gt;Duron&lt;/a&gt;-based &lt;code&gt;dumont&lt;/code&gt; (in
honor of Brazilian pioneer
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santos_Dumont&quot;&gt;Alberto Santos-Dumont&lt;/a&gt;).
It is interesting to note that, while the Level 2
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CPU_cache&quot;&gt;cache&lt;/a&gt; of the Duron system
is small for a low-cost processor (in reference to its rival
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celeron&quot;&gt;Celeron&lt;/a&gt; processor, that had
a bigger Level 2 cache), it has a much bigger
(128&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KiB&quot;&gt;KiB&lt;/a&gt;) Level 1 cache than
what I have in a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentium_D&quot;&gt;Pentium D&lt;/a&gt; machine: only
16KB for each core (at least for data; that&#39;s what my &lt;code&gt;dmesg&lt;/code&gt;
says). Surprising to say the least. And this explains why
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AMD&quot;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; stood on the front of the
race during the Athlon (Thunderbird) days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding other architectures (I have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerPC&quot;&gt;PowerPC&lt;/a&gt; in mind here), I&#39;m
not especially happy with them: my
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerPC_G3&quot;&gt;PowerPC G3&lt;/a&gt; lacks
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_processor&quot;&gt;vector instructions&lt;/a&gt;,
which means that playing multimedia files (read: movies) is
something painful. The problem is that I &lt;strong&gt;quite&lt;/strong&gt; like the iBook&#39;s
form factor and I have not yet seen anything that matches it yet.
Comments are welcome here. Yes, it seems that I am not alone here,
given all the frenziness about the surge of netbook computers, like
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASUS_Eee_PC&quot;&gt;Eee PC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I setup my old sound gear on what is my main (desktop)
computer. It is nice to have a good sound whenever I am working
(well, whenever I am working lightly, as I need sound to be absent
when I&#39;m working hard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, BTW, just found a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vindaci.members.sonic.net/cbreak/projects/autotools/&quot;&gt;superb autotools tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
that starts with the egregious &lt;code&gt;&quot;Hello, World!&quot;&lt;/code&gt; application. This
is a perfect point for reading more advanced documents on this
matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-07-19</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-19/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-19/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T08:57:55Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Have been
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/lame/lame/doc/html/history.html?revision=HEAD&quot;&gt;working quite a bit&lt;/a&gt;
on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; project to have the best MP3
encoder around. It&#39;s been all a learning exercise dealing with all
the magic behind
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lrde.epita.fr/~adl/autotools.html&quot;&gt;autotools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there are some areas where we can fix with just a
working knowledge of C and computer architecture, like fixing the
interface to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Sound_System&quot;&gt;Open Sound System&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ABX_test&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;abx&lt;/code&gt; tool&lt;/a&gt; that comes with
lame (in the &lt;code&gt;misc&lt;/code&gt; directory), as well as the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endianness&quot;&gt;endianness&lt;/a&gt; problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-07-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-04/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T08:57:19Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME 3.98 final&lt;/a&gt; was released.
Unfortunately, I missed the boat and didn&#39;t commit all the changes
that I had, but I will continue working on it nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-05-23</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-23/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-23/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T08:56:47Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Gave a second talk to the group of &quot;Error Correcting Codes&quot;. This
time, I carried my &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S1MP3&quot;&gt;S1MP3&lt;/a&gt;
player/recorder and recorded the talk. The nice thing is that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; with libsndfile1 can read those files
directly, without any kind of conversion first, which automates
things quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the seminar, I talked about algorithm invariants, how to
discover them, how close to mathematical induction they are, gave
examples of some programs, described the bubble sort algorithm in
our native/high level language, talked about its stability, talked
about its invariant, talked about its time and space complexity,
remarked that the algorithm works on any totally ordered set and,
finally, to answer a question from the audience, talked about the
limited precision of &quot;integers&quot; that we use on computers and
multiprecision libraries used to hold values as large as we
please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was also dad&#39;s birthday! Hippie!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-05-17</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-17/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T08:52:01Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dreamtheater.net/&quot;&gt;Dream Theater&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ytsejamrecords.com/&quot;&gt;Official Bootlegs&lt;/a&gt; (and some of
their regular releases), I can&#39;t fail to notice that they have the
2.0 Stereo part as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LPCM&quot;&gt;LPCM&lt;/a&gt; audio.
Sometimes, these streams are in 24 bits. I would like to convert
them to WAV files so that I can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; to
get the recordings on my portable digital music player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this effect, I spent some moments coding a program that I called
&lt;code&gt;lpcm2wav&lt;/code&gt; that takes a raw input of an LPCM audio from a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DVD&quot;&gt;DVD&lt;/a&gt; video disc and outputs a
WAV file suiltable for compression (in 48kHz, normally).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
