<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged hardware</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/hardware/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/hardware/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 03:17:08 -0200</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Some activities of the day</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-06_random_notes/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-06_random_notes/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>parenting</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 22:52:59 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-10T05:17:08Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I printed the first draft of the first chapter when my little boy
was here and he was impressed with this strange object called a &quot;printer&quot;.
Before I printed what I needed, I fired up LibreOffice and chose the biggest
font size that was available and let him type his first name by himself.
He was quicker than I thought with a keyboard. After seeing me print his
first name, he was jumping up and down with joy of having created something
and even showed grandma and grandpa what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, then, wanted more and I taught him how to use that backspace key, what
it meant and he wanted to type his full name. I let him and taught him that
there is a key called space that he should type every time he wants to start
a new word and, in the end, he typed his first two names. To my surprise, he
memorized the icon with the printer (which I must say that I have to hunt
every time, since it seems so similar to the adjacent ones!) and pressed
this new key called &quot;Enter&quot;. When he pressed, he wasn&#39;t expecting the
printer on his right to start making noises and printing his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was so excited and it was so nice to see his reaction full of joy to get
a job done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of getting a spare computer, building it with him and for him,
so that he can call it his computer every time he comes to see daddy. As a
serendipitous situation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/&quot;&gt;Packt Publishing&lt;/a&gt; offered yesterday their
title &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/application-development/python-projects-kids&quot;&gt;&quot;Python Projects for Kids&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, he does
not yet know how to read, but I guess that the right age is coming soon,
which is a good thing to make him be educated &quot;the right way&quot; (that is, with
the best support, teaching and patience that I can give him).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I printed the first draft of the first chapter and today I have to
turn it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I am &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/tools/vms/&quot;&gt;downloading a virtual machine from Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; to
try to install Java on it. Let me see if it works. I have none of the
virtualization options used, tough the closest seems to be virtualbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me cross my fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I updated some of the tags of very old posts of this blog,
and I am seriously thinking about switching from [ikiwiki][0] to another
blog platform. It is &lt;em&gt;slow&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;very slow&lt;/em&gt; on my system with the repositories
that I have, especially on my armel system. Some non-interpreted system
would be best, but I don&#39;t know if such a thing even exists. But the killer
problem is that it doesn&#39;t support easily the typing of Mathematics (even
though a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bk/ikiwiki-plugin-mathjax&quot;&gt;3rd party plugin&lt;/a&gt; for MathJax exists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I just received &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/telegram/status/927470283094499329&quot;&gt;an answer on twitter&lt;/a&gt; from @telegram and
it was nice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello, Telegram supports bold and italic. You can type &lt;code&gt;**bold**&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;__italic__&lt;/code&gt;. On mobile, you can also highlight text for this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is nice that this works with &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/telegram-desktop&quot;&gt;telegram-desktop&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I filed some bugs on Debian&#39;s BTS, responded to some issues on
my projects on GitHub (I&#39;m slowly getting back on maintaining things) and
file &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bk/ikiwiki-plugin-mathjax/issues/3&quot;&gt;wishlist bugs on some other projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I grabbed a copy of &quot;Wonder woman&quot; (&quot;Mulher Maravilha&quot;) and
&quot;Despicable Me 3&quot; (&quot;Meu Malvado Favorito 3&quot;) dubbed in Brazilian Portuguese
for my son. I have to convert the audio from AAC-LC in 6 channels to AC3 or
to stereo. Otherwise, my TVs have problem with the videos (one refuses to
play the entire file and another plays the audio with sounds of hiccups).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; After converting the VirtualBox image taken from Microsoft, I
could easily use &lt;code&gt;qemu&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;kvm&lt;/code&gt; to create screenshots of the installation of
Java.  The command that I used (for future reference) is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
qemu-system-x86_64 -enable-kvm -m 4096 -smp 2 -net nic,model=e1000 -net user -soundhw ac97 -drive index=0,media=disk,cache=unsafe,file=win7.qcow2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed some typos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-05-01</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-01/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-01/</link>



	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-06T07:17:39Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Got myself a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WSXGA+&quot;&gt;WSXGA+&lt;/a&gt; 22
inches LCD monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-04-30</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-30/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-30/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-06T07:16:54Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Upgraded my parent&#39;s computer from
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Feisty (7.10) to Hardy (8.04).
Now, some of the things that I&#39;m used to when using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s sid are available on their
computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I can&#39;t avoid to use this opportunity to complain once more
about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flash.net.br/&quot;&gt;ISP&lt;/a&gt;. If I weren&#39;t doing the
upgrade &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; early in the morning, I wouldn&#39;t have success,
as I am (right now), without signal from them. These outages are
getting on my nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some math related news, I finally saw a proof of the intuitive
fact the determinant of a 2x2 matrix is the signed area of the
parallelogram with vectors given by the column vectors of the
matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my D-Link G122 (I think that that&#39;s the model) doesn&#39;t work
with the &lt;code&gt;rt2500usb&lt;/code&gt; driver that ships with the distribution: I can
see that &lt;code&gt;iwconfig&lt;/code&gt; lists &lt;code&gt;wlan0&lt;/code&gt; as having wireless extensions, I
can set the device, it can see the access point, I can enter the
WEP key, but it doesn&#39;t seem to get a DHCP lease from the router.
&lt;code&gt;:-(&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2007-01-19</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2007-01-19/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2007-01-19/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-06T07:07:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that my 160GB IDE HD is back to life. I will check it
again, but the &quot;magic&quot; was to just write data on it, causing it to
remap the defective blocks. Thank you for the engineers that know
that machines &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I tried to get oggenc-aotuv compiled for amd64. The package is
in a sad state, unfortunately, and even after I changed the sources
a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-09-16</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-09-16/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-09-16/</link>



	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-06T06:56:25Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Some tools related to digital photography:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 2GB SD card, which at the maximum resolution that I&#39;m using
with the camera that I have here, gives me around 4500 photos;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small tripod, so that I can play with photos with a &quot;fill
flash&quot; or completely without flash and without getting the images
blurry;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An adaptor to the SD card so that it can be used just like an
USB pen/thumb/whatever-drive;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two pairs of rechargeable AAA batteries;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A battery recharger;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The smallest (in physical terms) USB pen/thumb/whatever-drive
that I could get, with 1GB of size. Nice for getting things along
with me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-03-30</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-30/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-30/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-07-14T18:26:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been (re-)discovering multimedia and all its wonders. It all
started with me seeing how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macmini/frontrow.html&quot;&gt;Front Row&lt;/a&gt; application
works. Ok, so I am behind the times. I&#39;m fine with that, but
catching up. The world is changing sooooo fast that it is hard to
keep up. Podcasts, wireless networks, media centers, digital video,
digital (still) cameras, megapixels and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add to that the things that &quot;need to be known&quot; by a Computer
Scientist/Mathematician-wannabe and we quickly arrive at the
conclusion that the days are way too short with their current 24
hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It, unfortunately, sucks and the fact that Apple is now &quot;changing
gears&quot; to support their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intel.com/&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macmini/intelcore.html&quot;&gt;Core&lt;/a&gt; processors is a
clear signal that their PowerPC line is dead and only waiting for
its coffin to be burried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the solution to this problem is? Partially, to employ Open
Source technology to leverage this to current standards, using
hardware that is already employed. We can &lt;em&gt;hardly&lt;/em&gt;, expect the new
machines to outnumber the installed resources that we already have.
And have to keep working.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-03-16</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-16/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-16/</link>



	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-07-14T18:26:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I resurrected Loreena McKennitt&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mask_and_Mirror&quot;&gt;&quot;The Mask and Mirror&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
and it now plays without skipping in any place. It&#39;s so nice to
have it &quot;back&quot;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m slowly progressing towards a better condition of my throat.
This is taking longer than what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally took some time to go to the police station to register the
damage done to my car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I got some new toys to play with, including a brand new
Firewire enclosure, wireless stuff and some DVD-R&#39;s. Fun ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-02-26</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-26/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-26/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-07-14T18:26:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Playing with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imagemagick.org/&quot;&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/a&gt;, I
discovered that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samsungcamera.org/&quot;&gt;camera&lt;/a&gt; saves
the pictures with &quot;quality&quot; settings of 95%, 85%, and 70% when
using &quot;super fine&quot;, &quot;fine&quot;, and &quot;normal&quot; settings for compression,
respectively. This answers one of the questions that I had in mind
when I started using this camera. Now, the other one is &quot;which
resolution to use?&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-02-24</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-24/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-24/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>photography</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-07-14T18:26:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Still trying to learn about digital photography. The subject is
fascinating. Too bad that I lack subjects to take pictures from,
but I guess that this is where the &quot;artistic&quot; part comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the is also the &quot;science&quot; part of the thing, which is
where the knowledge comes in: choosing exposure, knowing what
lenses you should (or should not) use, seeing the appropriate flash
light settings etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, many things are written in market-speak and it is
almost impenetrable for a layman to know exactly what is being
talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I upgraded
&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.matrox.com/pub/mga/archive/bios/2005/setup_258.exe&quot;&gt;the firmware&lt;/a&gt;
of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.matrox.com/&quot;&gt;Matrox&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.matrox.com/mga/support/user_manuals/mill_g400/home.cfm&quot;&gt;G400&lt;/a&gt;
card to version 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I didn&#39;t know why my students were all excited to go home until
I realized that today was the first day of 2006&#39;s carnival.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-06-06</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-06/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-06/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-06-11T14:03:17Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Holy freaking day! Today we had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2005/jun/06intel.html&quot;&gt;the announcement&lt;/a&gt;
that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; will be switching to
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intel.com&quot;&gt;Intel processors&lt;/a&gt;. This is a major movement,
in my very humber opinion. Does this mean that all the claims about
PowerPC being more effective are not true anymore (well, that may
be the case with Power 970 processors, but G3 processors seem to be
quite nice regarding power comsumption).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if that weren&#39;t enough news for one day,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; finally, after almost 3 (&lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt;)
years,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/News/2005/20050606&quot;&gt;released a new version of its distribution&lt;/a&gt;,
codenamed sarge. This is the major news for the day (and for the
month, if you ask me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And like if that weren&#39;t enough, Linus Torvalds also
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/pub/linux/kernel/v2.6/testing/patch-2.6.12-rc6.bz2&quot;&gt;announced kernel 2.6.12-rc6&lt;/a&gt;,
which is (hopefully) one of the final stages towards kernel 2.6.12
proper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
