<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged hardware</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/hardware/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>2002-01-01</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-01-01/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-01-01/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>macos</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:22:51Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, some progress on the PPC front. I&#39;ve just configured the PMac
to use the &lt;code&gt;imstt&lt;/code&gt; driver instead of the &lt;code&gt;fbdev&lt;/code&gt;. Due to this, the
X server is now &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster. In fact, the whole computer is much
faster. Before, it spent a lot of processing power just to update
the screen. Since it is not exactly the most powerful computer in
the world, those few moments indeed were important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very fast and now it is almost able to play AVI files with
MPlayer. Almost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Mac is now very usable and I&#39;d even dare to say that it would
be a good workstation, were it not that outdated (well, if one
could find replacement hardware for it easily...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&#39;ll end summarizing all the &quot;Mac Journey&quot; in a homepage
to save future souls enduring the problems that I&#39;ve experienced
(kernel configuration file, XF86Config file etc). It seems that
Linux running on PPC is indeed a quite nice alternative to paying
huge prices just for being able to run MacOS 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also installed the superb
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mosfet.org/liquid.html&quot;&gt;Liquid Theme&lt;/a&gt; for KDE2. It&#39;s
amazingly beautiful and quite fast, despite all the eye-candy. It
makes your Linux desktop seem like you are running
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&#39;s Acqua&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the down side of things, I guess that I&#39;m just encountering many
aspects of Perl that I don&#39;t like. It&#39;s saddening that I&#39;ve spent
so much time and money (buying books) for something that I&#39;m not
really enjoying (but it&#39;s ok).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-12-29</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-29/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-29/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:21:44Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally got the Power Macintosh 9500/180MP with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian testing&lt;/a&gt; installed in a semi-decent
way: I&#39;m using BenH&#39;s 2.4.17-ben0 kernel which finally has the mace
driver working again. What does this mean? Well, it means that I&#39;m
now not confined to 2.2.x kernels anymore. A 2.4 kernel has many
advantages, especially, for the PowerPC platform. Among other
things, they are faster for the same hardware, have good SMP
support, the IMSTT pci card is recognized (which wasn&#39;t in the 2.2
kernels) and a lot of other nice goodies like a journalling
filesystem (ext3) etc.
Also got &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mp3dev.org/mp3/&quot;&gt;lame 3.90.1&lt;/a&gt; compiled for the
PowerPC in a decent way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A collateral effect of having lame compiled for the ppc is that now
I have a have a good benchmark that shows me roughly how much
slower this thing is in relation to my Duron 600MHz. The sad news:
it is 5 or 6 times slower than the Duron. If lame were
multithreaded, then it could be up to 2.5 times slower, which would
be acceptable for day-to-day use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, got some work done to make the Debian packaging
scripts a bit nicer (read: closer to being lintian clean).
Unfortunately, lintian still complains about the shared library
package having an rpath and I don&#39;t know how to get rid of that
(not even a kludgy solution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;http://mplayer.sf.net&quot;&gt;MPlayer&lt;/a&gt; released another version
(0.60pre2), I downloaded the sources and, to my surprise, it
compiles on PPC (the 0.60pre1 didn&#39;t). And it even plays, errr,
tries to play DivX movies! Amazing job these guys are
accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After struggling a lot with the configuration files, also got X
4.1.0 working on a framebuffer device (the imstt driver doesn&#39;t
work). So, now I even have a reasonably fast, modest GUI working
(or a slower GUI if I load &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 2&lt;/a&gt;). And I can
even use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; here, although the
swapping doesn&#39;t make it a pleasant experience. In this respect,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com/&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;, while non-free, is much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this can now be a poor&#39;s man desktop machine. If it
only consumed power proportional to its speed, it would be nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-18</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-18/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:11:53Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, I know I messed up. My girlfriend told me that we were in July,
not June. What a shame! Anyway, I&#39;ve corrected my diary entries and
got things straight (I think). I guess that the problem was that
both months start with a &quot;J&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to the next (and final?) chapter on the mac: I returned it to
my uncle and set up the other mac on his store just to see if I
could get Debian installed. Well, I kind of could: I got the
bootfloppies installed in 1GB HD and was very surprised to see an
almost entire setup with the network. Amazing. I&#39;m almost without
words: just grab 4 FDs and install a whole operating system in your
machine with them. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; definitely keeps
its lead over other distributions this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, enough ads. I could get almost everything installed, but the
HD died (for good?) soon after the packages were being extracted
onto the new filesystem. I tried the other (4GB) HD, but it wasn&#39;t
being seen by &lt;code&gt;mac-fdisk&lt;/code&gt; for an unknown reason (despite it being
recognized during the SCSI bus scan and the partition check).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I guess that I can consider this as my first installation of
Linux on a PowerPC architecture, which could not be concluded only
because the hardware didn&#39;t help, but both the operator (that&#39;s me!
&amp;lt;grin&gt;) and the software were right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watched &quot;Monty Python&#39;s Life of Brian&quot; after that. Sent both my VCR
and TV set to the technician. For some strange reason, both
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konqueror.org&quot;&gt;Konqueror&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; are not rendering this page
justified, while &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netscape.com&quot;&gt;Netscape 4.77&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org&quot;&gt;Mozilla 0.9.2&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com&quot;&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt; are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-17</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-17/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:10:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the day that shouldn&#39;t have happened --- it was bad right
from start. First of all, I couldn&#39;t sleep well because I dreamt
with some perl scripts that didn&#39;t work and they took me almost all
my sleep time (or so it seemed). Then, my kind neighbor started
making lots of noises and I couldn&#39;t keep sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the worst part of the day was still coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to my uncle&#39;s shop to get a new SCSI HD and he lent me a 4GB
one, more than enough to hold both Linux and MacOS 8. I turned the
thing on and it started making noises like the one I used
yesterday, which wasn&#39;t good. Anyway, I left it on and decided to
install MacOS on it. It was progressing nicely and I was getting
happier and happier, but then the whole system froze. I turned the
power off and tried to install Linux. At least this time Linux saw
the HD and all partitions that it had (7, I think).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Linux, I used some CVS bootfloppies that will become
bootfloppies of Debian woody. While trying to make the brand new
ext2 filesystem, I got a kernel panic. I tried again. This time, I
went up to the point of choosing which kernel modules I wanted. I
was getting happy again. But then, when I chose the module for the
ethernet card, a new kernel panic. Ouch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then tried to install MacOS again and a new freeze. Tried again,
new freeze. Then, I noticed that the HD was getting hot and put a
fan near it. I don&#39;t know if it was coincidence or not, but after
that, I could finish the installation of MacOS. Ok, so time to boot
this thing with no CDs in the CD-ROM drive. Nothing. Grrrr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things got strange after I tried to put the Linux PPC CD that I had
burned and it didn&#39;t work. Washed the CD and no boot. But it did
some days ago! It was not scratched, had no fingerprints and was
absolutely clean. But couldn&#39;t boot. I tried using the floppies
again, but this time, another surprise: the HD &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; recognized,
but a partition scan timed out, Linux told that it could not read
read its beginning and that it assumed that the size of the HD was
1GB, and showed &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; partitions on the drive. On the other hand,
MacOS is able to see it just before formatting it, perhaps because
it re-scans the SCSI bus. Changing the SCSI-id of the drive didn&#39;t
help. Is that the reason why it can&#39;t boot from the HD? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my desire of seeing this thing encoding MP3s, using KDE, a
brand new browser and typing some texts with LaTeX seems a bit
farther than what I realized at first. I will still keep trying to
make this damn thing work, but I&#39;m not confident anymore that I&#39;ll
succeed. Well, I&#39;ll talk to my uncle tomorrow, perhaps and see if
the other Mac behaves the same way. Enough for a day already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-11</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-11/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-11/</link>


	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>macos</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:21:05Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Some weeks ago, my uncle that sells and fixes computers,
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:startmicro@uol.com.br&quot;&gt;Isaac&lt;/a&gt;, got a pair of old
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.info.apple.com/applespec/applespec.taf?RID=204&quot;&gt;Power Macintosh 9500/180MP&lt;/a&gt;
from a customer. His customer said that if he fixed one of them,
the other would be his as payment. So he kind of fixed one of them
and lent me the other, which means that I&#39;m now going to play with
both
&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.info.apple.com/Apple_Support_Area/Apple_Software_Updates/English-North_American/Macintosh/System/Mac_OS_8.1_Update/&quot;&gt;MacOS 8.0&lt;/a&gt;
and a Unix-like OS with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came with two PowerPC 604e processors of 180MHz (or so the specs
say), 64MB of RAM (where am I going to get more of it?), an
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com&quot;&gt;ATI&lt;/a&gt; graphics card with 2MB of memory, and a
4-speed CD-ROM. It features two SCSI interfaces, an Ethernet
adapter, a MacOS 8.0 CD, a keyboard and the (in)famous 1-button
mouse from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the first dual-head machine over which I am able to get my
greasy pawls. As welcome additionals, it is also the first time I
get to play with a non-x86 machine in a System Administrator
position (of course, I also use Solaris 2.x with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/&quot;&gt;my University&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; workstations, but that
doesn&#39;t count, since I&#39;m just a luser there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PowerPC machines are actually quite different from their ix86
counterparts. First of all, they don&#39;t have a BIOS setup, but you
can interface with the hardware before any Operating System gets
loaded with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://playground.sun.com/1275/home.html&quot;&gt;Open Firmware&lt;/a&gt;, which is
written in FORTH. You should be able to get into OF pressing
Command-Option-O-F while the machine chimes, or right after it
chimes. But, to be honest, I still couldn&#39;t see the damned OF
prompt, despite my numerous attempts and ways of pressing the
combination of keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the first task to make it work would, obviously, be to
install MacOS 8.0 on this machine. Well, this sounds great, but my
experience with it is a tiny bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first of the problems is that the machine doesn&#39;t boot while
the HD is connected to it. Weird, huh? I agree. If, on the other
hand, I disconnect the machine, put the MacOS CD on the CD drive,
let MacOS start loading and &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; plug the power connector
on the HD, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; the machine will boot MacOS and see the HD,
partition it and I am able to install MacOS on it. But on the next
reboot, I am not able to get things working without disconnecting
the power of the HD again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conformed to be working with the machine this way, I downloaded a
huge load of ISO images for it, including the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netbsd.org/Ports/macppc/&quot;&gt;NetBSD port for PPC&lt;/a&gt;, the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/ports/powerpc/&quot;&gt;Debian 2.2r3 port for PPC&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxppc.org&quot;&gt;LinuxPPC 2000 Q4&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yellowdoglinux.com&quot;&gt;Yellow Dog Linux 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. I made sure
the images I downloaded all had the right MD5SUMs and even used
rsync on the images after I had downloaded them, just to make sure
everything got alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, of all those images, the only one that booted on the Apple
was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxppc.org&quot;&gt;LinuxPPC 2000 Q4 image&lt;/a&gt;, which
was quite frustrating. The Debian CDs that I burned (I burned two:
one from a US site and another with non-US programs) didn&#39;t even
boot, including boot floppies generated from them -- quite a shame,
since that is, by far, my preferred operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to LinuxPPC. Seeing the machine boot with a
framebuffer with that little penguin holding a mug of beer and
telling me many things about the hardware that I didn&#39;t even know
is actually quite refreshing (no pun intended). After the kernel
boots, an X installer is started, a little menu appears and
things... ...STOP! That&#39;s right. After investigating a bit, I
discovered that programs are segfaulting consistenly in a reboot,
but in different reboots, the applications that segfault are not
necessarily the same that segfaulted in previous reboots. This may
be a hint that its memory is not OK, although I&#39;m not so sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I subscribed to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/#debian-powerpc&quot;&gt;Debian PowerPC mailing list&lt;/a&gt;
and I have been following it daily, learning a lot of things about
PPC in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My faith is restored now that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://penguinppc.org/~eb/&quot;&gt;Ethan Benson&lt;/a&gt; has posted CVS-snapshots
of the woody boot floppies on his page &lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt;, with them, I &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt;
boot my machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have those problems with the HD, although its days are
counted on this machine: I&#39;ll be soon getting a 2GB SCSI HD for it
(I hope!), so that I can continue my journey of installing Debian
potato/woody (or any other operating system!) on this machine. I
can&#39;t wait to have the beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 2.2&lt;/a&gt;,
the highly anticipated &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; and the
amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qmail.org/&quot;&gt;qmail&lt;/a&gt; running on this machine
(things that this machine designers never dreamt of running on this
old machine).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-05-18</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-05-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-05-18/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:19:51Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a long time since I last updated my diary. Let&#39;s see if I
can get things up to date (and let me see if I can keep me
organized and productive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the day started quite a bit messy: my computer, for some
reason, didn&#39;t want to turn on. It was beeping with my monitor
telling me to check the signal cable. &quot;Humm... Time to buy another
graphics card&quot; (and just the thought of having to choose from among
one less manufacturer of video cards scared me). I checked my
mainboard manual and it confirmed that the beeps I heard were
indeed problems with my graphics card (it&#39;s obvious that I didn&#39;t
want to believe the unfortunate situation of buying another card).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to use my computer anyway, I just removed my card from its
slot, and installed it again. Luckily, things started working
again. Whew! That was close! Anyway, I&#39;m now watching this card
closely. Very closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learned how to set up cookies with CGI scripts. Found out about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.recipesource.com/&quot;&gt;an site with recipes (for cooking)&lt;/a&gt;
while having my daily dose of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slashdot.org/&quot;&gt;Slashdot.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps due to lousy system administrators,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iname.com/&quot;&gt;Iname&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mail.com/&quot;&gt;Mail.com&lt;/a&gt; is
not delivering my e-mails. AGAIN. Enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, I have to finish a take home exam on Approximation
Algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-03-10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-03-10/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-03-10/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>health</category>

	<category>kde</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>network</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:18:54Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t do many important things today, besides making a brand new
installation of Debian&#39;s sid/unstable to see how things were going
with the bleeding edge. It turned out to be better than I expected
(I had some problems experiencing unstable before, so I was
scared).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the nicest things are that it features XFree86 4.0.2 (with
the RENDER extension, since I have a Matrox G400) and that, coupled
with KDE 2.1/qt 2.3.0, makes it possible to use antialised fonts,
which make one&#39;s surfing experience much more pleasing, for
instance. If you are on the same boat, don&#39;t forget to visit
&lt;a href=&quot;http://keithp.com/~keithp/&quot;&gt;Keith Packard&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, as it
features a handy
&lt;a href=&quot;http://keithp.com/~keithp/fonts/XftConfig&quot;&gt;XftConfig file&lt;/a&gt;. The
only lowpoint of KDE with antialiasing is that if AA is enabled,
then you loose non-scalable fonts with KDE applications, which
means that you can&#39;t make konsole use a 10x20 fixed font anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt;, KDE 2.1 allows one
to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windowmaker.org/&quot;&gt;Windowmaker&lt;/a&gt; Dock
Applications, and this is a very welcome thing as I love wmifs. The
more I use KDE, the more I&#39;m impressed with it, in many respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managed also to find some sites explaining Androgenetic Alopecia
and which are potential treatments for it. Frankly, I&#39;d love to not
have to surf these sites... And keeping with the surfing thing,
found a remarkable program called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vtun.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;vtun&lt;/a&gt;, for setting up encrypted
TCP/IP tunnels. Handy for WANs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&#39;m keeping reading about Multiple Sequence Alignment, which is
getting more exciting day after day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-01-31</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-01-31/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-01-31/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-20T01:06:20Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Millennium! So many things have happened since the last
time I&#39;ve updated my diary and I guess that since I can&#39;t summarize
everything accurately, I&#39;ll just list what I think are the
remarkable facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have now put my new computer (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amd.com&quot;&gt;Duron&lt;/a&gt;
600MHz with a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asus.com&quot;&gt;Asus&lt;/a&gt; A7V motherboard)
to actual use. Of course, I made a backup of my older computer, so
that I was prepared for worst (read on);
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;Linux 2.4.0&lt;/a&gt; has finally been released and
it includes a lot of new goodies. While I think that it is still
not the right time to switch to the new version, it is indeed quite
tempting (but I&#39;ll resist that temptation, since I&#39;ve read a lot of
people complaining of data corruption with the new IDE drivers when
used with VIA chipsets -- and my motherboard features, guess what,
a VIA chipset, of course).
At the time of this writing (Feb 4th), Linux 2.4.1 was already
released, with many minor fixes;
A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing&quot;&gt;new version&lt;/a&gt; of the
Linux Distribution that I use,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org&quot;&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt; is now getting more and
more functionality. It is ready for the new Linux 2.4.0 kernel, but
still under development (read: prone to break). Oh, why can&#39;t new
software be stable? In the mean time, I&#39;m using Debian&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/potato&quot;&gt;potato&lt;/a&gt;.
One week after I have started to use my new computer, my 40GB
Samsung drive broke. Ouch. Fortunately, I had taken backups of
everything from my old computer and any new data that I had on my
new computer was still readable. So, now, I&#39;m using a new 30GB
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quantum.com&quot;&gt;Quantum&lt;/a&gt; drive and everything seems to be
working fine again. Nice.
I am now reading more and more things about my Mastership work. It
will be in a sub-area of computer science called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/hardware/../compbio/index.html&quot;&gt;Computational (Molecular) Biology&lt;/a&gt;. In
particular, I&#39;m studying now alignments of multiple sequences. The
theory is quite general and applies to alignments of sequences over
any alphabets, but the biological motivation is to study and
compare (sub)sequences of DNA and of proteins;
I must confess that while I was reading slowly in the beginning,
without much motivation, now I&#39;m quite excited about the subject.
It has really grown on me and now I see how much I still have to
catch up to read bleading edge papers (it is also surprising that
this area of knowledge has evolved so much in so little time, but I
guess that this is natural whenever there are economic interests in
a given field). Now, I want to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-12-07</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-12-07/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-12-07/</link>


	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-20T01:06:20Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! Got Debian&#39;s XFree86 4.0.1 packaged for potato. It&#39;s faster
with my Trident 3D Imàge 975 than XFree86 3.3.6, because it uses
more hardware acceleration (in fact, this was the main reason I
tried to find it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it couldn&#39;t be a painless experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For configuration, dexter didn&#39;t work (it died reproducibly when I
was configuring it) and xf86cfg didn&#39;t work (I can&#39;t remember the
reason why it didn&#39;t work). So, I was &quot;forced&quot; to use X&#39;s internal
autoprobing. But then, my old, 2-button, serial mouse couldn&#39;t be
used with 3 button emulation. It took me a lot of time to figure
out how to do that (since the documentation -- both man pages and
extra documents -- don&#39;t mention it). After some painful hours,
I&#39;ve discovered the magical line `Option &quot;Emulate3Buttons&quot;&#39;. It
then worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, there were remaining problems: some dock WindowMaker
utilities were removed when I installed the new X (due to
dependendy problems). I had to recompile them. Then, rxvt was
strange. Recompile time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, everything seems fine. Another thing to throw on that &quot;extras&quot;
CD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-12-03</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-12-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-12-03/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-20T01:06:20Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t believe, but I&#39;ve packaged &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; those programs in just a
day. Granted, I was really tired when I finished and that was the
only thing I did today. But it was worth it, because now I can
migrate my computer to the new one quite easily (I really love
qmail and I sincerely depend on it to achieve happiness).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My qmail package is not as &quot;clean&quot; as I&#39;d like it be (for instance,
it would be nice if I made its configuration use debconf, but I
think that that is a task for another day).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
