<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged hardware</title>
<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/hardware/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>2001-01-31</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2001-01-31/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2001-01-31/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:04:51Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Millennium! So many things have happened since the last
time I&#39;ve updated my diary and I guess that since I can&#39;t summarize
everything accurately, I&#39;ll just list what I think are the
remarkable facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have now put my new computer (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amd.com&quot;&gt;Duron&lt;/a&gt;
600MHz with a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asus.com&quot;&gt;Asus&lt;/a&gt; A7V motherboard)
to actual use. Of course, I made a backup of my older computer, so
that I was prepared for worst (read on);
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;Linux 2.4.0&lt;/a&gt; has finally been released and
it includes a lot of new goodies. While I think that it is still
not the right time to switch to the new version, it is indeed quite
tempting (but I&#39;ll resist that temptation, since I&#39;ve read a lot of
people complaining of data corruption with the new IDE drivers when
used with VIA chipsets -- and my motherboard features, guess what,
a VIA chipset, of course).
At the time of this writing (Feb 4th), Linux 2.4.1 was already
released, with many minor fixes;
A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing&quot;&gt;new version&lt;/a&gt; of the
Linux Distribution that I use,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org&quot;&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt; is now getting more and
more functionality. It is ready for the new Linux 2.4.0 kernel, but
still under development (read: prone to break). Oh, why can&#39;t new
software be stable? In the mean time, I&#39;m using Debian&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/potato&quot;&gt;potato&lt;/a&gt;.
One week after I have started to use my new computer, my 40GB
Samsung drive broke. Ouch. Fortunately, I had taken backups of
everything from my old computer and any new data that I had on my
new computer was still readable. So, now, I&#39;m using a new 30GB
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quantum.com&quot;&gt;Quantum&lt;/a&gt; drive and everything seems to be
working fine again. Nice.
I am now reading more and more things about my Mastership work. It
will be in a sub-area of computer science called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/hardware/../compbio/index.html&quot;&gt;Computational (Molecular) Biology&lt;/a&gt;. In
particular, I&#39;m studying now alignments of multiple sequences. The
theory is quite general and applies to alignments of sequences over
any alphabets, but the biological motivation is to study and
compare (sub)sequences of DNA and of proteins;
I must confess that while I was reading slowly in the beginning,
without much motivation, now I&#39;m quite excited about the subject.
It has really grown on me and now I see how much I still have to
catch up to read bleading edge papers (it is also surprising that
this area of knowledge has evolved so much in so little time, but I
guess that this is natural whenever there are economic interests in
a given field). Now, I want to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-12-07</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-07/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-07/</link>


	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:02:00Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! Got Debian&#39;s XFree86 4.0.1 packaged for potato. It&#39;s faster
with my Trident 3D Imàge 975 than XFree86 3.3.6, because it uses
more hardware acceleration (in fact, this was the main reason I
tried to find it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it couldn&#39;t be a painless experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For configuration, dexter didn&#39;t work (it died reproducibly when I
was configuring it) and xf86cfg didn&#39;t work (I can&#39;t remember the
reason why it didn&#39;t work). So, I was &quot;forced&quot; to use X&#39;s internal
autoprobing. But then, my old, 2-button, serial mouse couldn&#39;t be
used with 3 button emulation. It took me a lot of time to figure
out how to do that (since the documentation -- both man pages and
extra documents -- don&#39;t mention it). After some painful hours,
I&#39;ve discovered the magical line `Option &quot;Emulate3Buttons&quot;&#39;. It
then worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, there were remaining problems: some dock WindowMaker
utilities were removed when I installed the new X (due to
dependendy problems). I had to recompile them. Then, rxvt was
strange. Recompile time again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, everything seems fine. Another thing to throw on that &quot;extras&quot;
CD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-12-03</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-03/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-03/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T20:59:35Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t believe, but I&#39;ve packaged &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; those programs in just a
day. Granted, I was really tired when I finished and that was the
only thing I did today. But it was worth it, because now I can
migrate my computer to the new one quite easily (I really love
qmail and I sincerely depend on it to achieve happiness).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My qmail package is not as &quot;clean&quot; as I&#39;d like it be (for instance,
it would be nice if I made its configuration use debconf, but I
think that that is a task for another day).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-12-02</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-02/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-02/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>kde</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T20:58:40Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m now mirroring both a repository of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://kde.tdyc.com&quot;&gt;Debian KDE packages&lt;/a&gt; for potato and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.helixcode.com&quot;&gt;Helix Gnome&lt;/a&gt; for Debian with rsync. It&#39;s
&lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; better than mirroring with wget, that&#39;s for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was expecting to go to the movies today, but due to some (ahem)
&quot;technical problems&quot;, I wasn&#39;t able to go. And this made me quite
sad, but that&#39;s not actually a problem. Perhaps next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repackaged &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; 3.87beta for
Debian/potato and it is lintian-clean (!). So far, it seems to be
good and I think that I&#39;ll post a message to debian-mentors asking
what could be improved. In fact, the only thing that I don&#39;t like
in my package is the fact that I&#39;ve hardcoded a Build-Depends:
libncurses5-dev line in the control file. That&#39;s not quite right,
IMO, and I&#39;ll learn how to change it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next step is to package &lt;a href=&quot;http://cr.yp.to/djb.html&quot;&gt;DJB&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
utilities qmail, ucspi-tcp, serialmail and checkpassword. The
former seems to be quite involved, but the latters seem to be
trivial enough to package in one afternoon only (am I optimistic or
what?) and then I&#39;ll be able to switch to my brand new computer
(MICROS\~1 free) with Debian 2.2 + KDE 2.2 + my local packages (I
still won&#39;t have XFree86 4.0.1 and all its nifty features, since
I&#39;ll be waiting for a version of it to be compiled for potato;
using woody is scary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another package that I may be interested in packaging is a
ftpparse-ified version of wget (for mirroring
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cr.yp.to/publicfile.html&quot;&gt;publicfile&lt;/a&gt; repositories).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-12-01</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-01/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-01/</link>


	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>freebsd</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T20:56:28Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;After a long time without updates, I&#39;m now back to &quot;work&quot;.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vai.com&quot;&gt;Steve Vai&lt;/a&gt; is making some concerts here in São
Paulo, but unfortunately, I didn&#39;t attend it (the tickets&#39; prices
were a bit on the steep side) and as I&#39;ve just bought myself a new
new computer (woohoo), I&#39;m saving a bit of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new machine is a virgin &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amd.com&quot;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; Duron 600MHz,
with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asus.com&quot;&gt;Asus&lt;/a&gt; A7V motherboard (which, among
other things, includes an UDMA/100 controller, FSB frequency
controls and multiplier control), 128MB of SDRAM/PC133, a great
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.matrox.com&quot;&gt;Matrox&lt;/a&gt; G400 card (monohead) with 16MB of
SGRAM and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samsung.com&quot;&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt; HD of 40GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m actually quite excited and aside from some problems that I had
with a defective Matrox (that I&#39;ve now returned), it&#39;s working
wonderfully. It&#39;s so good that it even runs
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; quite fast! I can&#39;t wait for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt; 2.0.1 to be released on Monday (Dec 4th)
so that I can try the latest incarnation of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konqueror.org&quot;&gt;Konqueror&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org&quot;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; 2.8 was released today and
I&#39;ve already downloaded a copy and burned onto CD. I think that
I&#39;ve made everything right to get a bootable CD, but the CD that
I&#39;ve made is only able to boot in my new computer. Strange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of BSD, I also have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freebsd.org&quot;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;
4.2-RELEASE downloaded and burned. In fact, I think that I&#39;m
spending way too much time with this Internet thing (I downloaded
FreeBSD the very same day it was released -- that&#39;s Nov 21st).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-08-19</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-08-19/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-08-19/</link>


	<category>broadband</category>

	<category>hack</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>symphony-x</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2000 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T20:50:59Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;After waking up at 2pm, I found myself pondering if I should or not
go to McDonald&#39;s to get those 10 Big Macs that mom had bought for
Mc Dia Feliz. I went and then, after being stuffed, went again to
my uncle&#39;s shop. I brought him my comp and he made a cool hack to
change my computer&#39;s battery. My computer seems happier and
healthier. Ok, not sure about happier, but it sure looks healthier.
And just found out that my uncle had a cool, brand-new
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.speedy.com.br&quot;&gt;ADSL&lt;/a&gt; installed in his office. Wow!
Those things kick some major ass! Downloading MP3s faster than I
can play them. It&#39;s officially a Good Thing(tm).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
