<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged hardware</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/hardware/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 03:23:45 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>2002-07-07</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>macosx</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:23:45Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Woke up quite early with that kernel panic bugging me. I read the
documentation and the fix for it was to reboot MacOS 9 (which
wasn&#39;t as simple as it should, since MacOS X apparently de-blessed
MacOS 9&#39;s System Folder). Anyway, after reusing XPostFacto, the
PowerMac booted with MacOS X! Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, seeing this OS booting on this old computer is quite cool.
Well,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=33385&amp;amp;cid=3607384&quot;&gt;apart from some severe usability problems&lt;/a&gt;
and slowness, MacOS X is an amazing operating system. The problem
is: it &lt;strong&gt;is slow&lt;/strong&gt;. It is slow with a G3 600MHz (100MHz of bus)
with 128MB of RAM and, obviously, much more so with a dual 604e
180MHz with only 64MB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, MacOS X isn&#39;t able to use both processors when it is booted
with XPostFacto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW#2, XFree86&#39;s native driver for Mach64 doesn&#39;t include support
for the XVideo extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also used the client-side of NFS and SMB on MacOS X, which is quite
easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-07-06</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>macosx</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:20:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Took the day to see how things regarding the old PowerMac
9500/180MP were with a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~branden/&quot;&gt;newer XFree86&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xfree86.org/&quot;&gt;XFree86 4.2&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t support the XVideo
extension for the &lt;code&gt;imst&lt;/code&gt;t adapter, which is quite a pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that I am not able to use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xine.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Xine&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mplayerhq.hu/&quot;&gt;Mplayer&lt;/a&gt;
to efficiently play videos on this computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see some things that make this computer slow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a modest amount of RAM for today&#39;s standards (64MB,
which is particularly little for PowerPC);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s RAM chips are in an interleaved
configuration or not;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it had a faster/better supported video card (say, like a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com/&quot;&gt;ATI&lt;/a&gt; Mach64), things would perhaps be better,
but this is just a guess. I don&#39;t know if the Mach64 sports XVideo
support under PowerPC, but perhaps the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gatos.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Gatos&lt;/a&gt; project might help here;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea why this computer, while having a SCSI interface
and drive, is so slow while it is using the disk. I see two things:
it freezes most things the user (that&#39;s me!) whenever it is writing
(reading?) anything to (from?) the disk and the transfer speeds are
quite sloooow. I wonder if this is a problem of the Linux SCSI
infra-structure, if it is a problem of the hardware or if it is a
problem of configuration. It probably isn&#39;t a problem with Linux,
since I also see the slowness with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt;
Classic (8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Anyway, just for fun, I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X 10.1&lt;/a&gt; on this old computer.
The catch is that MacOS X can&#39;t be installed on anything this old.
Well, at least, that&#39;s what Apple says. I had to grab a copy of
MacOS 9 (in German!) just to bootstrap the system. Then, using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://eshop.macsales.com/OSXCenter/XPostFacto/&quot;&gt;XPostFacto&lt;/a&gt;, the
installation was quite smooth (and slow). But with one gotcha at
the first reboot: a kernel panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-20</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-20/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-20/</link>



	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Just another common day. Attended the mini-course on
&lt;em&gt;Theory of Matroids&lt;/em&gt; (which just shown me that I should be studying
way, way more) and the seminar on Computational Biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also got the new speakers for my computer, Logitech&#39;s Soundman
S-4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-18</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-18/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>ibook</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>mac</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Typed the remaining bits of the first lecture on the
&lt;em&gt;Theory of Matroids&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read about how one makes a bootable CD for Newworlds with mkisofs:
apparently, the needed things are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;create a folder with &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;vmlinux&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;root.bin&lt;/code&gt;.
I&#39;m not sure if &lt;code&gt;boot-floppy-hfs.img&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ofboot.b&lt;/code&gt; are necessary. I
also don&#39;t have an idea of how OpenFirmware knows that it is
supposed to load yaboot during the boot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkisofs -hfs -map &amp;lt;file\&amp;gt; -part -hfs-bless &amp;lt;folder\&amp;gt; -r -o &amp;lt;isoimage.iso\&amp;gt; &amp;lt;root-of-cd\&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sent an e-mail to the bastards at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxjournal.com/&quot;&gt;Linux Journal&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that I&#39;m
not receiving my issues as I should (and my subscription is far
from being expired).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com.br/&quot;&gt;Apple Brasil&lt;/a&gt; is selling
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ibook/&quot;&gt;iBooks&lt;/a&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/br/appleensino/&quot;&gt;a promotion for education users&lt;/a&gt;.
Damn!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-17</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-17/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>ibook</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>mac</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Got &lt;a href=&quot;http://mplayer.sf.net/&quot;&gt;mplayer&lt;/a&gt; working well in PowerPC (G3,
600MHz), with the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://ffmpeg.sf.net/&quot;&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/a&gt;. I had to use
-ao sdl to get it working. The video wasn&#39;t as smooth as with -ao
null, but it was OK, at least. I am under the impression that using
-vo sdl:x11 is better than using -vo x11, at least with the Rage
Mobility 128. BTW, it was also possible to play DivX 5 movies with
this setup (the new Star Wars clip).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USB keyboard and USB mouse work fine under Linux. It was just a
simple matter of recompiling the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/&quot;&gt;kernel&lt;/a&gt;
with USB HID support enabled (in my case, as modules). They also
work fine with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-16</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-16/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-16/</link>



	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Went to see my uncle with my SO. Got myself an USB keyboard with an
USB mouse attached (with scroll wheel).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-01-01</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-01-01/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-01-01/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>macos</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, some progress on the PPC front. I&#39;ve just configured the PMac
to use the &lt;code&gt;imstt&lt;/code&gt; driver instead of the &lt;code&gt;fbdev&lt;/code&gt;. Due to this, the
X server is now &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster. In fact, the whole computer is much
faster. Before, it spent a lot of processing power just to update
the screen. Since it is not exactly the most powerful computer in
the world, those few moments indeed were important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very fast and now it is almost able to play AVI files with
MPlayer. Almost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Mac is now very usable and I&#39;d even dare to say that it would
be a good workstation, were it not that outdated (well, if one
could find replacement hardware for it easily...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&#39;ll end summarizing all the &quot;Mac Journey&quot; in a homepage
to save future souls enduring the problems that I&#39;ve experienced
(kernel configuration file, XF86Config file etc). It seems that
Linux running on PPC is indeed a quite nice alternative to paying
huge prices just for being able to run MacOS 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also installed the superb
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mosfet.org/liquid.html&quot;&gt;Liquid Theme&lt;/a&gt; for KDE2. It&#39;s
amazingly beautiful and quite fast, despite all the eye-candy. It
makes your Linux desktop seem like you are running
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&#39;s Acqua&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the down side of things, I guess that I&#39;m just encountering many
aspects of Perl that I don&#39;t like. It&#39;s saddening that I&#39;ve spent
so much time and money (buying books) for something that I&#39;m not
really enjoying (but it&#39;s ok).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2001-12-29</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-29/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-29/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I finally got the Power Macintosh 9500/180MP with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian testing&lt;/a&gt; installed in a semi-decent
way: I&#39;m using BenH&#39;s 2.4.17-ben0 kernel which finally has the mace
driver working again. What does this mean? Well, it means that I&#39;m
now not confined to 2.2.x kernels anymore. A 2.4 kernel has many
advantages, especially, for the PowerPC platform. Among other
things, they are faster for the same hardware, have good SMP
support, the IMSTT pci card is recognized (which wasn&#39;t in the 2.2
kernels) and a lot of other nice goodies like a journalling
filesystem (ext3) etc.
Also got &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mp3dev.org/mp3/&quot;&gt;lame 3.90.1&lt;/a&gt; compiled for the
PowerPC in a decent way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A collateral effect of having lame compiled for the ppc is that now
I have a have a good benchmark that shows me roughly how much
slower this thing is in relation to my Duron 600MHz. The sad news:
it is 5 or 6 times slower than the Duron. If lame were
multithreaded, then it could be up to 2.5 times slower, which would
be acceptable for day-to-day use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, got some work done to make the Debian packaging
scripts a bit nicer (read: closer to being lintian clean).
Unfortunately, lintian still complains about the shared library
package having an rpath and I don&#39;t know how to get rid of that
(not even a kludgy solution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;http://mplayer.sf.net&quot;&gt;MPlayer&lt;/a&gt; released another version
(0.60pre2), I downloaded the sources and, to my surprise, it
compiles on PPC (the 0.60pre1 didn&#39;t). And it even plays, errr,
tries to play DivX movies! Amazing job these guys are
accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After struggling a lot with the configuration files, also got X
4.1.0 working on a framebuffer device (the imstt driver doesn&#39;t
work). So, now I even have a reasonably fast, modest GUI working
(or a slower GUI if I load &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 2&lt;/a&gt;). And I can
even use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; here, although the
swapping doesn&#39;t make it a pleasant experience. In this respect,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com/&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;, while non-free, is much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this can now be a poor&#39;s man desktop machine. If it
only consumed power proportional to its speed, it would be nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2001-07-18</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-18/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, I know I messed up. My girlfriend told me that we were in July,
not June. What a shame! Anyway, I&#39;ve corrected my diary entries and
got things straight (I think). I guess that the problem was that
both months start with a &quot;J&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to the next (and final?) chapter on the mac: I returned it to
my uncle and set up the other mac on his store just to see if I
could get Debian installed. Well, I kind of could: I got the
bootfloppies installed in 1GB HD and was very surprised to see an
almost entire setup with the network. Amazing. I&#39;m almost without
words: just grab 4 FDs and install a whole operating system in your
machine with them. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; definitely keeps
its lead over other distributions this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, enough ads. I could get almost everything installed, but the
HD died (for good?) soon after the packages were being extracted
onto the new filesystem. I tried the other (4GB) HD, but it wasn&#39;t
being seen by &lt;code&gt;mac-fdisk&lt;/code&gt; for an unknown reason (despite it being
recognized during the SCSI bus scan and the partition check).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I guess that I can consider this as my first installation of
Linux on a PowerPC architecture, which could not be concluded only
because the hardware didn&#39;t help, but both the operator (that&#39;s me!
&amp;lt;grin&gt;) and the software were right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watched &quot;Monty Python&#39;s Life of Brian&quot; after that. Sent both my VCR
and TV set to the technician. For some strange reason, both
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konqueror.org&quot;&gt;Konqueror&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; are not rendering this page
justified, while &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netscape.com&quot;&gt;Netscape 4.77&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org&quot;&gt;Mozilla 0.9.2&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com&quot;&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt; are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2001-07-17</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-17/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the day that shouldn&#39;t have happened --- it was bad right
from start. First of all, I couldn&#39;t sleep well because I dreamt
with some perl scripts that didn&#39;t work and they took me almost all
my sleep time (or so it seemed). Then, my kind neighbor started
making lots of noises and I couldn&#39;t keep sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the worst part of the day was still coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to my uncle&#39;s shop to get a new SCSI HD and he lent me a 4GB
one, more than enough to hold both Linux and MacOS 8. I turned the
thing on and it started making noises like the one I used
yesterday, which wasn&#39;t good. Anyway, I left it on and decided to
install MacOS on it. It was progressing nicely and I was getting
happier and happier, but then the whole system froze. I turned the
power off and tried to install Linux. At least this time Linux saw
the HD and all partitions that it had (7, I think).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Linux, I used some CVS bootfloppies that will become
bootfloppies of Debian woody. While trying to make the brand new
ext2 filesystem, I got a kernel panic. I tried again. This time, I
went up to the point of choosing which kernel modules I wanted. I
was getting happy again. But then, when I chose the module for the
ethernet card, a new kernel panic. Ouch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then tried to install MacOS again and a new freeze. Tried again,
new freeze. Then, I noticed that the HD was getting hot and put a
fan near it. I don&#39;t know if it was coincidence or not, but after
that, I could finish the installation of MacOS. Ok, so time to boot
this thing with no CDs in the CD-ROM drive. Nothing. Grrrr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things got strange after I tried to put the Linux PPC CD that I had
burned and it didn&#39;t work. Washed the CD and no boot. But it did
some days ago! It was not scratched, had no fingerprints and was
absolutely clean. But couldn&#39;t boot. I tried using the floppies
again, but this time, another surprise: the HD &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; recognized,
but a partition scan timed out, Linux told that it could not read
read its beginning and that it assumed that the size of the HD was
1GB, and showed &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; partitions on the drive. On the other hand,
MacOS is able to see it just before formatting it, perhaps because
it re-scans the SCSI bus. Changing the SCSI-id of the drive didn&#39;t
help. Is that the reason why it can&#39;t boot from the HD? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my desire of seeing this thing encoding MP3s, using KDE, a
brand new browser and typing some texts with LaTeX seems a bit
farther than what I realized at first. I will still keep trying to
make this damn thing work, but I&#39;m not confident anymore that I&#39;ll
succeed. Well, I&#39;ll talk to my uncle tomorrow, perhaps and see if
the other Mac behaves the same way. Enough for a day already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
