<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged advertisements</title>
<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/advertisements/"/>
<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/advertisements/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/advertisements/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2012-09-04T03:21:59Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Trying out AdSense</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/"/>






	<category term="adsense" />

	<category term="advertisements" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="debian-planet" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="funding" />


	<updated>2012-09-04T03:21:59Z</updated>
	<published>2012-09-03T23:12:42Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I have been having quite costly experiments with &lt;a href=&quot;http://buffalo.nas-central.org/wiki/LS_Hardware_and_Software_information&quot;&gt;(embeded) hardware&lt;/a&gt; in
the last few weeks/months. To cover at least part of the expenses, I am
trying out to use Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; with my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on blogging more frequently with the results of the experiments, but
it will take me a few days, as I want to offer people only the &quot;meat&quot; of
what I actually did, pointing out some pitfalls that made me waste a lot of
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to AdSense, one interesting thing about trying it is that I
applied to be part of the program for 3 or 4 times late in August and, due
to unspecified reasons, my application was rejected for &quot;not complying with
their policies&quot;.  I read the policies from left to side, from up and down
and nowhere I saw anything that my blog infringed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I tried once again and I&#39;m now in a sort of &quot;probation period&quot;
for AdSense, which is progress I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I only put one advertisement at the top of my pages, but I am
curious to know how &quot;targeted&quot; those ads would be to a blog that has
articles that were written more than a decade ago, with posts in at least
two languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that this is a weaker version of what &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaelhertzog.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël Hertzog&lt;/a&gt; is trying
to do with his funding campaigns, except that I only expect to cover the
costs of my hardware (even if I am skeptical that I will actually manage to
reach that point of self-sufficiency).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
