<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged opeth</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/opeth/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/opeth/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/opeth/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Seeing Opeth Live in Brazil</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/seeing-opeth-live-in-brazil/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/seeing-opeth-live-in-brazil/"/>






	<category term="music" />

	<category term="opeth" />

	<category term="pain-of-salvation" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2007-03-15T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;The acoustic show of Pain of Salvation is really nice. I didn&#39;t have enough
time to watch it yet, but it is an amazing thing that should be kept, as the
performance is superb (I did look quickly at some points of it and, of
course, the expectations have been met---we are, after all, talking about a
band that has a unique touch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, speaking about unique bands, I will be seeing Opeth playing live here in
Brazil. Yes. This day has arrived. I will see my favourite band playing
here. I guess that I have to get in touch with Mikael and see if I can sneak
in a camera, so that I can shot and film the show.  This will be amazing, to
say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Sourceforge, SSH keys, Free audiobooks, DVD&#x27;s</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/sourceforge-ssh-keys-free-audiobooks-dvds/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/sourceforge-ssh-keys-free-audiobooks-dvds/"/>






	<category term="audiobooks" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="descartes" />

	<category term="dvds" />

	<category term="hashes" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="opeth" />

	<category term="pain-of-salvation" />

	<category term="public-domain" />

	<category term="security" />

	<category term="ssh" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2007-03-11T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Found out about &quot;The Right Way (TM)&quot; to hash an existing SSH&#39;s &lt;code&gt;known_hosts&lt;/code&gt;
file (&lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen -H&lt;/code&gt;) and how to remove a hashed host entry from your
&lt;code&gt;known_hosts&lt;/code&gt; file: &lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen -H -R host.name&lt;/code&gt;.  I needed this for newer
checkouts of LAME&#39;s CVS repository at &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/&quot;&gt;Sourceforge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, just to save myself the trouble of looking it up again, here is the
link to the place where sourceforge keeps their &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.sourceforge.net/trac/sitedocs/wiki/SSH%20key%20fingerprints&quot;&gt;SSH key fingerprints&lt;/a&gt;.
I&#39;m always lost trying to find it, so I thought that it would be best to
record it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also discovered a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; amazing thing: a &lt;a href=&quot;http://librivox.org/&quot;&gt;free source of audiobooks&lt;/a&gt;
in podcast format, while I was looking for René Descartes&#39; &quot;The Method&quot;.
While surfing the net, I also found that there is this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dominiopublico.gov.br/pesquisa/DetalheObraForm.do?select_action=&amp;amp;amp;co_obra=2274&quot;&gt;very same text&lt;/a&gt;
in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dominiopublico.gov.br/&quot;&gt;Brazilian site&lt;/a&gt; backed by the government that hosts works in the
public domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still downloading Pain of Salvation&#39;s Acoustic set. Now, I finally had some
time to watch the somewhat incomplete VOBs and it, indeed, has the show. And
it is an amazing piece of music. Recommended for all fans of good music.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-08-18</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-08-18/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-08-18/"/>






	<category term="crypto" />

	<category term="drm" />

	<category term="dvds" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="opeth" />


	<updated>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</updated>
	<published>2001-08-18T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Well, it&#39;s been quite a while since I last wrote an entry of my
weblog. Anyway, much has happened since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting things was that I spent some 18 hours
just trying to grab a rare video in VHS format to a digital file.
It was a very special show from
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com&quot;&gt;my favorite band&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s appearance in July 28th
of 2000, at the Milwaukee Metalfest festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I borrowed a bt878a-based capture from my uncle and used it to grab
the video. After much strugles with the computer and programs to
save the video, I finally ended up with the job done. I compressed
the video in an amazing fast-motion
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.divx.com&quot;&gt;DivX &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/opeth/../../smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;-)&quot; /&gt; 3.11&lt;/a&gt; stream of high bitrate.
Unfortunately, I couldn&#39;t get the sound better than mono, 11kHz,
8bit, but since the VHS was already a bootleg, it sounds almost the
same as the original tape that I have (indeed, it is actually quite
hard to tell them apart just by the sound). So, I&#39;m now happier
with a 500MB file of the whole concert (which lasts for 54:59).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also bought myself an
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asus.com/&quot;&gt;Asus DVD-ROM E608&lt;/a&gt;, which is an RPC-1 drive
that reads up to 8x. It is cool to have a DVD drive that ignores
all the region cruft established by the MPAA. Thus, now I can play
all DVDs of my preferred bands... Almost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DVD support under Linux is way behind DVD support under Windows.
Cyberlink&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gocyberlink.com/&quot;&gt;PowerDVD&lt;/a&gt; generates quite
smooth movies with the hardware that I have (and I don&#39;t even know
if it uses the Matrox in any way to accelerate the output).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are many programs to play DVDs under
Linux, with some of them bein &lt;a href=&quot;http://xine.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Xine&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videolan.org/&quot;&gt;Videolan&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dtek.chalmers.se/groups/dvd/&quot;&gt;Ogle&lt;/a&gt;. All of them quite
immature as the time of this writing and there&#39;s also the whole
problem with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lemuria.org/DeCSS/&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xine is packaged for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, but the
package is quite old in the Debian repository. It also does not
incorportate DeCSS. It does not interpret DVD menus. And subtitles
bring the player down to its knees (is it disabling overlay mode?).
It can play the subtitles using the little controls at the side of
the &quot;off&quot; word. A command line option to use subtitles is available
on version 0.4.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, only Videolan supports DeCSS out of the box, has
Debian packages on its site, but also has problems with subtitles
(they are not available in overlay mode -- only usable using
command line switches &lt;code&gt;--vout x11&lt;/code&gt; or or &lt;code&gt;--vout sdl&lt;/code&gt;). Videolan&#39;s
subtitles are ugly. Overall, it seems to be a player with a good
potential and better user interface than xine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, ogle is the only player that supports DVD menus. I haven&#39;t
used it as much as the other ones, but not all DVD menus are usable
(ogle sometimes skips menus). It seems that the future of this
player is just to serve to other players as a source for
menu-handling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DVD output on Linux is also quite bad: the video shows clear
signs of being interlaced, with, say, odd lines shifted to the
right some 10-20 pixels in relation to even lines. This artifact is
especially bad on fast-moving scenes. Since this is a problem with
all players under Linux, is there any library that is doing
something wrong? PowerDVD for Windows is also not perfect: the
image is not as crisp as I&#39;d expect from a DVD: while it doesn&#39;t
show the effects just mentioned above, its image is a bit blurred,
like if someone used a &quot;gaussian blur&quot; filter on the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I still don&#39;t know how things are handled with regions
under Linux: are region codes simply ignored by both the drive and
the application? Is the application (say, xine) responsible for
setting it/lying to the drive? Shouldn&#39;t I care? It seems that I&#39;ll
have to use that dreaded trial-and-error again to discover.
Humpft.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-14</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-14/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-14/"/>






	<category term="movies" />

	<category term="opeth" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-14T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a day! I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; tired that I woke up at (almost) 5pm.
And, surprise: no light. Yes, a power outage. Anyway, my parents
weren&#39;t at home and I found a note that mom left on my computer&#39;s
keyboard telling me that they were shopping around. Then, I
discovered two new boxes at home: a brand new TV set and a new VCR.
The first time in 5 or 6 months that would be able to see my
amazing tape of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt; playing at Milwaukee
Metalfest. Woohoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But without power, my main concern was to be able to &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; anything
before the day became too dark. After half an hour (or was it an
hour?) trying to find some candles and fire, my parents arrived and
two hours later, I was watching &quot;As Good As It Gets&quot;. Cool movie,
BTW. Excellent acting of both Helen Hunt and Jack Nicholson (mom
told me that I act like him most of the time -- is that
compliment?).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
