<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged ffmpeg</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/ffmpeg/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/ffmpeg/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/ffmpeg/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2014-02-16T17:10:07Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Miscellanea</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-14_miscellanea/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-14_miscellanea/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="ffmpeg" />

	<category term="libav" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2014-02-16T17:10:07Z</updated>
	<published>2014-02-15T02:59:22Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;h1 id=&quot;initsystem&quot;&gt;Init system&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy that Debian&#39;s Technical Committee was able to reach a very good
decision with the choice of systemd as the default init system for the Linux
ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I was very pleasantly surprised by the lucidity of Russ
Allbery&#39;s analyses and, above all, his &lt;em&gt;patience&lt;/em&gt; even with people that, in
my understanding, were just being trolls or trying to cause confusion and
disrupt a process that was already chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russ, thank you for your exemplary role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also, you type fast or what? You fill whole e-mails seemingly faster than I
can read!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unexpectedunionofforces&quot;&gt;Unexpected union of forces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that Mark Shutterworth&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/1316&quot;&gt;decision&lt;/a&gt; of (perhaps?)
embracing Debian&#39;s decision in the init system is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that one way where Ubuntu did a great thing with respect to Debian
was their initial attitude towards cherry-picking the best of breed of Free
Software from Debian&#39;s archive and polishing that to create a really &quot;for
human beings&quot; operating system.  I hope that this means that, at least in
part, money (Mark&#39;s?) can be channeled in the best of the interests so that
we all gain from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And, to be honest, I see no problem in making money with Free Software and
I welcome a well done integration job).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;morepolarizingthings&quot;&gt;More polarizing things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that, now, I may even have some hope of sending another
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/729203&quot;&gt;potentially polarizing&lt;/a&gt; bug to the Tech Ctte (that is ffmpeg vs. libav)
and have faith that some rational decision would be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not even aware of it, but the ffmpeg folks even
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ffmpeg.org/&quot;&gt;featured a news item in their page&lt;/a&gt; of me having filed the RFP bug
mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;debconf14&quot;&gt;DebConf 14&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes as expected, I hope to attend this year&#39;s DebConf.  In
fact, I am anticipating this, since I would love to, e.g., talk with Joey
Hess and discuss a better way of having &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/parallel/&quot;&gt;GNU parallel&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt;
program in &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/moreutils&quot;&gt;moreutils&lt;/a&gt; have amicable co-installability among many,
many other things with respect to my packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, quite probably, work on packaging ffmpeg with other interested people
(which seem to be numerous).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Fix markdown link pointing twice to the ffmpeg site. Thanks
Marius Gedminas for pointing this out.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
