<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged quotient-groups</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/quotient-groups/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/quotient-groups/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/quotient-groups/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2012-09-07T07:19:57Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Random Points on Group Theory</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/random-points-on-group-theory/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/random-points-on-group-theory/"/>






	<category term="abstract-algebra" />

	<category term="group-theory" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="quotient-groups" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T07:19:57Z</updated>
	<published>2007-05-24T17:07:11Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;It is not a surprise for anyone that I&#39;m reviewing a little bit of Abstract
Algebra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Fraleigh&#39;s book is proving to be quite a good refresher, especially
since my short-term goal is to study &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coding%20Theory&quot;&gt;Coding Theory&lt;/a&gt; and the
finer aspects of Coding Theory do involve Algebra (actually, one could say
that the finer aspects of Coding Theory, especially Error Correcting Codes,
depend quite a lot on Algebra).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, while studying Group Theory, one can&#39;t avoid to be amazed by some
results that are not exactly that intuitive. For instance, I just discovered
that the additive group !!mathjaxbegin-i!! XG1hdGhiYiBaW1hd
 !!mathjaxend-i!! of univariate polynomials with
integer coefficients is isomorphic to the multiplicative group !!mathjaxbegin-i!! XG1hdGhiYiBRXis=
 !!mathjaxend-i!!
of positive rationals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that this was a relatively easy exercise until I posed the problem
to a very competent friend of mine and he had some problems trying to come
up with the isomorphism. His failure maybe tells me that this is not as
obvious as I once thought and I think that this exercise should be better
known, as it can show that very differently looking algebraic structures can
be &quot;the same&quot; and the most surprising fact here is that &lt;em&gt;we are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;
dealing with any pathologically &quot;made up&quot; example&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that maybe is hard for students to grasp is the concept of a
factor group. Knowing that a subgroup is normal iff it is the kernel of some
homomorphism of groups is a handy way to memorize and &quot;see&quot; what a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/normal%20subgroup&quot;&gt;normal subgroup&lt;/a&gt; is. And students should be shown that there
are some quite special (&quot;natural&quot;?) normal subgroups of a group: the &lt;em&gt;center
of the group&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;commutator subgroup&lt;/em&gt;, just as two examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter one, together with a good explanation of what does it mean for
taking &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quotient%20group&quot;&gt;factor groups&lt;/a&gt; (i.e., taking the
elements of the normal subgroup and equating them to the unity), leads to a
better understanding of quotient/factor groups. A nice thing to prove (that
is short and shows the &quot;mechanics&quot; of factor groups) is the fact that a
quotient group is abelian iff the normal group used as the &quot;denominator&quot;
contains the commutator subgroup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that is worth doing is proving that a normal subgroup !!mathjaxbegin-i!! Tg==
 !!mathjaxend-i!! is
maximal in a group !!mathjaxbegin-i!! Rw==
 !!mathjaxend-i!! iff !!mathjaxbegin-i!! Ry9O
 !!mathjaxend-i!! is simple. The proof of this fact is
analogous to the proof of the quotient of a ring being a field iff a ring is
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Factor%20ring&quot;&gt;factored&lt;/a&gt; by a maximal ideal (and that we
get an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/integral%20domain&quot;&gt;integral domain&lt;/a&gt; if the ideal is only prime instead of
maximal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, two groups that I feel that should merit way more attention than what
I perceive as being given in a first course are the dihedral groups !!mathjaxbegin-i!! RF8z
 !!mathjaxend-i!!
and !!mathjaxbegin-i!! RF80
 !!mathjaxend-i!!. Asking the students to draw the lattice of subgroups of such
groups is quite enlightening, as they are &quot;natural&quot; groups that are not
abelian (but with &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the proper subgroups being abelian). Nice examples
to have in mind, without any shadow of doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
