<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged debian</title>
<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/debian/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>Some experiences with ZFS</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/some_experiences_with_zfs/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/some_experiences_with_zfs/</link>


	<category>compression</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>debian-planet</category>

	<category>deduplication</category>

	<category>filesystems</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>zfs</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 23:42:24 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-09T02:48:33Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/117659222649141007981/posts/T3BcxA7wKjK&quot;&gt;ZFS evaluation journey&lt;/a&gt; (which I will summarize here with
the things that I learned), I was able to fit about 2.5TB of data on a
single 2TB drive, with deduplication enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, even &lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt; files around in ZFS (which you would think
would be a cheap operation) takes ages. Removing files also takes ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; unloaded Phenom II X4 910 system running Linux 3.5.2
(actually, from Debian&#39;s experimental), and zfsonlinux version
0.6.0.71-0ubuntu1~precise1 (recompiled from source to work with my Debian
system), I tried to remove a subdirectory that had about 4000
files. According to time, it took:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;real    42m51.487s
user    0m0.188s
sys     0m16.769s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is a bit too slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just (read: &quot;yesterday&quot;) upgraded this machine from 4GB to 6GB of RAM
(well, I would have updated it to 8GB of RAM as that is what I ordered, but
it one of the RAM chips arrived dead here and I simply took one of the new
4GB card and one of the older 2GB card).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, honestly, I don&#39;t see change in upgrading the RAM from 4GB to 6GB and,
unless something magic happens with 2GB more, I wouldn&#39;t expect a whole
different story with 8GB of RAM. Oh, no swap is being used (well, it is an
unloaded machine after all), and the Linux kernel swappiness knob is at its
default of 60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; see, though, is that even for a single file removal, the disk is
thrashing a lot. I mean &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; crazy and that is, of course, the prime
suspect of the bad performance (of course, of course). So, there must be
some really crazy metadata churning going on here and I guess that the
people from the LLNL would like to know of their modules producing this
behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep tuned for some future impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>NOT Trying out AdSense</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense_not/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense_not/</link>


	<category>adsense</category>

	<category>advertisements</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>debian-planet</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>funding</category>

	<category>google</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 13:16:18 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T16:17:48Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;On the 3rd of September, I applied to Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; program, as I
told in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog/posts/trying_out_adsense/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that was a short-lived experience. On the 5th of September, I received
the following e-mail, which, sincerely, is as uninformative as it could get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Date: Wed, 05 Sep 2012 16:52:22 -0000
From: adsense-noreply@google.com
To: rbrito@gmail.com
Subject: Google AdSense Support

Hello,

As mentioned in our welcome email, we conduct a second review of your
AdSense application once AdSense code is placed on your site(s). As a
result of this review, we have disapproved your account for the following
violation(s):

Issues:

- Site does not comply with Google policies


---------------------

Further detail:


Site does not comply with Google policies: We&#39;re unable to approve your
AdSense application at this time because we feel that your site does not
comply with Google AdSense policies or webmaster quality guidelines. It&#39;s
our goal to provide our advertisers sites that offer rich and meaningful
content, receive organic traffic, and allow us to serve well-targeted ads
to users. We believe that currently your site does not fulfill this
criteria. 

For more details, please read the webmaster quality guidelines at
http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=35769 and
the AdSense program policies at
http://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?answer=48182,
https://support.google.com/adsense/bin/topic.py?topic=1271507

(...)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I went on and read &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the documentation on program policies
etc.  I investigate each point here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invalid clicks and impressions: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouraging clicks: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content guidelines: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copyrighted material: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmaster guidelines: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic sources: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad behavior: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad placement: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site behavior: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive ads and services: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google advertising cookies: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, I RTFM and did everything correctly. So, dear
lazyweb, what would my options be to fund a tiny bit of my software
contributions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Trying out AdSense</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/</link>


	<category>adsense</category>

	<category>advertisements</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>debian-planet</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>funding</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 20:12:42 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-03T23:16:51Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have been having quite costly experiments with &lt;a href=&quot;http://buffalo.nas-central.org/wiki/LS_Hardware_and_Software_information&quot;&gt;(embeded) hardware&lt;/a&gt; in
the last few weeks/months. To cover at least part of the expenses, I am
trying out to use Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; with my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on blogging more frequently with the results of the experiments, but
it will take me a few days, as I want to offer people only the &quot;meat&quot; of
what I actually did, pointing out some pitfalls that made me waste a lot of
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to AdSense, one interesting thing about trying it is that I
applied to be part of the program for 3 or 4 times late in August and, due
to unspecified reasons, my application was rejected for &quot;not complying with
their policies&quot;.  I read the policies from left to side, from up and down
and nowhere I saw anything that my blog infringed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I tried once again and I&#39;m now in a sort of &quot;probation period&quot;
for AdSense, which is progress I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I only put one advertisement at the top of my pages, but I am
curious to know how &quot;targeted&quot; those ads would be to a blog that has
articles that were written more than a decade ago, with posts in at least
two languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that this is a weaker version of what &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaelhertzog.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël Hertzog&lt;/a&gt; is trying
to do with his funding campaigns, except that I only expect to cover the
costs of my hardware (even if I am skeptical that I will actually manage to
reach that point of self-sufficiency).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>I am not going to DebConf 12</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</link>


	<category>debconf</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>fonts</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>handbrake</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 01:59:42 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-06-07T04:58:09Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Due to some real life impediments (including a beautiful one with just over
2 months of life called Daniel), I will not be able to go to this year&#39;s
DebConf, even though it seems that this DebConf will exceed many
expectations with the support that the governement of Nicaragua just
offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Things that I would like to have worked on&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this means that I will not be working with some fellows that
may be there, like people from the &lt;code&gt;pkg-multimedia&lt;/code&gt; team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, as I am working on some packages that are not that well
suited to distributions (especially regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://handbrake.fr/&quot;&gt;HandBrake&lt;/a&gt;), it would be
highly productive to have a hacking session or two with other people
interested in having this popular and easy-to-use video ripper/transcoder on
Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to be able to talk in person with other people (including
&lt;a href=&quot;http://joeyh.name/blog/&quot;&gt;Joey Hess&lt;/a&gt;) about controversial packaging of some programs, like GNU
Parallel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/parallel&quot;&gt;which I maintain in Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things else that I would love to work on, besides helping a
bit with some of the still pending transitions of the the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;, meeting friends and other social
stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, well. I guess that working at home will be the solution for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Running GRUB2 on PowerPC Macs</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/running_grub2_on_powerpc_macs/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/running_grub2_on_powerpc_macs/</link>


	<category>configuration</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>ibook</category>

	<category>kernel</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>mac</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 22:18:12 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-04-03T01:21:31Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Here I write a little bit about my experiences running GRUB2 with a PowerPC
Mac (actually, an iBook G4), since the current documentation is lacking in
many places (outdated, incorrect, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of what I say is platform agnostic, though, and may be of interest to
users of GRUB in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Basics using GRUB2 with PowerPC&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is important to understand (at least superficially) how
botting on a Mac works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first programs that run in your Mac is the OpenFirmware. It works
with more or less the same purpose of a BIOS in a regular x86 system. The
basic idea is the same: get the computer running with whatever programs you
want it to run. The implementation, though, differs quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, OpenFirmware (OF) usually presents itself as a command-line
interface that is programmable, differently from the common day BIOSes from
x86 boxes. As it is programmable, it is more flexible, but this flexibility
comes at the price of an increased complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may write some things more in a future article, if there is any
interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, it just suffices to say that to get to the OF prompt in a Mac, you
have to press a combination keys during the time that your Mac gives a chime
when you turn it on. At that moment, you have to press (simulaneously) Cmd +
Option + O + F. (Note: the Cmd key is the key that has an Apple drawn on it,
usually on the side of the space bar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Limitations of Open Firmware&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Differently from usual BIOSes of x86 computers, Open Firmware &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; read the
contents of a partition in your HD (or other devices), as long as it is
formatted in the original HFS format (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in HFS+ or one of its
descendents).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why some older versions of Linux create an HFS partition
in your HD, even if you don&#39;t intent to run or use anything besides Linux.
The &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; bootloader consists of, among other things, one binary that is
understandable by OpenFirmware. That binary is a file called &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt;, after
the name of the booloader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, you have to indicate to OF what is the file that you want it to
load during the boot process, so that it knows what to do. The way to
indicate this is to &quot;bless&quot; the file (and the folder that contains it).
Some ways to bless a file are to, for example, use the &lt;code&gt;bless&lt;/code&gt; command in
MacOS X or the &lt;code&gt;hattrib -b&lt;/code&gt; command from hfsutils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Files in an HFS filesystem have two attributes that many other filesystems
don&#39;t: a creator ID (the &quot;application&quot; that created the file) and the type
ID (which determines what kind of file it is).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenFirmware, in particular, looks for files with the type &lt;code&gt;tbxi&lt;/code&gt; for the
bootstrap process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; binary is loaded by OF into memory and, then, control is passed
to the yaboot program, which then reads its configuration file
(&lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt;) from the same folder where the binary was in. The file
&lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt; contains instructions for yaboot to do its job. The file
yaboot.conf is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; similar in construction to configurations of an older
bootloader for x86 computers, &lt;code&gt;lilo.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in a way similar to what LILO requires, after you install some new
kernel, change some parameter in the configuration file, etc., you have to
run a program that will set up everything so that the boot process can know
of your new configuration. With LILO, this command was called &lt;code&gt;lilo&lt;/code&gt;, while
with yaboot the command is called &lt;code&gt;ybin&lt;/code&gt; (which, essentially, takes care of
putting &lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt; in the bootstrap/HFS partition and blesses the
&lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; binary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Going to GRUB2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the characteristics of yaboot (which is left as an exercise to the
reader to determine if it is a drawback or not) is exactly the way that
changes in the configuration have to be copied to the special HFS partition:
the step of running &lt;code&gt;ybin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GRUB2 (and its older sibling, GRUB legacy) do away with that: during
boot-time, it can understand the filesystems that you have in your computer
and interactively load whatever you want from there, also from a
command-line like OF, before any (regular) operating system has even been
started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; GRUB2? Well, the way that this is performed is
copying a binary to that special HFS partition. Here things start to be
hairy, because GRUB2 has a lot of functionality, but it comes at the price
of it consuming a lot of space (especially if you are using encrypted
partitions or some kind of logical volume managements with some journalling
filesystem that allows files to be compressed etc. on top of it).  The list
goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, that special HFS partition only has 800KB, which, BTW, is the size
of an old 3.5&quot; floppy used with older Macs (note: due to some contraints on
partitions and aligments of such partitions on cylinders, it is not uncommon
for disk partitioning software to create partitions slighly larger than
800KB, but &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; much larger than that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full-featured binary of GRUB2 to be placed on that HFS partition can have
much more than those 800KB. But how do you get that binary, in the first
place? And how do you fit that in the HFS partition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating the GRUB2 binary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the first question, you have to construct it from your
&lt;code&gt;grub-ieee1275&lt;/code&gt; package (I&#39;m assuming here that you are using Debian or
Ubuntu, but similar instructions may apply to other distributions). Then, a
first step would be to create such binary with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; mkdir /tmp/foo
 cd /tmp/foo
 cp -a /usr/lib/grub/powerpc-ieee1275/* .
 grub-mkimage -O powerpc-ieee1275 -o ../grub.img *.mod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last command of these create an executable named &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; that is
callable from OF and which contains every module from &lt;code&gt;grub-ieee1275&lt;/code&gt;.  This
executable that I call here &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; is called, in GRUB2 parlance,
&lt;em&gt;the core image&lt;/em&gt; and it it seems to be named &lt;code&gt;core.img&lt;/code&gt; in many systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my system, with those commands, the binary &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; is about 1208KB,
which is 50% larger than that 800KB partition. And you would like it to be
&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; smaller, becase you want to still have your &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; bootloader by
default while you are evaluating your bootloaders (or using it as a backup
plan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As GRUB2 follow a modular design, you can mix and match the features that
you want. This already hints you to the way we can fit it in the HFS
partition, and it is always the same story: just trim the fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating the configuration file&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also have to have GRUB2 configuration&#39;s file (or you will have to
play with way more commands than you&#39;d want to). An important distinction
here is that you usually have 2 or more partitions on your Mac:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the special bootstrap/HFS partition where OF is going to look at (I&#39;ll
call it &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda2&lt;/code&gt; here);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the partition where your &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; filesystem resides (denoted by &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda3&lt;/code&gt;
here);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some partition to hold &lt;code&gt;/boot&lt;/code&gt; (I don&#39;t have one of these, but let&#39;s say
that it is &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda7&lt;/code&gt; for our discussion purposes), usually containing
your kernels and initial ramdisks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other partitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, you can With Let&#39;s say that this last one, in Linux
parlance, is &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda3&lt;/code&gt; (as is the case of this author), and optionally a
partition where your Linux kernel resides (people usually use it to store
the &lt;code&gt;/boot&lt;/code&gt; subtree of a Linux filesystem). Let&#39;s say that this last one is
&lt;code&gt;/dev/hda7&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, you would compose something like the following as a configuration file
for GRUB2 (named &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;insmod part_apple
insmod ext2
set root=&#39;(hd,apple7)&#39;

menuentry &quot;Linux&quot; {
    linux /vmlinux root=/dev/hda3
    initrd /initrd
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are one two important points here that deserve more comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that, &lt;strong&gt;differently&lt;/strong&gt; from a regular x86 system, in a Mac system with
only one HD the way that you specify an HD does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a trailing
zero. For instance, in the case above of the variable &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt;, we have
&lt;code&gt;(hd,apple7)&lt;/code&gt;, while in a &quot;common PC&quot; we would have the &lt;code&gt;(hd&lt;/code&gt; part
replaced with &lt;code&gt;(hd0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s something that you should make your distribution aware of, if they
aren&#39;t yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an addendum, I don&#39;t know how it works with systems with more than one
HD, as I only have (PowerPC) Macs that are notebooks. If you can share any
experiences, please do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One point of caution here: what GRUB2 calls &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; is not necessarily the
root of your filesystem (i.e., the partition that holds &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;), but the
&lt;em&gt;device&lt;/em&gt; that everything that is &quot;not fully qualified&quot; is interpreted as
being relative to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &quot;not fully qualified&quot; above means anything that is not prefixed with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/grub/manual/grub.html#Device-syntax&quot;&gt;GRUB&#39;s device notation&lt;/a&gt;.
As an example, &lt;code&gt;(hd,apple2)/boot/vmlinux&lt;/code&gt; if fully qualified for GRUB&#39;s
purpose, while &lt;code&gt;/boot/vmlinux&lt;/code&gt; is not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to just copy the files &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; to the
special HFS partition. You can do that using &lt;code&gt;hmount&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;hcopy&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;humount&lt;/code&gt; or you can use the regular Linux &lt;code&gt;hfs&lt;/code&gt; module to copy to that
partition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, boot your system, get into the OF prompt and execute:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;boot hd:2,grub.img
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, the &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; above is a reference to my HFS partition. Substitute that with
yours, appropriately. You will then see the common (familiar?) GRUB prompt
and, from there, everything else that you know will (hopefully) work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The list of modules that &quot;Works for Me(TM)&quot;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, I use a subset of all modules that come with
&lt;code&gt;grub-ieee1275&lt;/code&gt; to create my &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; binary. Here is the list of modules
that I use and that gives me a reasonably sized bootloader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bitmap.mod        datehook.mod  gzio.mod         lsmmap.mod      reboot.mod          terminal.mod
bitmap_scale.mod  datetime.mod  halt.mod         memdisk.mod     regexp.mod          test.mod
blocklist.mod     echo.mod      help.mod         memrw.mod       relocator.mod       trig.mod
boot.mod          elf.mod       hexdump.mod      minicmd.mod     scsi.mod            true.mod
bufio.mod         ext2.mod      hfs.mod          msdospart.mod   search.mod          video.mod
cat.mod           fat.mod       hfsplus.mod      normal.mod      search_fs_file.mod  video_fb.mod
cmp.mod           font.mod      ieee1275_fb.mod  part_apple.mod  search_fs_uuid.mod  videoinfo.mod
configfile.mod    fshelp.mod    linux.mod        part_msdos.mod  search_label.mod
cpio.mod          gettext.mod   loadenv.mod      parttool.mod    setjmp.mod
crypto.mod        gfxmenu.mod   loopback.mod     probe.mod       sleep.mod
date.mod          gfxterm.mod   ls.mod           read.mod        suspend.mod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for the record, my &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; file has 624KB, and that can certainly be
shrunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The command line that &quot;Works for Me(TM)&quot; to create the image&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I lied when I told you that I used the lines above to create my
&lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; file, because I&#39;m lazy and I don&#39;t want to type the &lt;code&gt;.img&lt;/code&gt;
extension. I also &lt;em&gt;embed&lt;/em&gt; my configuration file in the binary that I create
with GRUB2, so that I don&#39;t have two files to copy to my HFS partition, but
only one. I do that with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grub-mkimage -c grub.cfg -o ../grub -O powerpc-ieee1275 -d . *.mod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK. No more lies here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice aspect of GRUB is that one you install that image, you don&#39;t have
to touch that HFS partition anymore: you simply update your regular
filesystem&#39;s &lt;code&gt;/boot/grub/grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; file (which is usually performed when you
install a new kernel, at least with Debian) and you&#39;re ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good way to do that is to use a minimal configuration file embedded in
your &lt;code&gt;grub&lt;/code&gt; binary in your HFS partition that will hook into the system&#39;s
&lt;code&gt;/boot/grub/grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; to read newer kernels and leave the HFS partition (and
your system&#39;s NVRAM) alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I am using right now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;search --no-floppy --fs-uuid --set=root 35d26869-f7c9-4852-a9b8-100314560c34
set prefix=($root)/boot/grub
configfile /boot/grub/grub.cfg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will, of course, want to modify the file above as you install newer
kernels (perhaps even that unsupported operating system from that fruity
company, who knows?). Don&#39;t forget to change the UUID&#39;s, and partition
numbers to fit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&#39;s it. I hope that it helps somebody out there, as the information
that I got otherwise was way outdated, incomplete, etc. to keep up with
GRUB2 from these days. Now, let&#39;s go patch the tools that we have so that
not everybody who wants to use GRUB2 have to learn about its workings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, of course, you can now have your kernels in ext4, btrfs, xfs
etc. partitions without the fear that your bootloader won&#39;t load them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>(Some) Solutions with Chromium</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/some_solutions_with_chromium/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/some_solutions_with_chromium/</link>


	<category>browsers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>extensions</category>

	<category>free-software</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 14:33:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-03-12T03:52:56Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/debian/../../posts/problems_with_chromium/&quot;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I was pointing out some of
my frustrations with Chromium/Chrome.  A very kind reader, Timo Juhani
Lindfors, gave me answers to many of the problems that I pointed out and got
me straight on some issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can disable full zoom in Iceweasel (i.e., I only want to zoom the text,
not the images). According to Chromium&#39;s project BTS, it seems that this
will be a &lt;code&gt;WONTFIX&lt;/code&gt; bug, despite many people asking for it (and it having
a lot of duplicates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timo told me that there is an extension called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ombpcpigmndepfckcifdblemkabaoihk&quot;&gt;&quot;Font Size Increase&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
(ID: ombpcpigmndepfckcifdblemkabaoihk) that adds a button on the side of the
URL bar that you can click to increase the size of the text, without
affecting the size of the images. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that I need this one as much as &quot;Font Size Increase&quot;, but there is also
a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mpajngnpcmjjeoflljdjpnehcfaldcia&quot;&gt;&quot;Font Size Decrease&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (ID: mpajngnpcmjjeoflljdjpnehcfaldcia) that,
as the name implies, decreases the size of the text. It is nice to have this
one when you clicked on the button to increase the size of the font one or
two times too many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I have a way (without resorting to many extensions or
hackish solutions) to use the equivalent of Firefox&#39;s &quot;View &gt; Page Style &gt;
No Style&quot; (i.e., to ignore any CSS sheet that the document author may have
specified on the page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timo also told me that there is a very cool extension called
&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ddpkgkegfklikkmfmneldonhldahhacb&quot;&gt;&quot;Chrome Page Style&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (ID: ddpkgkegfklikkmfmneldonhldahhacb) that
allows you to alternate between stylesheets provided by the page (see Joey
Hess&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://ikiwiki.info/css_market/&quot;&gt;ikiwiki&#39;s CSS Market&lt;/a&gt; for an example of that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also has the possibility of disabling all the CSS&#39;es that a page may
have, which, in many cases around the web &lt;em&gt;actually improves&lt;/em&gt; the
readability of the pages, for many &quot;fancy&quot; things detract from readability,
especially if you have poor eyesight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I had said that I didn&#39;t want to resort to extensions, this was a
simple solution enough that made me consider revisit my requirements.  I do,
though, wonder why some frequently used extensions are not built into the
programs from stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I can press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Q&lt;/code&gt; and make the damn browser quit, instead
of me having to use the mouse/trackpad/pointing device. This is probably a
lack of my understanding on how to associate key bindings to Chromium, but
the problem still stands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Timo also set me straight and told me about &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shift+Q&lt;/code&gt; for
that purpose, which I had missed completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, when there is only one tab open, pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; in Chromium
does not close the tab (say, presenting me a blank tab or the list of most
visited sites), nor it closes the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a poor writing of my part, &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; does close the tabs. But when there
is only one tab present, it doesn&#39;t close the window. I&#39;m OK with that,
since I now know the way to close the window. Thanks again Timo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one point that may not be known by many is that using &lt;code&gt;about:flags&lt;/code&gt;
in Chrome does something analogue to Firefox&#39;s &lt;code&gt;about:config&lt;/code&gt; (even with the
warning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And tweaking with it you can try to see if you can enable hardware
acceleration of some parts of your pages, as present in newer releases of
Chromium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there I am: way more satisfied than with earlier with Chromium, but
still having Firefox/Iceweasel as my primary browser. Good to have two
usable browsers now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>My problems with Chromium</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/problems_with_chromium/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/problems_with_chromium/</link>


	<category>browsers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>extensions</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>launchpad</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 11:55:06 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-03-12T03:52:56Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Given that Chromium/Chrome is used more and more (as became apparent
&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.debian.org/debian-release/2010/09/msg00610.html&quot;&gt;with the discussion of including it in Debian&#39;s squeeze&lt;/a&gt;), I decided to
give it some tries, mainly Giuseppe Iuculano&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.qa.debian.org/c/chromium-browser.html&quot;&gt;version&lt;/a&gt;. I occasionally
install Chromium from Fabien Tassin&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~chromium-daily/+archive/ppa&quot;&gt;daily builds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, to be honest, I have also contributed a good amount (about 400) of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~rbrito/+karma&quot;&gt;translated strings&lt;/a&gt; to the Brazilian Portuguese part of Chromium. As a
matter of fact, I have even done some &quot;activism&quot; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~savanabifulco&quot;&gt;incentivated&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~bifulcojunior&quot;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~victor.westmann/+karma&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; to create their accounts on Launchpad and help with
the projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I always come back to Iceweasel/Firefox, especially with Mike Hommey&#39;s
frequently updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozilla.debian.net/&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are my reasons for staying with Iceweasel, and not with Chromium?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can disable full zoom in Iceweasel (i.e., I only want to zoom the text,
not the images). According to Chromium&#39;s project BTS, it seems that this
will be a &lt;code&gt;WONTFIX&lt;/code&gt; bug, despite many people asking for it (and it having
a lot of duplicates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can, in Iceweasel, set my preferred fonts without resorting to hacks on
the system level, like say, having to lie with fontconfig or other stuff.
And I really want Deja Vu Sans, not a serifed font.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, a middle mouse click on &quot;an inactive portion&quot; of the page
makes me go to the URL that is the system clipboard, just like pasting
stuff in X, in general, works.  I guess that there may be some way to
enable this in Chromium, but, so far, I have not found it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I have a way (without resorting to many extensions or
hackish solutions) to use the equivalent of Firefox&#39;s &quot;View &gt; Page Style &gt;
No Style&quot; (i.e., to ignore any CSS sheet that the document author may have
specified on the page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, my personal data is encrypted before being synced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I can press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Q&lt;/code&gt; and make the damn browser quit, instead
of me having to use the mouse/trackpad/pointing device. This is probably a
lack of my understanding on how to associate key bindings to Chromium, but
the problem still stands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, when there is only one tab open, pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; in Chromium
does not close the tab (say, presenting me a blank tab or the list of most
visited sites), nor it closes the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I would be satisfied if any of the above were fixed or better documented,
but it seems that some of those are, at best, going to wait a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>First post from DebConf 10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/first-post-from-debconf-10/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/first-post-from-debconf-10/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>people</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 06:09:46 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2010-08-03T09:09:46Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I am late with this post, it is nice to say that I am writing here from this year&#39;s DebConf10, in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today (well, yesterday) was the day of the Cheese and Wine party and I think that it was cool, at least for the moments that I were there. This post, though, isn&#39;t technical in any sense. I only talks shortly about my impressions of the community, as this is my first DebConf ever (despite the fact that I have been using Debian since the late nineties).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very pleased to have met Bdale Garbee. I saw him the other day arriving with Keith Packard, but I just didn&#39;t want to disturb them at that point. We only talked for, say, 2 minutes, and his was one of the nicest receptions that I had here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there were some other people that were equally easy to approach, nice to talk with and, to my surprise, knew my name after some brief moments (yes, this &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make a difference, especially when you are in a strange country, when you don&#39;t know anybody with whom you have worked for some years). Being involved in the organization stuff, one would think that Jimmy Kaplowitz would be so busy, but he was so kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had longer conversations with Tássia Camões, Tiago Vaz (as always) and some other people that I had not yet had the pleasure of meeting in person. In particular, Daniel Baumann (who apparently is now crazy about our FISL and wants to drink all Guaraná that he can get &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt;), Chris Lamb and Otávio Salvador and his mom. Those people are so cool and it is nice to discuss some legal issues among different continents in the lounge of their building at late night. &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt; Too bad that I am allocated to the other building. &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; forgetting many other people (hey, it is 2 am here in NYC), but I would feel guilty if I had not mentioned at least three people more: Martin Michlmayr, Phil Hands, and Reinhard Tartler (who is uploading lame to the debian repository, as the patents regarding it are expiring or expired already).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: I just created an account on flickr that I hope to populate with some photos that I took here. And even with a nice squirrel. &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>I am going to DebConf 10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>fonts</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>web-of-trust</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 03:34:40 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2010-07-18T06:34:40Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I just bought my tickets today to NYC and I am glady to say that I am going to Debconf 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;attachment_55&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; caption=&quot;I am going to DebConf10&quot;]&lt;a rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-55&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost/blog/2010/07/18/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/im_going_to_debconf10/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-55 &quot; title=&quot;im_going_to_debconf10&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/im_going_to_debconf10.png&quot; alt=&quot;I am going to DebConf10&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;101&quot;  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets have this information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRU-&amp;gt;JFK:&lt;/strong&gt; Departure: 2010-07-30, 21:25; Arrival: 2010-07-31, 6:10, Flight AA950&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JFK-&amp;gt;GRU:&lt;/strong&gt; Departure: 2010-08-09, 21:40; Arrival: 2010-08-10, 8:35, Flight AA951&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This represents a personal milestone for me, as I have many plans for the conference. In fact, this will be a trip of many &quot;firsts&quot; for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be my first international trip by airplaine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be my first DebConf ever (despite the fact that I could not apply for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://upsilon.cc/~zack/blog/posts/2010/04/the_DebConf_Newbies_initiative/&quot;&gt;DebConf Newbies initiative&lt;/a&gt;, due to my visa interview being delayed until the 7th of this month).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be the first time to see many people with whom I work together for some years now, but have not yet had the opportunity to meet in person.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a nice opportunity to work hard on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/Articles/396079/&quot;&gt;some issues that threaten the PowerPC port&lt;/a&gt; of Debian.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a nice opportunity to do some QA work with some packages that I would like to have sponsored; also to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/551955&quot;&gt;upload&lt;/a&gt; some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/580005&quot;&gt;fonts&lt;/a&gt; that I &lt;a href=&quot;http://git.debian.org/?p=pkg-fonts/ttf-paratype-sans.git&quot;&gt;already packaged&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/581839&quot;&gt;intend&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/589094&quot;&gt;take care&lt;/a&gt;) and that will be maintained under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a very nice opportunity to get myself in a &quot;big&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strongly_connected_component&quot;&gt;strongly connected component &lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_of_trust&quot;&gt;Web-of-Trust&lt;/a&gt; with as many arcs as feasible, by means of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~anibal/ksp-dc10/ksp-dc10.html&quot;&gt;key signing party.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and many, many other things that I would like to do for the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am thankful for the DebConf team sponsoring both accomodation and food.  It is highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in NYC! Any hints that you may happen to have are warmly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>A version of xpdf with the poppler backend available</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/a-version-of-xpdf-with-the-poppler-backend-available/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/a-version-of-xpdf-with-the-poppler-backend-available/</link>


	<category>c++</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>documents</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>libraries</category>

	<category>programming</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 19:46:13 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-03-12T03:27:55Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&#39;s been some time since I last wrote here and things are quite hectic, due to some real-life happenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Announcement&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For those people that are insterested in a &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; PDF viewer, based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://poppler.freedesktop.org/&quot;&gt;an actively maintained backend&lt;/a&gt;, and that &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/blog/2010/05/27/please-let-me-zoom-my-documents/&quot;&gt;doesn&#39;t bring your computer to a halt&lt;/a&gt; when you try to zoom your documents when you need to see some details, then you might want to give &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/rbrito/xpdf-poppler&quot;&gt;this version of xpdf&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already received some reports for some bugs and fixed them, with one of them being a problem related by a kind user of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gentoo.org/&quot;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some people have asked me why this even needs to exist in the first place and I agree that it would be better if it didn&#39;t: I would love to spend my time actually &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; my computers rather than &lt;em&gt;fixing&lt;/em&gt; my computers for better tasks (read: studying Mathematics, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upstream maintainer of xpdf uses it as one source of income and keeps it running across many system (even legacy ones).  I &lt;em&gt;imagine&lt;/em&gt; that this one of the reasons why he tries to keep xpdf almost self contained, with many parts that could be delegated to other libraries, and with some abstraction code that makes the code compile even in the presence of &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; broken compilers.  Of course, this means, in part, that as long as you take more duties, maintaing the code becomes more and more complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me that he doesn&#39;t offer an open development tree because he wants to give his customers some advantages over the public version and his reasons are perfectly justifiable, of course.  He also manifested the interest of possibly basing xpdf on a &quot;more modern toolkit&quot; and, when I asked him what that would be, he mentioned that, perhaps, it would be Qt. The development of xpdf will, quite probably, take newer directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, xpdf has not seen a new upstream release since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foolabs.com/xpdf/CHANGES&quot;&gt;2007-02-27&lt;/a&gt;.  It did, though, have &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl1.patch&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl2.patch&quot;&gt;patchlevel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl3.patch&quot;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl4.patch&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;. Taking care of the maintainance of the code is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/527840&quot;&gt;high concern&lt;/a&gt; for distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people, though, would like to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&quot;&gt;keep it simple&lt;/a&gt; (me included).  Unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/351279&quot;&gt;some efforts&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2010/06/msg00046.html&quot;&gt;maintain&lt;/a&gt; it had &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=289803&quot;&gt;not had&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2010/06/msg00068.html&quot;&gt;necessary coordination&lt;/a&gt; and duplication of effort has occured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am willing to become a patch aggregator for the code in xpdf with a poppler backend. I would love to give it some refactoring too, drop some of the legacy code that is not used (and only serves to make the code hard to read), and adopt some good coding style standard (I particularly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/CodingStyle&quot;&gt;like the one from the Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt;---with the proper adaptations for C++).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have already &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=323469&quot;&gt;contacted the people at Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;, and I would love to get people from Fedora, Ubuntu, and Suse involved also. Alas,  the last time I tried to mail their mailing lists, I got  messages telling me that my messages were rejected or waiting for moderation, because I was not a subscriber. I never heard back, since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate it if you could help spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
