<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged debian</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 13:49:20 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>The importance of flexible deadlines in MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 13:48:59 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-04-04T16:49:20Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have always thought that having flexible deadlines in MOOCs is important,
despite not having used them too much. Until last night, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course in question is Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://statlearning.class.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning&lt;/a&gt; and they
adopted a policy of letting the students complete all the assignments of the
10 week course until the last day of the course, in March 21. Then, they
graciously extended the deadline to April 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it not for such an extension, I would not have completed the course. I
sent them a message on the course forums this morning to thank them for
this, as this, in my experience, is not so common with MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reproduce below the message that I posted on the forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Thank you also for the EXTENSION of the deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Dear professors and staff,&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you (of course) for the course, as many others have
  already. Despite not liking edX platform too much (preferring the UI of,
  say, Coursera), your course was an exception, interesting enough (and funny
  enough) that I sticked to it until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But I would like to bring attention here to a point that many may not have
  appreciated (or, perhaps, not expressed as clearly as I thought that it
  deserved), namely, the extension of the deadlines (and a uniform deadline
  for all homeworks).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, due to some unfortunate facts of my personal life, I could
  not work on the course at all in the past few weeks. In fact, I completed
  units 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 in the last 3 or 4 days and submitted my
  last quiz a few hours before today&#39;s midnight (at my local time, UTC-0300),
  and I still got a passing grade(!).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Even with my desire to finish the course, this would not have been
  possible if you had not graciously allowed for the deadline extension. I am
  sure that I may not be alone here in appreciating this extension (even
  though I think that I may be many standard deviations from the mean, doing
  the homework and R programs of 7 weeks in only 4 days).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Thank you so very much for everything (including this extension!),&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Rogério Brito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 02:35:11 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-03-03T05:35:23Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian/../../posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Paco de Lucia</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-27_paco_de_lucia/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-27_paco_de_lucia/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 21:48:04 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-03-03T04:43:11Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I was super sad to know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paco%20de%20Lucia&quot;&gt;Paco de Lucia&lt;/a&gt; passed a few days
ago. It was shocking to know that he was so young (only 66 year old, if I am
not mistaken).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share some of his fine work with his frequent collaborators
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John%20McLaughlin&quot;&gt;John McLaughlin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Al%20Di%20Meola&quot;&gt;Al Di Meola&lt;/a&gt; to people that
may not otherwise know him or his work, I offered on a Facebook post to
upload a bootleg of a show of the Guitar Trio (John McLaughlin, Paco De
Lucia and Al Di Meola) with the entire performance (possibly out of order,
as that is a bootleg, after all) ripped from a broadcast to Dutch TV
station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This performance includes the exceptional Paco de Lucia prominently and the
show has many songs from the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friday%20Night%20in%20San%20Francisco&quot;&gt;Friday Night in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&quot;
record, including the magnificent (IMVHO)
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mediterranean%20Sundance&quot;&gt;Mediterranean Sundance&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The credits of the video are, of course, of the musicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only ripped, deinterlaced (remember, analog TV&amp;mdash;it was interlaced),
denoised, encoded, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/0tzfUYz2t5w&quot;&gt;uploaded the video to youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Trivial fact #3: Continued fractions via matrices</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-23-trivial_fact_3/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-23-trivial_fact_3/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>tex</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 23:30:30 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-26T03:11:47Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Note&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, it&#39;s not Debian planet that has problems to deal with MathJax
(which makes posts usingn it appear illegible on Debian planet), but the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/ikiwiki-plugin-mathjax&quot;&gt;ikiwiki plugin&lt;/a&gt; that I am using which generates garbage in the feeds
that get consumed by planet.debian.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you it know of a better plugin (which doesn&#39;t generate such output)
please let me know, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; if it is not super computationally
expensive for a Core 2 Duo T7250 (which is my notebook).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;therealthing&quot;&gt;The real thing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://wstein.org/&quot;&gt;William Stein&lt;/a&gt; is now offering a course on Number Theory and he has
been posting recorded videos of his lectures, I started watching some of
them (mainly, the ones regarding continued factions).  In particular, he
shows the usual recursive formula for convergents of a continued fraction
and that&#39;s super nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the curious reader, the recurrence relations for the convergents of
!!mathjaxbegin-i!! W2FfMCwgYV8xLCBcbGRvdHMsIGFfbiwgXGxkb3RzXQ==
 !!mathjaxend-i!! are:
!!mathjaxbegin-d!! CnBfbiA9IGFfbiBwX3tuLTF9ICsgcF97bi0yfVxcCnFfbiA9IGFfbiBxX3tuLTF9ICsgcV97bi0y
fSwK
 !!mathjaxend-d!! with initial conditions (!!mathjaxbegin-i!! cF97LTJ9ID0gMA==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, !!mathjaxbegin-i!! cF97LTF9ID0gMQ==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, !!mathjaxbegin-i!! cF8wID0gYV8w
 !!mathjaxend-i!!,
!!mathjaxbegin-i!! cV97LTJ9ID0gMQ==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, !!mathjaxbegin-i!! cV97LTF9ID0gMA==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, !!mathjaxbegin-i!! cV8wID0gMQ==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He even motivated the use of continued fractions with the golden ratio,
which is super nice, given that I like the subject and have been writing a
document collecting facts that I know about the Fibonacci numbers (well,
this document is horribly incomplete and not even close to something that I
would consider proper for public consumption&amp;mdash;I plan on publishing
them soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, after he discussed the basics of it convergents, he noted that the
recurrence relations are like those defining the Fibonacci numbers, just
that one of the terms is &quot;weighted&quot; by the coefficients of the continued
fraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I missed one thing, though: neither &lt;a href=&quot;http://wstein.org/ent/&quot;&gt;his book&lt;/a&gt; nor wikipedia&#39;s article on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/continued%20fractions&quot;&gt;continued fractions&lt;/a&gt; mentions a very neat, alternative way to
express the convergents of continued fractions (truth be said, I took a
quick peek at wikipedia&#39;s article and I found that it doesn&#39;t mentionat
least explicitly, in a 1 min skim&amp;mdash;it may well be buried somewhere
else).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, then, &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/115360165819500279592/posts/guGv6w9jmxr&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; the following exercise for his students (which he
apparently liked, as he +1&#39;s the suggestion):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prove that the recurrence relation of the !!mathjaxbegin-i!! cF9p
 !!mathjaxend-i!!&#39;s and !!mathjaxbegin-i!! cV9p
 !!mathjaxend-i!!&#39;s that we
mentioned before can be obtained via matrix multiplication. More precisely,
prove that:
!!mathjaxbegin-d!! ClxiZWdpbntibWF0cml4fQphXzAgJmFtcDsgMVxcCjEgJmFtcDsgMApcZW5ke2JtYXRyaXh9Clxi
ZWdpbntibWF0cml4fQphXzEgJmFtcDsgMVxcCjEgJmFtcDsgMApcZW5ke2JtYXRyaXh9ClxjZG90
cwpcYmVnaW57Ym1hdHJpeH0KYV9uICZhbXA7IDFcXAoxICZhbXA7IDAKXGVuZHtibWF0cml4fQog
PQpcYmVnaW57Ym1hdHJpeH0KcF9uICZhbXA7IHBfe24tMX1cXApxX24gJmFtcDsgcV97bi0xfQpc
ZW5ke2JtYXRyaXh9Lgo=
 !!mathjaxend-d!!
As a corollary, derive Cassini&#39;s identity for the Fibonacci Numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, if you any errors on this, please let me know so that I can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks &quot;noone&quot; for spotting a typographical error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Some new Youtube-dl functionality</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-17-youtube-dl_news/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-17-youtube-dl_news/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>

	<category>python</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 18:27:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian/../../posts/2013-10-23-assorted_news/#youtube-dl&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; that
Youtube changed their way of delivering videos, with the use of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic%20Adaptive%20Streaming%20over%20HTTP&quot;&gt;Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP&lt;/a&gt;.  On top of that, they
started serving both the audio and the video in separate streams, which
meant trouble for downloader tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtube-dl.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in that previous post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What does this mean in practical terms for users of youtube-dl?  Well, if
  you wanted to download videos in resolutions like the 480p (format 35)
  that I mentioned, then you will probably have to change your way of doing
  things, until a more automated solution is in place.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;You will have to download both the audio and the video and, then,
  &quot;combine&quot; them (that is, multiplex them) to create one &quot;normal&quot; video file
  with both the audio and the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And latter, I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Otherwise, to download 480p videos (which I do for lectures and so on with
  other projects of mine, like edx-dl) I have to call youtube-dl twice: once
  for format 135 and another for format 140, since the old &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian/../../smileys/question.png&quot; alt=&quot;(?)&quot; /&gt; format 35
  files are much smaller than the lower resolution 360p files (due to the
  former being encoded in High profile vs. the latter being encoded in
  Constrained Baseline profile).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, now, we don&#39;t have this problem anymore:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new release of &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; brings us many goodies, including that it is
possible to &lt;em&gt;automatically&lt;/em&gt; combine/merge/multiplex audio and video formats
that Youtube now offers separately (See the previous comments about separate
audio and video).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you want a 480p video in H.264 format, High profile, with 128kbps
AAC audio (this used to be Youtube&#39;s format 35), you can specify format &lt;code&gt;-f
135+140&lt;/code&gt; on the command-line and it will download both the audio, the video
and multiplex it with &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;avconv&lt;/code&gt;, depending on what you have
installed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides being convenient, this automatic downloading and merging makes it
unnecessary to write scripts to, say, retrieve all the videos in a playlist
that contains a lot of lectures (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EPQgeAz264g&amp;amp;list=PLA58AC5CABC1321A3&quot;&gt;one example here&lt;/a&gt;, taught by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benedict%20Gross&quot;&gt;Benedict Gross&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 2014.02.17 of &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; will be soon in your favorite mirror of
the Debian archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Miscellanea</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-14_miscellanea/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-14_miscellanea/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>ffmpeg</category>

	<category>libav</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:59:22 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;initsystem&quot;&gt;Init system&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy that Debian&#39;s Technical Committee was able to reach a very good
decision with the choice of systemd as the default init system for the Linux
ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I was very pleasantly surprised by the lucidity of Russ
Allbery&#39;s analyses and, above all, his &lt;em&gt;patience&lt;/em&gt; even with people that, in
my understanding, were just being trolls or trying to cause confusion and
disrupt a process that was already chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russ, thank you for your exemplary role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also, you type fast or what? You fill whole e-mails seemingly faster than I
can read!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unexpectedunionofforces&quot;&gt;Unexpected union of forces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that Mark Shutterworth&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/1316&quot;&gt;decision&lt;/a&gt; of (perhaps?)
embracing Debian&#39;s decision in the init system is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that one way where Ubuntu did a great thing with respect to Debian
was their initial attitude towards cherry-picking the best of breed of Free
Software from Debian&#39;s archive and polishing that to create a really &quot;for
human beings&quot; operating system.  I hope that this means that, at least in
part, money (Mark&#39;s?) can be channeled in the best of the interests so that
we all gain from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And, to be honest, I see no problem in making money with Free Software and
I welcome a well done integration job).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;morepolarizingthings&quot;&gt;More polarizing things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that, now, I may even have some hope of sending another
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/729203&quot;&gt;potentially polarizing&lt;/a&gt; bug to the Tech Ctte (that is ffmpeg vs. libav)
and have faith that some rational decision would be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not even aware of it, but the ffmpeg folks even
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ffmpeg.org/&quot;&gt;featured a news item in their page&lt;/a&gt; of me having filed the RFP bug
mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;debconf14&quot;&gt;DebConf 14&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes as expected, I hope to attend this year&#39;s DebConf.  In
fact, I am anticipating this, since I would love to, e.g., talk with Joey
Hess and discuss a better way of having &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/parallel/&quot;&gt;GNU parallel&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt;
program in &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/moreutils&quot;&gt;moreutils&lt;/a&gt; have amicable co-installability among many,
many other things with respect to my packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, quite probably, work on packaging ffmpeg with other interested people
(which seem to be numerous).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Fix markdown link pointing twice to the ffmpeg site. Thanks
Marius Gedminas for pointing this out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Trivial fact #2: Harmonic Numbers</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-30-trivial_fact_2/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-30-trivial_fact_2/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>tex</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:43:30 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-30T02:44:49Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know how Debian planet deals with MathJax (it seems to
become illegible), but I will try to post this, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fact:&lt;/strong&gt; Since the harmonic numbers can be approximated by the
natural logarithm, that is, !!mathjaxbegin-i!! SF9uIFxzaW1lcSBcbG4gbg==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, we can clearly
see that
!!mathjaxbegin-d!! CiBcZnJhY3sxfXtpKzF9ICsgXGNkb3RzICsgXGZyYWN7MX17bn0gPSBIX24gLSBIX2kgXHNpbWVx
IFxsbiBuIC0gXGxuIGkgPSBcbG4gXGZyYWN7bn17aX0sCg==
 !!mathjaxend-d!!
which is a trivial approximation that may be handy sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spot any errors on this, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Developing for Android with Debian</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 20:18:04 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-17T22:17:37Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have just enrolled in a MOOC to learn about programming with Android.
There are many tutorials and reports of people using Linux for the
development of the apps out there, but, unfortunately, many of them are
outdated or contain misleading information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will find bazillion instructions out there telling you to install
JDK6. (Even the instructions in the MOOCs say so, and Google says that it is
the only supported version of Java). Even more than that, some of them will
tell you that you should &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; use OpenJDK, but use Oracle&#39;s JDK instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you have a pure &lt;code&gt;amd64&lt;/code&gt; system and you try to install the x86-64
version of Google&#39;s Android Developer Tools (ADT), you are going to have a
surprise: you will have all sorts of programs telling you that you have file
not found, even though the required binaries are there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is, of course, besides install &lt;code&gt;openjdk-7-jdk&lt;/code&gt;, if you wish to use the
integrated Eclipse environment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that the so-called 64-bit ADT/SDK actually has many 32-bit
executables(!) and they aren&#39;t statically linked. Inspecting them, I needed
the following packages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    gcc-4.8-base:i386
    libc6-i686:i386
    libc6:i386
    libgcc1:i386
    libstdc++6:i386
    zlib1g:i386
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth observing that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libstdc++6:i386&lt;/code&gt; depends (transitively) on &lt;code&gt;libc6:i386&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;libgcc1:i386&lt;/code&gt;,
and &lt;code&gt;gcc-4.8-base:i386&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;zlib1g:i386&lt;/code&gt; depends (transitively) on &lt;code&gt;libc6:i386&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;libgcc1:i386&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;gcc-4.8-base:i386&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the above, and given that the version of the GCC libraries can vary a
lot, it is perhaps better to simply do something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install libstdc++6:i386 zlib1g:i386
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although not necessary, since you are using an amd64 machine, your computer
already supports many more recent instructions that will be used if you
install the package &lt;code&gt;libc6-i686:i386&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid the emulator from spitting out error messages related to &lt;code&gt;libGL.so&lt;/code&gt;,
install &lt;code&gt;libgl1-mesa-dev&lt;/code&gt; (note: &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;i386&lt;/code&gt; here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, you will be able to run the embedded QEMU with full KVM
acceleration if you pass the options &lt;code&gt;-qemu -m 1024 -enable-kvm&lt;/code&gt; on
Eclipse&#39;s &quot;Run &gt; Run Configurations... &gt; Target &gt; Additional Emulator
Command Line Options&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, you are probably good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Trivial fact: convexity of polyhedra</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-12-11-trivial_fact_convexity_of_polyhedra/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-12-11-trivial_fact_convexity_of_polyhedra/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:27:41 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-12-11T02:35:41Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Just a trivial fact: every polyhedron that is used in linear programming is
convex, that is !!mathjaxbegin-i!! QXggXGxlcSBi
 !!mathjaxend-i!! is convex, for a matrix !!mathjaxbegin-i!! QQ==
 !!mathjaxend-i!! and a (column)
vector !!mathjaxbegin-i!! Yg==
 !!mathjaxend-i!!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; Take any !!mathjaxbegin-i!! eCcsIHgnJw==
 !!mathjaxend-i!! that satisfy the system of inequalities !!mathjaxbegin-i!! QXggXGxlcSBi
 !!mathjaxend-i!!.
Then, for !!mathjaxbegin-i!! MCBcbGVxIFxsYW1iZGEgXGxlcSAx
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, we have that !!mathjaxbegin-i!! XGxhbWJkYSBBeCcgXGxlcSBcbGFtYmRhIGI=
 !!mathjaxend-i!!,
that is !!mathjaxbegin-i!! QSBcbGFtYmRhIHgnIFxsZXEgXGxhbWJkYSBi
 !!mathjaxend-i!!.  Similarly, for !!mathjaxbegin-i!! eCcn
 !!mathjaxend-i!!, we have
that !!mathjaxbegin-i!! QSAoMS1cbGFtYmRhKSB4JyBcbGVxICgxLVxsYW1iZGEpIGI=
 !!mathjaxend-i!!. Summing the inequalities, we
get:
!!mathjaxbegin-d!! CiBBW1xsYW1iZGEgeCcgKyAoMS1cbGFtYmRhKSB4JyddIFxsZXEgW1xsYW1iZGEgKyAoMS1cbGFt
YmRhKV0gYiA9IGIsCg==
 !!mathjaxend-d!!
which means that !!mathjaxbegin-i!! XGhhdHt4fSA9IFxsYW1iZGEgeCcgKyAoMS1cbGFtYmRhKSB4Jyc=
 !!mathjaxend-i!! is again a
solution of the original set of inequalities, thus concluding the argument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Assorted random notes</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-10-23-assorted_news/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-10-23-assorted_news/</link>



	<category>btrfs</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>filesystem</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>python</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 21:08:42 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-11-06T17:36:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This post is just a bunch of random notes, but I think that things are going
well, this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;btrfs&quot;&gt;Btrfs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just started playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/btrfs&quot;&gt;btrfs&lt;/a&gt; after converting a 2TB disk
with about 1.3TB of data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ext4&quot;&gt;ext4&lt;/a&gt; to btrfs.  This particular
filesystem contains my backup data and I hope that btrfs is able to live up
to high standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will probably write a detailed review with my impressions, but suffice to
say that it is working fine and I hope that I will be happy for a long time
to come. My other filesystems, for the moment, will be ext4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;courseradownloader&quot;&gt;Coursera Downloader&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jplehmann&quot;&gt;John Lehmann&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s generosity, now &lt;code&gt;coursera-dl&lt;/code&gt; has a new home:
a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coursera-dl&quot;&gt;github organization&lt;/a&gt; of its own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;youtube-dl&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl/issues/1612&quot;&gt;Some people may have noticed, others may not&lt;/a&gt;, but when downloading
videos from Youtube, they apparently are getting more aggressive with the
use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic%20Adaptive%20Streaming%20over%20HTTP&quot;&gt;Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP&lt;/a&gt; (also called
DASH) and, as a result, some (perhaps going to be all in the near future?)
of the videos may not be available in the resolution/formats that you used
to like (like me, with format number 35).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, one thing that is interesting with youtube videos provided via
DASH is that they are available in different streams: one for the video and
another for the audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean in practical terms for users of youtube-dl?  Well, if
you wanted to download videos in resolutions like the 480p (format 35) that
I mentioned, then you will probably have to change your way of doing things,
until a more automated solution is in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to download both the audio and the video and, then, &quot;combine&quot;
them (that is, multiplex them) to create one &quot;normal&quot; video file with both
the audio and the video. I usually do this via:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
ffmpeg -i audio.m4a -i video.mp4 -vcodec copy -acodec copy combined.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer having a Matroska container instead of an mp4 container
(which, BTW, results in &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; muxing overhead), then you can use the
command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
mkvmerge -o combined.mkv audio.m4a video.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, those &lt;code&gt;m4a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt; extensions are a new addition that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl/pull/1622&quot;&gt;I just sent upstream&lt;/a&gt; (in the past, both would have been named with an
extension of &lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As, an aside, I like formats &lt;code&gt;135&lt;/code&gt; for video and &lt;code&gt;140&lt;/code&gt; for audio, for the
reasons that I mentioned in a comments to issue 1612:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Otherwise, to download 480p videos (which I do for lectures and so on with
  other projects of mine, like edx-dl) I have to call youtube-dl twice: once
  for format 135 and another for format 140, since the old &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian/../../smileys/question.png&quot; alt=&quot;(?)&quot; /&gt; format 35
  files are much smaller than the lower resolution 360p files (due to the
  former being encoded in High profile vs. the latter being encoded in
  Constrained Baseline profile).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is unfortunate for some, this is a good thing for others: I once
had a blind user of &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; asking me if he could avoid downloading the
whole video just to extract the audio, so that he save on bandwidth. Well,
now this is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect a new version of &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; to be uploaded soon to Debian unstable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;music&quot;&gt;Music&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is so nice to see the music that I like getting better. It was
particularly pleasant to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/hAnVFJFmFx8&quot;&gt;see&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarja%20Turunen&quot;&gt;Tarja Turunen&lt;/a&gt; being joined
on stage by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Floor%20Jansen&quot;&gt;Floor Jansen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it is my impression that the once female-fronted bands are getting
more and more into collaborations and side-projects and they are, in many
ways, getting more refined. Examples of this includes Floor, Tarja,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anneke%20van%20Giersbergen&quot;&gt;Anneke van Giersbergen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sharon%20den%20Adel&quot;&gt;Sharon den Adel&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kari%20Ruesl%C3%A5tten&quot;&gt;Kari Rueslåtten&lt;/a&gt; and many others that I can&#39;t remember right
now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, some thanks to people that take the time to film, and
upload/share the videos so that other people not at these events can watch
them is highly appreciated and they usually are treated as anonymous, but,
of course, this should be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
