<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged multimedia</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/multimedia/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/multimedia/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/multimedia/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2013-01-30T00:16:56Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Looking for (Free) a Video Editor</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/dear_lazyweb_what_is_a_good_free_video_editor/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/dear_lazyweb_what_is_a_good_free_video_editor/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="lazyweb" />

	<category term="multimedia" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2013-01-30T00:16:56Z</updated>
	<published>2013-01-30T00:16:07Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s suppose that you went to a show of your favourite some time ago and
you were able to sneak in a camera (well, in those times, cell phones
weren&#39;t able to record much more than 176x144 pixels at 12fps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, then, you suddenly found that some people uploaded (short) fragments of
that very same show to youtube and, collecting those, you may be able to
create a &quot;multi-camera&quot; version of the video that you can record to keep of
your memorable concert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The multi-camera, in the sense above, is not the same as
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DVD-Video#Chapters_and_angles&quot;&gt;multiple angles&lt;/a&gt; (like some DVDs), but something like a TV broadcast,
where the stage is filmed by cameras positioned at some places and the image
that is broadcast is switched from time to time according to that who is
singing, or playing etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Dear Lazyweb, do we happen to have any Free Software (preferably already
packaged in Debian) that is able to help with the task of &quot;aligning&quot; (in
time) videos from various (different) sources so as to produce one
multi-camera video?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would my options be? I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e7IPeuK1tQ&amp;amp;lc=Zwz7xq5ANT43j64jh8zLRYCMVRnJQgINcgSOhf-5Ozg&quot;&gt;asked this&lt;/a&gt; on youtube for a person that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e7IPeuK1tQ&quot;&gt;did exactly what I want&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e7IPeuK1tQ&amp;amp;lc=Zwz7xq5ANT6jkGhCF9g1RzmZAsFIGmYzChDJwqwovNc&quot;&gt;their answer&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sony_Vegas_Pro&quot;&gt;Sony Vegas&lt;/a&gt;,
which I fear that does not exactly would be allowed in Debian. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/multimedia/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any comments are welcome, thanks, and if I am successful, I will upload the
final video. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/multimedia/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>I am not going to DebConf 12</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/"/>






	<category term="debconf" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="development" />

	<category term="fonts" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="handbrake" />

	<category term="multimedia" />


	<updated>2012-06-07T04:58:09Z</updated>
	<published>2012-06-07T04:59:42Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Due to some real life impediments (including a beautiful one with just over
2 months of life called Daniel), I will not be able to go to this year&#39;s
DebConf, even though it seems that this DebConf will exceed many
expectations with the support that the governement of Nicaragua just
offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Things that I would like to have worked on&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this means that I will not be working with some fellows that
may be there, like people from the &lt;code&gt;pkg-multimedia&lt;/code&gt; team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, as I am working on some packages that are not that well
suited to distributions (especially regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://handbrake.fr/&quot;&gt;HandBrake&lt;/a&gt;), it would be
highly productive to have a hacking session or two with other people
interested in having this popular and easy-to-use video ripper/transcoder on
Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to be able to talk in person with other people (including
&lt;a href=&quot;http://joeyh.name/blog/&quot;&gt;Joey Hess&lt;/a&gt;) about controversial packaging of some programs, like GNU
Parallel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/parallel&quot;&gt;which I maintain in Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things else that I would love to work on, besides helping a
bit with some of the still pending transitions of the the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;, meeting friends and other social
stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, well. I guess that working at home will be the solution for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Preliminary support for webm in youtube-dl</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/preliminary-support-for-webm-in-youtube-dl/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/preliminary-support-for-webm-in-youtube-dl/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hacks" />

	<category term="libraries" />

	<category term="multimedia" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2011-03-12T03:27:55Z</updated>
	<published>2010-05-29T20:06:18Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I just added some very, very preliminary support for web in &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; which &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel-changes/2010/05/msg02694.html&quot;&gt;I uploaded&lt;/a&gt; to unstable some minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, at least people will have some material (in, fact, a chance) to play with this format.  I implemented this because, so far, I was only hoping here that a player for this would emerge. I guess that Debian&#39;s ffmpeg/mplayer will take some time, but I was pleased to see that Sebastian Dröge to upload a version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel-changes/2010/05/msg02596.html&quot;&gt;something&lt;/a&gt; that could use the new &lt;code&gt;libvpx&lt;/code&gt; codec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that, now, as a side effect of webm being widely available, more people become interested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorbis.com/&quot;&gt;Vorbis&lt;/a&gt;. More support (no, not &quot;alternative&quot;, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rockbox.org/&quot;&gt;Rockbox&lt;/a&gt;, but straight from the manufacturers) for it in hardware devices will be sweet. Well, I can dream. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/multimedia/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:-)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it seems to be time to shape up that local build of mine of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/aoyoume/aotuv/&quot;&gt;aotuv&lt;/a&gt; tuned version of Vorbis with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/aoyoume/&quot;&gt;Aoyumi&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s patches for libvorbis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exciting times in the multimedia world.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
