<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged music</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/music/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/music/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/music/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2018-04-17T09:27:25Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Paco de Lucia</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-27_paco_de_lucia/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-27_paco_de_lucia/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2014-03-03T04:43:11Z</updated>
	<published>2014-02-28T00:48:04Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I was super sad to know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paco%20de%20Lucia&quot;&gt;Paco de Lucia&lt;/a&gt; passed a few days
ago. It was shocking to know that he was so young (only 66 year old, if I am
not mistaken).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share some of his fine work with his frequent collaborators
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John%20McLaughlin&quot;&gt;John McLaughlin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Al%20Di%20Meola&quot;&gt;Al Di Meola&lt;/a&gt; to people that
may not otherwise know him or his work, I offered on a Facebook post to
upload a bootleg of a show of the Guitar Trio (John McLaughlin, Paco De
Lucia and Al Di Meola) with the entire performance (possibly out of order,
as that is a bootleg, after all) ripped from a broadcast to Dutch TV
station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This performance includes the exceptional Paco de Lucia prominently and the
show has many songs from the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friday%20Night%20in%20San%20Francisco&quot;&gt;Friday Night in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&quot;
record, including the magnificent (IMVHO)
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mediterranean%20Sundance&quot;&gt;Mediterranean Sundance&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The credits of the video are, of course, of the musicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only ripped, deinterlaced (remember, analog TV&amp;mdash;it was interlaced),
denoised, encoded, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/0tzfUYz2t5w&quot;&gt;uploaded the video to youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Assorted random notes</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-10-23-assorted_news/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-10-23-assorted_news/"/>






	<category term="btrfs" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="filesystem" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="python" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-11-06T17:36:48Z</updated>
	<published>2013-10-23T23:08:42Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;This post is just a bunch of random notes, but I think that things are going
well, this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;btrfs&quot;&gt;Btrfs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just started playing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/btrfs&quot;&gt;btrfs&lt;/a&gt; after converting a 2TB disk
with about 1.3TB of data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ext4&quot;&gt;ext4&lt;/a&gt; to btrfs.  This particular
filesystem contains my backup data and I hope that btrfs is able to live up
to high standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will probably write a detailed review with my impressions, but suffice to
say that it is working fine and I hope that I will be happy for a long time
to come. My other filesystems, for the moment, will be ext4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;courseradownloader&quot;&gt;Coursera Downloader&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jplehmann&quot;&gt;John Lehmann&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s generosity, now &lt;code&gt;coursera-dl&lt;/code&gt; has a new home:
a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coursera-dl&quot;&gt;github organization&lt;/a&gt; of its own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;youtube-dl&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl/issues/1612&quot;&gt;Some people may have noticed, others may not&lt;/a&gt;, but when downloading
videos from Youtube, they apparently are getting more aggressive with the
use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic%20Adaptive%20Streaming%20over%20HTTP&quot;&gt;Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP&lt;/a&gt; (also called
DASH) and, as a result, some (perhaps going to be all in the near future?)
of the videos may not be available in the resolution/formats that you used
to like (like me, with format number 35).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, one thing that is interesting with youtube videos provided via
DASH is that they are available in different streams: one for the video and
another for the audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean in practical terms for users of youtube-dl?  Well, if
you wanted to download videos in resolutions like the 480p (format 35) that
I mentioned, then you will probably have to change your way of doing things,
until a more automated solution is in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to download both the audio and the video and, then, &quot;combine&quot;
them (that is, multiplex them) to create one &quot;normal&quot; video file with both
the audio and the video. I usually do this via:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
ffmpeg -i audio.m4a -i video.mp4 -vcodec copy -acodec copy combined.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer having a Matroska container instead of an mp4 container
(which, BTW, results in &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt; muxing overhead), then you can use the
command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
mkvmerge -o combined.mkv audio.m4a video.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, those &lt;code&gt;m4a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt; extensions are a new addition that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl/pull/1622&quot;&gt;I just sent upstream&lt;/a&gt; (in the past, both would have been named with an
extension of &lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As, an aside, I like formats &lt;code&gt;135&lt;/code&gt; for video and &lt;code&gt;140&lt;/code&gt; for audio, for the
reasons that I mentioned in a comments to issue 1612:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Otherwise, to download 480p videos (which I do for lectures and so on with
  other projects of mine, like edx-dl) I have to call youtube-dl twice: once
  for format 135 and another for format 140, since the old &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//smileys/question.png&quot; alt=&quot;(?)&quot; /&gt; format 35
  files are much smaller than the lower resolution 360p files (due to the
  former being encoded in High profile vs. the latter being encoded in
  Constrained Baseline profile).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is unfortunate for some, this is a good thing for others: I once
had a blind user of &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; asking me if he could avoid downloading the
whole video just to extract the audio, so that he save on bandwidth. Well,
now this is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect a new version of &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; to be uploaded soon to Debian unstable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;music&quot;&gt;Music&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is so nice to see the music that I like getting better. It was
particularly pleasant to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/hAnVFJFmFx8&quot;&gt;see&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarja%20Turunen&quot;&gt;Tarja Turunen&lt;/a&gt; being joined
on stage by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Floor%20Jansen&quot;&gt;Floor Jansen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it is my impression that the once female-fronted bands are getting
more and more into collaborations and side-projects and they are, in many
ways, getting more refined. Examples of this includes Floor, Tarja,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anneke%20van%20Giersbergen&quot;&gt;Anneke van Giersbergen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sharon%20den%20Adel&quot;&gt;Sharon den Adel&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kari%20Ruesl%C3%A5tten&quot;&gt;Kari Rueslåtten&lt;/a&gt; and many others that I can&#39;t remember right
now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, some thanks to people that take the time to film, and
upload/share the videos so that other people not at these events can watch
them is highly appreciated and they usually are treated as anonymous, but,
of course, this should be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>A Wish: The Ability of Playing MP3 CDs/DVDs created by iTunes with Free Software</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="indexed-metadata" />

	<category term="library" />

	<category term="mp3" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-25T23:34:09Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Apple&#39;s iTunes has a very cool feature that I would like to have and that I
still have not yet noticed in any of the Linux music players (be them
rhythmbox, amarok, quodlibet, audacious etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feature is the following: Apple&#39;s iTunes player has the possibility of
playing CD-DA, with the information about the tracks (in computer jargon,
metadata) taken from on-line databases like Gracenote&#39;s CDDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software that I use doesn&#39;t have problems with this, at least
regarding audio CDs. They check some free on-line databases (like gnudb.org
or freedb.org, which, by the way, have CDs in their catalog that aren&#39;t
available in the commercial CDDB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the nicest feature that iTunes has is the ability to burn MP3/AAC CDs
taken from playlists composed by the user, neatly organized in a filesystem
structure of the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;artist&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;album&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;song&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also generates an XML file with the contents of the MP3 CD in a way that
makes it playable just like a CD-DA, but with remarkable characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it doesn&#39;t need a connection to the Internet to grab metadata (which is,
of course, stored both in the XML file and in some file&#39;s metadata). This
means that no network connection is necessary to have information about
songs and the XML file acts like a cache to avoid the program reading the
whole CD to show the information in a user-friendly fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MP3 CD is treated like a CD-DA, but with a much longer capacity (say,
12 hours, depending on the bitrate of the songs and their lengths).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the songs don&#39;t have to be imported into playlists and not even queued for
playing. Just selecting the first song to be played is enough for it to
start plaing things (and, of course, it is not always that we want to
import songs to our library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think that this would be a great thing for the GNOME
Desktop (and for others too), since it would increase the interoperability
with other Operating Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only iTunes can create such CDs, but it can also create DVDs containing
MP3/AAC files, which, of course, means that the capacity of such &quot;CDs&quot; is
huge compared to that of usual audio CDs and it is also a convenient way to
carry the discs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience and workflow, it would be really nice to be able to play
such CDs/DVDs with rhythmbox/amarok/quodlibet, as it would represent both a
handy feature and a nice interoperability factor (and convenience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of Free Software players, more formats could be considered, of
course, than just MP3 and Low Complexity AAC. Vorbis, Speex, MP2, AC-3 and
other less-known formats would be possible (well, even Window&#39;s WMA files,
as they are playable by a lot of set-top boxes and car players).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, in addition to playing such CDs/DVDs, those programs could also create
such CDs (say, by passing the responsibility to another program), then
everything would be a dream come true and many other friends of mine would
be one step further from being tied to Mac OS X or Windows and closer to
Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this shows to be an improvement for the Free Software Desktop
environments like GNOME and KDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: The same thing applies to Photo CDs created by iPhoto. It would be
really exciting to have them be recognized by F-Spot or other similar Photo
organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Getting things from the iTunes Music Store without iTunes</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="itunesu" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-24T14:11:54Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free%20Software&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; advocate that I am, I want to use as
much Free Software as I can (and spread the world).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: no, I don&#39;t like to call what I use
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open%20Source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.  I prefer the things the RMS way and if you
don&#39;t like the fact that I like his way, I&#39;m afraid that you may miss some
of the things that I have here, even if you don&#39;t necessarily agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I would like to use, see etc., the material that is available
on the Internet, that people has put available for others to see. In
particular, many Universities around the world are making the shift of being
only in the classroom to being present in their students&#39; lifes all the
time. This is accomplished by putting their educational material available
on-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade or two ago, this was usually accomplished by publishing the
so-called &quot;lecture notes&quot; on the website of the course and maintaining
mailing-lists with the currently enrolled students. The lecture notes were
usually taken using the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scribe&quot;&gt;Scribe&lt;/a&gt; method&quot;, where, for each
class, one student is responsible of taking notes of the material, writing
it in a &quot;finished&quot; form and distributing it back for all the other
students. This was made in a round-robin fashion, as a means to spread the
responsibilities among the students taking the course. Also, the most common
tool used to edit the material, especially in Mathematically-oriented
courses, was to typeset everything in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; (or even plain
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TeX&quot;&gt;TeX&lt;/a&gt;, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecturer frequently distributed a template, which the students used and,
this way, all the notes written by the students had the same, uniform look
and style. The work was usually revised by the lecturer and, many times, it
resulted in a kind of a book, published in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device%5Findependent%5Ffile%5Fformat&quot;&gt;DVI&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PostScript&quot;&gt;PostScript&lt;/a&gt; form (latter, it became common to use
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portable%5Fdocument%5Fformat&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, as it is a format more
popular).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it is still quite frequent (and welcome!) to produce such lecture
notes. But, now, things have changed slightly. (I could discuss &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things
have changed the way they have, but it is beyond the scope of these short
notes here.) People have been recording lectures in audio and, after the
technology became more accessible, in video. Now, a new term is used for
distributing those contents: &lt;em&gt;podcasting&lt;/em&gt;. Essentially, a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/podcast&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is a way of publishing, say, audio so that people can
subscribe to your &quot;podcast&quot; (sometimes also said to be a &quot;channel&quot;). It is
very much like a radio program, where people tune in to listen to a given
program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way most people use to distribute the &quot;episodes&quot; of such
programs/podcasts is actually a combination of technologies, but nothing
exactly new: the description of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is available is given in a format
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; (which is a specialization of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt;,
but this isn&#39;t important for our subject matter) and the content is usually
in form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP3&quot;&gt;MP3&lt;/a&gt; files (or some variation of that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough background. Now, there are on-line stores on the Internet that
make available podcasts. Those podcasts are usually free of charge for the
listener. Some of the most prominent stores nowadays are
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple%5FInc%2E&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &quot;iTunes Store&quot; and Amazon&#39;s store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has created its &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes%20Store&quot;&gt;iTunes Store&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to foster the use of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; program and to boost the sales of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iPod&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; digital players (and, also, to make some extra money).
But people in the education field have seen that using a podcast would be a
good way of sharing knowledge and Apple wouldn&#39;t loose this market: they
invented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ITunes%5FStore%23iTunes%5FU&quot;&gt;iTunes U&lt;/a&gt;, which is
a way for Universities around the world to publish their content on &quot;iTunes
Store&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several big Universities have been putting their content on Apple&#39;s
iTunes-U. And, to see the directory of podcasts on iTunes-U, you have (in
theory) to use Apple&#39;s proprietary program iTunes, only available for
proprietary platforms: for Microsoft&#39;s Windows and for Apple&#39;s own
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac%20OS%20X&quot;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. No Free Software alternative is officially
supported, despite the fact that the blurb on the Universities pages say
that only the access to the content has to be via iTunes and that the
content can be used with any MP3 player or with programs other than
iTunes. Yes, this means that the content is playable under
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; and Linux plays a big role in higher education
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, isn&#39;t there a way to access the blogs avoiding the use of proprietary
software? What about people that only want to use Free Software solutions
or, not even a matter of desiring to use Free Software, having only access
to Free Software?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there is. Apple has changed the way that people use to get the
contents from its iTunes store during time, but, now, it seems to be quite
easy to grab it under a 100% Free environment. I have used this recipe for
two Universities only so far, but it has worked perfectly well. The
Universities in question are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford%20University&quot;&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say that you come across a link with the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;itms://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Browse/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a link is &lt;em&gt;usually not&lt;/em&gt; recognized by browsers without the help of
extra software. In platforms where iTunes is available, the browser sends it
to iTunes and iTunes takes the duty of connecting to the &quot;iTunes Music
Store&quot; (that&#39;s where the &quot;itms&quot; thing at the beginning of the URL comes
from, by the way). Pay close attention to the part
&lt;code&gt;mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646&lt;/code&gt;. That is the important part of
the URL here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is quite easy to convert the link above to something that can be
grabbed with a usual browser or, say, a program like wget or curl. Just
write the link as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/DownloadTracksFile/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part up to and including &lt;code&gt;DownloadTracksFile/&lt;/code&gt; is constant. Only the
part after it is changed and taken from the original link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another way of rewriting the link. Its format is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/FeedEnclosure/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646/enclosure.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the middle part of this URL is the actual part that we alluded
to. The rest is simply a constant thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this way, we can get the contents of podcasts with Free Software in an
automated way. That is, until Apple changes its scheme of doing things. But,
by that time, we will already have the things we want and newer solutions
can be devised soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&#39;s fire those wget&#39;s and start to study things (or prozilla&#39;s,
aria2c&#39;s etc, for some speed boost).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2009-02-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-02-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-02-03/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="ipod" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:27:25Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-03T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;In the past few days, I did quite a good amount of things. One of
the things that took most of my mind was to convert some videos in
a proper format for the iPod. At first, I thought that the format
of the videos would have to have an H.264 encoded video with
resolution 320x240 (without using cabac, which increases the
compression factor of the video) and audio in the AAC format with
bitrates up to 160kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, using Apple&#39;s Quicktime Pro 7, I exported a video from the
Dutch band called After Forever, which had the resolution bigger
than 320x240. This made me revisit Apple&#39;s site where the
specifications of videos meant to be played on iPods. It seems
that, now, with the latest firmware update, the iPod that I have
can play H.264 videos encoded with resolutions up to 640x480 (the
standard VGA resolution). Also, the bitrate doesn&#39;t need to be
restricted to 768kbps: some of the videos produced by Quicktime
(and which the iPods can play) have bitrates of up to 1500kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that I can now encode some of my videos that are in the
nasty WMV format to formats that can be supported in a decent
manner by Free Software system. I have, for instance, the
BBC-produced DVD called &quot;The Codebreakers&quot;, whose audio is in pure
DVD LPCM format (that is, uncompressed) and the space that it takes
on my hard disk is considerable (approx. 1GB).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-09-24</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-09-24/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-09-24/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:10:06Z</updated>
	<published>2008-09-24T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Now I am officially a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/changelogs/pool/main/d/debian-maintainers/current/changelog#versionversion1.45&quot;&gt;Debian Maintainer&lt;/a&gt;.
I&#39;m very happy now. This means that I can upload my own packages to
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, without pestering
&lt;a href=&quot;http://alfie.ist.org/&quot;&gt;Rhonda&lt;/a&gt; about them. But I still want her
opinions on some packages, given the experience that she has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it seems that I&#39;ll be part of another project,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/lossywav&quot;&gt;lossyWAV&lt;/a&gt;, given the current
discussions on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hydrogenaudio.org/forums/index.php?showtopic=65499&amp;amp;st=50&amp;amp;gopid=589938&quot;&gt;hydrogenaudio forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and only today I realized that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&#39;s Intrepid Ibex&lt;/a&gt; alpha 6 was
released. Time to go downloading things to use on my most recent
purchase...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more musically related note, Symphony X
&lt;a href=&quot;http://whiplash.net/materias/news_883/077645-symphonyx.html&quot;&gt;will be coming here&lt;/a&gt;
to São Paulo, which is a nice thing.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-07-20</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-20/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-20/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="lame" />

	<category term="mp3" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T08:58:59Z</updated>
	<published>2008-07-20T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Just discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com/&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt; (or would it be
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roadrunnerrecords.com/&quot;&gt;Roadrunner Records&lt;/a&gt;?) has
released a version of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watershed_(Opeth_album)&quot;&gt;Watershed with extra tracks and with a DVD documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
They have also released another special version that has
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cKx5zrb0Z_0&quot;&gt;Porcelain Heart&lt;/a&gt;
played with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mellotron&quot;&gt;Mellotron&lt;/a&gt;
(which brings orgasms to all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_rock&quot;&gt;progressive rock&lt;/a&gt;
fans, like myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also got my parents to sit in front of my old, trusty
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duron&quot;&gt;Duron&lt;/a&gt;-based &lt;code&gt;dumont&lt;/code&gt; (in
honor of Brazilian pioneer
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santos_Dumont&quot;&gt;Alberto Santos-Dumont&lt;/a&gt;).
It is interesting to note that, while the Level 2
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CPU_cache&quot;&gt;cache&lt;/a&gt; of the Duron system
is small for a low-cost processor (in reference to its rival
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celeron&quot;&gt;Celeron&lt;/a&gt; processor, that had
a bigger Level 2 cache), it has a much bigger
(128&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KiB&quot;&gt;KiB&lt;/a&gt;) Level 1 cache than
what I have in a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentium_D&quot;&gt;Pentium D&lt;/a&gt; machine: only
16KB for each core (at least for data; that&#39;s what my &lt;code&gt;dmesg&lt;/code&gt;
says). Surprising to say the least. And this explains why
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AMD&quot;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; stood on the front of the
race during the Athlon (Thunderbird) days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding other architectures (I have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerPC&quot;&gt;PowerPC&lt;/a&gt; in mind here), I&#39;m
not especially happy with them: my
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerPC_G3&quot;&gt;PowerPC G3&lt;/a&gt; lacks
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_processor&quot;&gt;vector instructions&lt;/a&gt;,
which means that playing multimedia files (read: movies) is
something painful. The problem is that I &lt;strong&gt;quite&lt;/strong&gt; like the iBook&#39;s
form factor and I have not yet seen anything that matches it yet.
Comments are welcome here. Yes, it seems that I am not alone here,
given all the frenziness about the surge of netbook computers, like
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASUS_Eee_PC&quot;&gt;Eee PC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I setup my old sound gear on what is my main (desktop)
computer. It is nice to have a good sound whenever I am working
(well, whenever I am working lightly, as I need sound to be absent
when I&#39;m working hard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, BTW, just found a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vindaci.members.sonic.net/cbreak/projects/autotools/&quot;&gt;superb autotools tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
that starts with the egregious &lt;code&gt;&quot;Hello, World!&quot;&lt;/code&gt; application. This
is a perfect point for reading more advanced documents on this
matter.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-05-17</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-17/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-17/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="lame" />

	<category term="mp3" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T08:52:01Z</updated>
	<published>2008-05-17T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Seeing one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dreamtheater.net/&quot;&gt;Dream Theater&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ytsejamrecords.com/&quot;&gt;Official Bootlegs&lt;/a&gt; (and some of
their regular releases), I can&#39;t fail to notice that they have the
2.0 Stereo part as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LPCM&quot;&gt;LPCM&lt;/a&gt; audio.
Sometimes, these streams are in 24 bits. I would like to convert
them to WAV files so that I can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; to
get the recordings on my portable digital music player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this effect, I spent some moments coding a program that I called
&lt;code&gt;lpcm2wav&lt;/code&gt; that takes a raw input of an LPCM audio from a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DVD&quot;&gt;DVD&lt;/a&gt; video disc and outputs a
WAV file suiltable for compression (in 48kHz, normally).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-05-14</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-14/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-14/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="videos" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T08:47:46Z</updated>
	<published>2008-05-14T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t sleep too much today (2nd day in a row!), since I was
watching one of the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dream_Theater&quot;&gt;Dream Theater&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dream_Theater#Bootleg_culture&quot;&gt;official bootlegs&lt;/a&gt;,
&quot;When Dream and Day Reunite&quot;. (It was &lt;em&gt;cold!&lt;/em&gt; in the morning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this was after I spent a very good amount of time
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;-packaging the upstream source code
of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAME&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; (to which I have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concurrent_Versions_System&quot;&gt;CVS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commit_(data_management)&quot;&gt;commit access&lt;/a&gt;).
It now passes almost every
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lintian&quot;&gt;lintian&lt;/a&gt; check, besides the
fact that the &lt;code&gt;config.sub&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;config.guess&lt;/code&gt; scripts have
time-stamps in the year of 2003. But I am not changing that (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am using my own dog-food, instead of relying on Christian
Marillat&#39;s precompiled versions of lame. And I even provided some
compatibility/transitional packages, so that packages like his
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ffmpeg&quot;&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/a&gt; with the newer and nicest
improvements of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAME&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; (like
fractional
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variable_bitrate&quot;&gt;variable bitrate&lt;/a&gt;
qualities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means, in particular, that I can use better
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP3&quot;&gt;MP3&lt;/a&gt; sounding tracks for
videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the good news is that, according to
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hydrogenaudio.org/&quot;&gt;Hydrogenaudio&lt;/a&gt;, there is finally a
release of the lossy (but almost non-lossy!) compressor for audio
streams, called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.hydrogenaudio.org/index.php?title=LossyWAV&quot;&gt;lossyWAV&lt;/a&gt;.
It surely seems quite promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I finally discovered that the last show to which I went was
a looong time ago:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monsters_of_Rock#1998_3&quot;&gt;Monsters of Rock Festival, September 24 1998&lt;/a&gt;.
I was there to see Dream Theater, Megadeth, and Slayer, but some of
the people that were with me didn&#39;t like Slayer, unfortunately and
they wanted to exit the venue after I negotiated that I was there
to listen to, at least, &quot;Raining Blood&quot;. Oh, Manowar was a joke.
Hilarious. I don&#39;t know if they take themselves seriously or not,
but they were ridiculous. This was the first time where I thought
of writing a program with a stochastic grammar to generate lyrics
for such stereotyped metal.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-05-13</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-13/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-13/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="study" />

	<category term="videos" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T07:22:19Z</updated>
	<published>2008-05-13T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t sleep too much today (actually I spent the whole night awake
trying to understand the simple program presented on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; for the generation of the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Farey_series&quot;&gt;Farey Series&lt;/a&gt; (as Hardy
&amp;amp; Wright call them). Finally, looking at my copy of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concrete_Mathematics&quot;&gt;&quot;Concrete Mathematics&quot;&lt;/a&gt;,
I discovered a &quot;bonus problem&quot; (read: a very hard problem) that has
a deceivingly simple solution that I was looking for the past few
days to justify the program correctness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latter, I went with my dad to &quot;Galeria do Rock&quot; to grab myself a
copy of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pain_of_Salvation&quot;&gt;Pain of Salvation&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&quot;Be&quot; (DVD+CD),
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tristania_(band)&quot;&gt;Tristania&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&quot;Widow&#39;s Weeds&quot; and &quot;Beyond the Veil&quot;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opeth&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deliverance_(Opeth_album)&quot;&gt;&quot;Deliverance&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
