<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged latex</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/latex/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/latex/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 17:34:15 -0200</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>2008-04-12</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-12/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-12/</link>



	<category>latex</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-06T19:34:15Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;During he past few days, I have been writing (in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;, of course!) some (very)
elementary notes on Elementary Number Theory, after starting to
read the classic book &quot;Introduction to Number Theory&quot;, by Hardy &amp;amp;
Wright. The reasons for me taking such notes are threefold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To know how much I retained of the content of my studies and to
serve as a reference for future for facts that I will surely
forget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide a text that has a language different from the book,
which, while quite good, uses old-fashioned terms (e.g., they use
consistently the word &quot;aggregate&quot; for the word &quot;set&quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide both some algorithmic aspects of Elementary Number
Theory that are usually not covered in similar texts (while there
is quite a lot of room for the computational side of things) and to
provide multiple proofs (where I know them) of theorems, which
serve to illuminate the understanding of facts and see connections
with other fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I got a phone call from a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; dear friend of mine. I
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.floresonline.com.br/&quot;&gt;sent her flowers and chocolate&lt;/a&gt;
as a birthday gift.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-11-17</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-17/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>tex</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:09:53Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that one post of mine to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-user&quot;&gt;debian-user&lt;/a&gt; mailing list
stimulated at least one reader to try
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;From: Clive Menzies &amp;lt;clive@xxxxxxxxxxxx.xx.xx&amp;gt;
To: debian-user@lists.debian.org
Date: Wed, 16 Nov 2005 00:25:33 +0000
Subject: Re: Using LaTeX (was: Re: Writing technical text - THANKS !)
Message-ID: &amp;lt;20051116002533.GI4285@clivemenzies.co.uk&amp;gt;
User-Agent: Mutt/1.5.11

On (15/11/05 20:49), Rogério Brito wrote:

[snip]
&amp;gt; I would say that many people learn LaTeX the wrong way: getting a poorly
&amp;gt; designed document and just changing it quickly until it contains more or
&amp;gt; less what the person wants it to have.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; This is wrong in, at least, two aspects:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; 1 - this is not in line with the philosophy of LaTeX of separation of
&amp;gt;     content and presentation (which was here for a loooong time before
&amp;gt;     people in the Web decided to use Cascading Style Sheets with their
&amp;gt;     pages and all the technology that accompanies XML);
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; 2 - as an extension of point 1, I&#39;d say that writers should learn at
&amp;gt;     least a modicum of how to use LaTeX macro, so that they create new
&amp;gt;     environments for their necessities instead of hardcoding things.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;     See, if you have a good macro, you can even put that in a style file
&amp;gt;     of your own and forget about formatting something in that way in the
&amp;gt;     future. In this sense, you can regard your style file as a &quot;library&quot;
&amp;gt;     (in the computer programming sense) of distilled knowledge.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;     And this also implies that a good approach to using LaTeX is to
&amp;gt;     regard the text as &quot;the source code&quot; of your text and even use tools
&amp;gt;     like control revision systems (e.g., RCS, CVS, Subversion etc).
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; &quot;apt-get install&quot; is great here, since installing from source has got
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; to be a nightmare.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; Don&#39;t forget to install tetex-doc and use the &quot;TeX Catalogue on-line&quot;
&amp;gt; for looking for packages to accomplish what you want. Also, a *very*
&amp;gt; good source of information here is the UK TeX FAQ (search in Google).
&amp;gt; Not only it is very good, but it is quite entertaining.

Thanks Rogerio

I flirted with LaTex briefly, a while ago, but didn&#39;t get very far.
Your advice prompts me to revisit it :)

Regards

Clive

--
www.clivemenzies.co.uk ...
...strategies for business
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I&#39;m swamped with middle terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-11-12</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-12/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-12/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>tex</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:45:35Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Stop the presses! If there is any text editor that would be worth
working with, that is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emacswiki.org/&quot;&gt;GNU Emacs&lt;/a&gt;. The
version in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/unstable/&quot;&gt;unstable&lt;/a&gt; (aka
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/emacs-snapshot&quot;&gt;emacs-snapshot&lt;/a&gt;) is
absolutely amazing. Some small (but nice) improvements that I could
grasp with just five minutes of use of emacs-snapshot in comparison
to Emacs 21 are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works out of-the-box with many control revision systems. In
particular, it works &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt; with subversion with the standard C-x
v-v for check-in/check-out of the repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sems to work better with modes like AUCTeX, with something
closer to WYSIWYG, but still faithful to the LaTeX usage cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems to have better &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unicode.org/&quot;&gt;UTF-8&lt;/a&gt;
support, which means that I may, finally, forget about using
anything else (like iso-8859-1). Now, I&#39;m only waiting for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mutt-ng.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;Mutt-ng&lt;/a&gt; to reach testing and I will
be a happier man. I may even start using the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/latex-ucs&quot;&gt;latex-ucs&lt;/a&gt; package to encode
everything that I type in Unicode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The font-locking mode works better and for more modes.
Absolutely sweet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Emacs version is also available with use of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gtk.org/&quot;&gt;GTK 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, which is much more beautiful than
other toolkits used in the past. Also, as the same libraries are
shared among other applications, there is a slight chance of
observing lower memory footprint in some areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe it&#39;s just me, but using dired mode is now much easier. I
always feared using emacs as a file manager, but now it seems to be
a feasible alternative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I see that there is much more to learn. I feel that I have
barely scratched the surface of Emacs 22. Stay tunned kids. It will
surprise you, honest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/docbook-utils&quot;&gt;docbook-utils&lt;/a&gt; is indeed
a possibility instead of using passivetex. But typing everything in
XML is painful. Perhaps there is a mode for Emacs for working with
DocBook files? I&#39;d be pleased to know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-07-27</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-07-27/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-07-27/</link>



	<category>cvs</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>latex</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:36:20Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Made some commits to the CVS version of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/lame&quot;&gt;lame&lt;/a&gt;, since version 3.97 is expected
to have its status upgraded from alpha to beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took care of spell-fixing some bits of documentation, but didn&#39;t
have the time to do a proper job. Some work will be postponed until
the 3.98 release opens for development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it seems that &lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;
has reached a good &quot;mind share&quot; in the sense that some leading
Computer Scientists seem to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-06-19</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-19/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-19/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-06-11T14:07:11Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Feelling extremely bad today. I have an enormous headache. I think
that I will work a little bit on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;, but I don&#39;t know if I
will be able to commit anything today. I can&#39;t really concentrate
and I don&#39;t want to release something that I am not proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, BTW, been swamped by e-mail. Please, stop the madness! I
can understand why Donald Knuth quit this 15 years ago. I
understand that he must be a happier man without Internet annoying
him (especially since he is such a precious celebrity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funnier thing is that people rarely realize how they are doing
things backwards today: they are working more for the computer than
the computer is working for them. They don&#39;t care about things
being automated, which is one thing where computers shine at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I think that such things are the way they are due to the
ignorance of the potential of a computer. Indeed, there are tasks
that a computer can&#39;t embrace (the halting problem, the tiling
problem etc already told us this), but for other mundane things,
computers are useful. Just not the way people seem to be using
them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this, BTW, includes people with high education (like many
Ph.D.&#39;s that I know): they simply don&#39;t make their life easier. One
example of this in action: using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; is a way of producing
high-quality documents. But some people that are actually convinced
that LaTeX is the way to go rarely take the time to use this tool
in all its usefulness. What a pity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I see people doing wrong things, I tell them a better way.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~lymber/&quot;&gt;Very few&lt;/a&gt; seem to understand that,
but others don&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, Linus released a new
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;kernel&lt;/a&gt;, 2.6.12.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-05-29</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-29/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-29/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>latex</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-06-11T13:59:30Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today it was a &quot;software writing&quot; day. I woke up early in the
morning and then I decided to fix
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/src:vrms&quot;&gt;vrms&lt;/a&gt;. I have almost taken the
role of a maintainer, with the exception that I am not one. I have
changed the severity of bugs, merged them etc. All without the
maintainers saying &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt;. Impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, then, updated the package and put a new version of it at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~rbrito/debian/&quot;&gt;my homepage&lt;/a&gt; for perusal by
other developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I have updated the page for the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt; package, now with a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de/screenshots.html&quot;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;. I have
also done some janitorial work on the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.berlios.de/feature/?group_id=3442&quot;&gt;feature requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel-announce/2005/05/msg00020.html&quot;&gt;sarge won&#39;t be released on the 30th of May&lt;/a&gt;,
unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-04-05</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-05/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-05/</link>



	<category>cvs</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>latex</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally &lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;uploaded the homepage&lt;/a&gt; of
the algorithms package to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;BerliOS&lt;/a&gt;. The
fact that they use &lt;a href=&quot;http://subversion.tigris.org/&quot;&gt;subversion&lt;/a&gt; as
an option to CVS was a big plus on deciding where to host the
project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-03-17</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-17/</link>



	<category>abstract-algebra</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>graph-theory</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;So, now I am officially a maintainer of the
&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.dante.de/tex-archive/help/Catalogue/entries/algorithms.html&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;
package, which makes me quite happy. Many thanks go to the previous
maintainer, Peter Williams, for creating such a great piece of
software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it seems that finally &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/&quot;&gt;Adobe&lt;/a&gt; has
understood that the scientific community uses Unix and they have
released
&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.adobe.com/pub/adobe/reader/unix/7x/7.0/enu/&quot;&gt;Acrobat/Adobe Reader 7.0&lt;/a&gt;
for Linux, with widgets with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gtk.org/&quot;&gt;Gtk 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. Trés
cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, I have stopped reading on Graph Theory just for a tiny bit to
learn things on Abstract Algebra. I want to study algebraic
properties of graphs and, for that, I have to get my rusty algebra
in shape. Also, some Linear Algebra wouldn&#39;t hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-11-09</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-09/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-09/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2004 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-24T06:56:59Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;What a strange year this one has been. I was almost killed today in
a car accident. Modulo some pain and the lack of a car, everything
is fine right now. But I wished that everything were slightly
different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the good news front,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&quot;&gt;Firefox 1.0&lt;/a&gt; was
released today, which is one of the most anticipated software
releases of the year. Nice to counter-balance the other bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/latex/index.html&quot;&gt;my mini-tour&lt;/a&gt; for making
presentations in LaTeX with PPower4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-11-03</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>phd</category>

	<category>studies</category>

	<category>toefl</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2004 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-24T06:55:36Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been quite a long time since I last wrote anything here. In
the mean time, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orkut.com/&quot;&gt;orkut&lt;/a&gt; has changed my life
(for the worse) and it seems that I&#39;m now &quot;up for adoption&quot; again.
Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.newcastle.edu.au/~nbi/&quot;&gt;Oz&lt;/a&gt; isn&#39;t that far
away. Or maybe it is. I still don&#39;t know. The last missing piece
(the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toefl.org/&quot;&gt;Test of English as a Foreign Language&lt;/a&gt;) was
completed and the only problem now is the competition for
scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2004/10/msg00325.html&quot;&gt;packaged&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-sp.iti.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de/software/ppower4/&quot;&gt;PPower4&lt;/a&gt;,
which works perfectly now with all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kaffe.org/&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sablevm.org/&quot;&gt;JVMs&lt;/a&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing/&quot;&gt;Debian&#39;s testing&lt;/a&gt;, which
means that one can depend on even less non-free software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the very reason that Free JVMs entered testing were the
reason for me to pick up &lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;. It seems to
be a nice language and the fact that it doesn&#39;t present a problem
to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; makes it a plausible
addition in my book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also patched iTunes 4.7 to work with iPod Download. The
hard-coded blacklist that Apple put in iTunes isn&#39;t nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt;, on the contrary &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;
nice. Also nice is the fact that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://texcatalogue.sarovar.org/entries/algorithms.html&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;
is now Free (and soon will be back into
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tug.org/tetex/&quot;&gt;teTeX&lt;/a&gt;, which is what ships with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;). I am happy, because this means
that my local home directory will get a tiny bit smaller, with less
cruft. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;The Global Operating System&lt;/a&gt;
even more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/faac/&quot;&gt;faac&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s package made by
Christian Marillat now works with the MP4 wrapper, which means that
now I can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://nostatic.org/grip/&quot;&gt;grip&lt;/a&gt; with AAC files for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipod/&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; and use its space in a slighlyt
more efficient manner (well, at least I hope so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, I hate daylight savings time and it seems that now I&#39;m
back in love with Elementary Number Theory. If only Elementary
Number Theory liked me...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
