<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged powerpc</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/powerpc/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 03:38:33 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Running GRUB2 on PowerPC Macs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/running_grub2_on_powerpc_macs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/running_grub2_on_powerpc_macs/</link>



	<category>configuration</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>ibook</category>

	<category>kernel</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>mac</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 22:18:12 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-04-03T01:21:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Here I write a little bit about my experiences running GRUB2 with a PowerPC
Mac (actually, an iBook G4), since the current documentation is lacking in
many places (outdated, incorrect, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of what I say is platform agnostic, though, and may be of interest to
users of GRUB in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Basics using GRUB2 with PowerPC&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is important to understand (at least superficially) how
botting on a Mac works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first programs that run in your Mac is the OpenFirmware. It works
with more or less the same purpose of a BIOS in a regular x86 system. The
basic idea is the same: get the computer running with whatever programs you
want it to run. The implementation, though, differs quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, OpenFirmware (OF) usually presents itself as a command-line
interface that is programmable, differently from the common day BIOSes from
x86 boxes. As it is programmable, it is more flexible, but this flexibility
comes at the price of an increased complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may write some things more in a future article, if there is any
interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, it just suffices to say that to get to the OF prompt in a Mac, you
have to press a combination keys during the time that your Mac gives a chime
when you turn it on. At that moment, you have to press (simulaneously) Cmd +
Option + O + F. (Note: the Cmd key is the key that has an Apple drawn on it,
usually on the side of the space bar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Limitations of Open Firmware&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Differently from usual BIOSes of x86 computers, Open Firmware &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; read the
contents of a partition in your HD (or other devices), as long as it is
formatted in the original HFS format (&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in HFS+ or one of its
descendents).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why some older versions of Linux create an HFS partition
in your HD, even if you don&#39;t intent to run or use anything besides Linux.
The &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; bootloader consists of, among other things, one binary that is
understandable by OpenFirmware. That binary is a file called &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt;, after
the name of the booloader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, you have to indicate to OF what is the file that you want it to
load during the boot process, so that it knows what to do. The way to
indicate this is to &quot;bless&quot; the file (and the folder that contains it).
Some ways to bless a file are to, for example, use the &lt;code&gt;bless&lt;/code&gt; command in
MacOS X or the &lt;code&gt;hattrib -b&lt;/code&gt; command from hfsutils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Files in an HFS filesystem have two attributes that many other filesystems
don&#39;t: a creator ID (the &quot;application&quot; that created the file) and the type
ID (which determines what kind of file it is).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenFirmware, in particular, looks for files with the type &lt;code&gt;tbxi&lt;/code&gt; for the
bootstrap process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; binary is loaded by OF into memory and, then, control is passed
to the yaboot program, which then reads its configuration file
(&lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt;) from the same folder where the binary was in. The file
&lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt; contains instructions for yaboot to do its job. The file
yaboot.conf is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; similar in construction to configurations of an older
bootloader for x86 computers, &lt;code&gt;lilo.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in a way similar to what LILO requires, after you install some new
kernel, change some parameter in the configuration file, etc., you have to
run a program that will set up everything so that the boot process can know
of your new configuration. With LILO, this command was called &lt;code&gt;lilo&lt;/code&gt;, while
with yaboot the command is called &lt;code&gt;ybin&lt;/code&gt; (which, essentially, takes care of
putting &lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt; in the bootstrap/HFS partition and blesses the
&lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; binary).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Going to GRUB2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the characteristics of yaboot (which is left as an exercise to the
reader to determine if it is a drawback or not) is exactly the way that
changes in the configuration have to be copied to the special HFS partition:
the step of running &lt;code&gt;ybin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GRUB2 (and its older sibling, GRUB legacy) do away with that: during
boot-time, it can understand the filesystems that you have in your computer
and interactively load whatever you want from there, also from a
command-line like OF, before any (regular) operating system has even been
started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do you &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; GRUB2? Well, the way that this is performed is
copying a binary to that special HFS partition. Here things start to be
hairy, because GRUB2 has a lot of functionality, but it comes at the price
of it consuming a lot of space (especially if you are using encrypted
partitions or some kind of logical volume managements with some journalling
filesystem that allows files to be compressed etc. on top of it).  The list
goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, that special HFS partition only has 800KB, which, BTW, is the size
of an old 3.5&quot; floppy used with older Macs (note: due to some contraints on
partitions and aligments of such partitions on cylinders, it is not uncommon
for disk partitioning software to create partitions slighly larger than
800KB, but &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; much larger than that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full-featured binary of GRUB2 to be placed on that HFS partition can have
much more than those 800KB. But how do you get that binary, in the first
place? And how do you fit that in the HFS partition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating the GRUB2 binary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the first question, you have to construct it from your
&lt;code&gt;grub-ieee1275&lt;/code&gt; package (I&#39;m assuming here that you are using Debian or
Ubuntu, but similar instructions may apply to other distributions). Then, a
first step would be to create such binary with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; mkdir /tmp/foo
 cd /tmp/foo
 cp -a /usr/lib/grub/powerpc-ieee1275/* .
 grub-mkimage -O powerpc-ieee1275 -o ../grub.img *.mod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last command of these create an executable named &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; that is
callable from OF and which contains every module from &lt;code&gt;grub-ieee1275&lt;/code&gt;.  This
executable that I call here &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; is called, in GRUB2 parlance,
&lt;em&gt;the core image&lt;/em&gt; and it it seems to be named &lt;code&gt;core.img&lt;/code&gt; in many systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my system, with those commands, the binary &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; is about 1208KB,
which is 50% larger than that 800KB partition. And you would like it to be
&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; smaller, becase you want to still have your &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt; bootloader by
default while you are evaluating your bootloaders (or using it as a backup
plan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As GRUB2 follow a modular design, you can mix and match the features that
you want. This already hints you to the way we can fit it in the HFS
partition, and it is always the same story: just trim the fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating the configuration file&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also have to have GRUB2 configuration&#39;s file (or you will have to
play with way more commands than you&#39;d want to). An important distinction
here is that you usually have 2 or more partitions on your Mac:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the special bootstrap/HFS partition where OF is going to look at (I&#39;ll
call it &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda2&lt;/code&gt; here);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the partition where your &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; filesystem resides (denoted by &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda3&lt;/code&gt;
here);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some partition to hold &lt;code&gt;/boot&lt;/code&gt; (I don&#39;t have one of these, but let&#39;s say
that it is &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda7&lt;/code&gt; for our discussion purposes), usually containing
your kernels and initial ramdisks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other partitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, you can With Let&#39;s say that this last one, in Linux
parlance, is &lt;code&gt;/dev/hda3&lt;/code&gt; (as is the case of this author), and optionally a
partition where your Linux kernel resides (people usually use it to store
the &lt;code&gt;/boot&lt;/code&gt; subtree of a Linux filesystem). Let&#39;s say that this last one is
&lt;code&gt;/dev/hda7&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, you would compose something like the following as a configuration file
for GRUB2 (named &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;insmod part_apple
insmod ext2
set root=&#39;(hd,apple7)&#39;

menuentry &quot;Linux&quot; {
    linux /vmlinux root=/dev/hda3
    initrd /initrd
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are one two important points here that deserve more comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that, &lt;strong&gt;differently&lt;/strong&gt; from a regular x86 system, in a Mac system with
only one HD the way that you specify an HD does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a trailing
zero. For instance, in the case above of the variable &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt;, we have
&lt;code&gt;(hd,apple7)&lt;/code&gt;, while in a &quot;common PC&quot; we would have the &lt;code&gt;(hd&lt;/code&gt; part
replaced with &lt;code&gt;(hd0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s something that you should make your distribution aware of, if they
aren&#39;t yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an addendum, I don&#39;t know how it works with systems with more than one
HD, as I only have (PowerPC) Macs that are notebooks. If you can share any
experiences, please do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One point of caution here: what GRUB2 calls &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; is not necessarily the
root of your filesystem (i.e., the partition that holds &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;), but the
&lt;em&gt;device&lt;/em&gt; that everything that is &quot;not fully qualified&quot; is interpreted as
being relative to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &quot;not fully qualified&quot; above means anything that is not prefixed with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/grub/manual/grub.html#Device-syntax&quot;&gt;GRUB&#39;s device notation&lt;/a&gt;.
As an example, &lt;code&gt;(hd,apple2)/boot/vmlinux&lt;/code&gt; if fully qualified for GRUB&#39;s
purpose, while &lt;code&gt;/boot/vmlinux&lt;/code&gt; is not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to just copy the files &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; to the
special HFS partition. You can do that using &lt;code&gt;hmount&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;hcopy&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;humount&lt;/code&gt; or you can use the regular Linux &lt;code&gt;hfs&lt;/code&gt; module to copy to that
partition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, boot your system, get into the OF prompt and execute:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;boot hd:2,grub.img
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, the &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; above is a reference to my HFS partition. Substitute that with
yours, appropriately. You will then see the common (familiar?) GRUB prompt
and, from there, everything else that you know will (hopefully) work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The list of modules that &quot;Works for Me(TM)&quot;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, I use a subset of all modules that come with
&lt;code&gt;grub-ieee1275&lt;/code&gt; to create my &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; binary. Here is the list of modules
that I use and that gives me a reasonably sized bootloader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bitmap.mod        datehook.mod  gzio.mod         lsmmap.mod      reboot.mod          terminal.mod
bitmap_scale.mod  datetime.mod  halt.mod         memdisk.mod     regexp.mod          test.mod
blocklist.mod     echo.mod      help.mod         memrw.mod       relocator.mod       trig.mod
boot.mod          elf.mod       hexdump.mod      minicmd.mod     scsi.mod            true.mod
bufio.mod         ext2.mod      hfs.mod          msdospart.mod   search.mod          video.mod
cat.mod           fat.mod       hfsplus.mod      normal.mod      search_fs_file.mod  video_fb.mod
cmp.mod           font.mod      ieee1275_fb.mod  part_apple.mod  search_fs_uuid.mod  videoinfo.mod
configfile.mod    fshelp.mod    linux.mod        part_msdos.mod  search_label.mod
cpio.mod          gettext.mod   loadenv.mod      parttool.mod    setjmp.mod
crypto.mod        gfxmenu.mod   loopback.mod     probe.mod       sleep.mod
date.mod          gfxterm.mod   ls.mod           read.mod        suspend.mod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for the record, my &lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; file has 624KB, and that can certainly be
shrunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The command line that &quot;Works for Me(TM)&quot; to create the image&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, I lied when I told you that I used the lines above to create my
&lt;code&gt;grub.img&lt;/code&gt; file, because I&#39;m lazy and I don&#39;t want to type the &lt;code&gt;.img&lt;/code&gt;
extension. I also &lt;em&gt;embed&lt;/em&gt; my configuration file in the binary that I create
with GRUB2, so that I don&#39;t have two files to copy to my HFS partition, but
only one. I do that with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grub-mkimage -c grub.cfg -o ../grub -O powerpc-ieee1275 -d . *.mod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK. No more lies here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice aspect of GRUB is that one you install that image, you don&#39;t have
to touch that HFS partition anymore: you simply update your regular
filesystem&#39;s &lt;code&gt;/boot/grub/grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; file (which is usually performed when you
install a new kernel, at least with Debian) and you&#39;re ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good way to do that is to use a minimal configuration file embedded in
your &lt;code&gt;grub&lt;/code&gt; binary in your HFS partition that will hook into the system&#39;s
&lt;code&gt;/boot/grub/grub.cfg&lt;/code&gt; to read newer kernels and leave the HFS partition (and
your system&#39;s NVRAM) alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I am using right now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;search --no-floppy --fs-uuid --set=root 35d26869-f7c9-4852-a9b8-100314560c34
set prefix=($root)/boot/grub
configfile /boot/grub/grub.cfg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will, of course, want to modify the file above as you install newer
kernels (perhaps even that unsupported operating system from that fruity
company, who knows?). Don&#39;t forget to change the UUID&#39;s, and partition
numbers to fit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&#39;s it. I hope that it helps somebody out there, as the information
that I got otherwise was way outdated, incomplete, etc. to keep up with
GRUB2 from these days. Now, let&#39;s go patch the tools that we have so that
not everybody who wants to use GRUB2 have to learn about its workings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, of course, you can now have your kernels in ext4, btrfs, xfs
etc. partitions without the fear that your bootloader won&#39;t load them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>I am going to DebConf 10</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>fonts</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>web-of-trust</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 03:34:40 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2010-07-18T06:34:40Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I just bought my tickets today to NYC and I am glady to say that I am going to Debconf 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;attachment_55&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; caption=&quot;I am going to DebConf10&quot;]&lt;a rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-55&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost/blog/2010/07/18/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/im_going_to_debconf10/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-55 &quot; title=&quot;im_going_to_debconf10&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/im_going_to_debconf10.png&quot; alt=&quot;I am going to DebConf10&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;101&quot;  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets have this information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRU-&amp;gt;JFK:&lt;/strong&gt; Departure: 2010-07-30, 21:25; Arrival: 2010-07-31, 6:10, Flight AA950&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JFK-&amp;gt;GRU:&lt;/strong&gt; Departure: 2010-08-09, 21:40; Arrival: 2010-08-10, 8:35, Flight AA951&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This represents a personal milestone for me, as I have many plans for the conference. In fact, this will be a trip of many &quot;firsts&quot; for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be my first international trip by airplaine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be my first DebConf ever (despite the fact that I could not apply for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://upsilon.cc/~zack/blog/posts/2010/04/the_DebConf_Newbies_initiative/&quot;&gt;DebConf Newbies initiative&lt;/a&gt;, due to my visa interview being delayed until the 7th of this month).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be the first time to see many people with whom I work together for some years now, but have not yet had the opportunity to meet in person.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a nice opportunity to work hard on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/Articles/396079/&quot;&gt;some issues that threaten the PowerPC port&lt;/a&gt; of Debian.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a nice opportunity to do some QA work with some packages that I would like to have sponsored; also to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/551955&quot;&gt;upload&lt;/a&gt; some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/580005&quot;&gt;fonts&lt;/a&gt; that I &lt;a href=&quot;http://git.debian.org/?p=pkg-fonts/ttf-paratype-sans.git&quot;&gt;already packaged&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/581839&quot;&gt;intend&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/589094&quot;&gt;take care&lt;/a&gt;) and that will be maintained under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a very nice opportunity to get myself in a &quot;big&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strongly_connected_component&quot;&gt;strongly connected component &lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_of_trust&quot;&gt;Web-of-Trust&lt;/a&gt; with as many arcs as feasible, by means of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~anibal/ksp-dc10/ksp-dc10.html&quot;&gt;key signing party.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and many, many other things that I would like to do for the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I am thankful for the DebConf team sponsoring both accomodation and food.  It is highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in NYC! Any hints that you may happen to have are warmly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Simple Annotations on Compiling a Linux Kernel for an Embedded Platform</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/simple-annotations-on-compiling-a-linux-kernel-for-an-embedded-platform/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/simple-annotations-on-compiling-a-linux-kernel-for-an-embedded-platform/</link>



	<category>configuration</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>embedded</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>kernel</category>

	<category>kurobox</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:54:52 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-03-12T03:52:56Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some facts distilled from my experience with preparing kernels to
some embedded platforms. In other words, this is some of the stuff that is
usually presumed to be known, but that you won&#39;t find compiled in many
places, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing them here in the hope that they can be useful to other folks
trying to compile their kernel to embedded devices (and I would venture to
say that these &quot;non-standard&quot; platforms would become more popular in the
future).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;some machines don&#39;t have monitors, keyboards etc. They may only have
network connections (e.g., ethernet) and USB ports. In such cases, it
console&quot; called a netconsole. It can be enabled with the options: is quite
handy to see how the machine is booting with a &quot;virtual console&quot; called a
netconsole. It can be enabled with the options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  CONFIG_NETCONSOLE=y
  CONFIG_NETPOLL=y
  CONFIG_NET_POLL_CONTROLLER=y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You have to tell the kernel where to send the messages that would,
otherwise, be presented on a screen. For sending them over the network, just
tell the kernel to use the command line option:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    netconsole=6666@192.168.11.150/,@192.168.11.149/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, you can easily connect from another (more comfortable?) computer
with something like (this connection is made via UDP, not TCP):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ip addr add 192.168.11.149/24 broadcast 192.168.11.255 dev eth0
    nc -u -n -p 6666 192.168.11.150 6666
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;while some popular bootloaders for desktops are LILO and GRUB, many other
platforms use other bootloaders: yaboot, quik, bootx, silo, refit, etc. In
the case of embedded platforms, one that is popular is &quot;das uBoot&quot;, which
needs a special kind of kernel image, a &lt;code&gt;uImage&lt;/code&gt;, instead of a regular
&lt;code&gt;{b}zImage/vmlinu{x,z}&lt;/code&gt; image. (Well, actually, some other arches need
images in other formats, like &lt;code&gt;vmlinux.coff&lt;/code&gt; etc). Fortunately, the
kernel&#39;s makefile knows about some such arches and it generates the
correct image---but it is the task of the packager/distributor to find if
those images are needed or not. For the KuroBox HD/HG, all that is needed
is a simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  cp $LINUXPATH/arch/powerpc/boot/uImage $BUILT_ROOT/boot/uImage-$VERSION
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;some extra care is needed when generating a kernel for such arches: the
tree of the devices which the kernel needs does not seem to be built
automatically (this is the case of the the KuroBox HD/HG). Something like
this is needed after the compilation of the kernel proper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ./scripts/dtc/dtc -I dts -O dtb -V 16 -o $BUILT_ROOT/boot/kuroboxHD.dtb-$VERSION ./arch/powerpc/boot/dts/kuroboxHD.dts
  ./scripts/dtc/dtc -I dts -O dtb -V 16 -o $BUILT_ROOT/boot/kuroboxHG.dtb-$VERSION ./arch/powerpc/boot/dts/kuroboxHG.dts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;to cross compile a kernel, don&#39;t forget to set the appropriate environment
options, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  INSTALL_MOD_PATH=$BUILT_ROOT ARCH=powerpc CROSS_COMPILE=powerpc-linux-gnu- make clean
  INSTALL_MOD_PATH=$BUILT_ROOT ARCH=powerpc CROSS_COMPILE=powerpc-linux-gnu- make oldconfig
  INSTALL_MOD_PATH=$BUILT_ROOT ARCH=powerpc CROSS_COMPILE=powerpc-linux-gnu- make menuconfig
  INSTALL_MOD_PATH=$BUILT_ROOT ARCH=powerpc CROSS_COMPILE=powerpc-linux-gnu- make all modules
  INSTALL_MOD_PATH=$BUILT_ROOT ARCH=powerpc CROSS_COMPILE=powerpc-linux-gnu- make modules_install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It won&#39;t hurt if you use a concurrency setting (like -j3 or more) when
compiling all and modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The uBoot command line (accessed via the network) can be something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ext2load ide ${hdpart} ${ldaddr} ${hdfile}
  ext2load ide ${hdpart} 7f0000 boot/kuroboxHD.dtb
  setenv bootargs root=/dev/sda1 netconsole=6666@192.168.11.150/,@192.168.11.149/
  bootm ${ldaddr} - 7f0000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two lines tell uBoot to load the both the kernel and the device
tree from the disk to the memory, the third line sets the kernel command
line (familiar to users of the &quot;common&quot; arches) and the fourth line
actually boots the kernel once it is loaded in the memory. Here, ${hdpart}
is the partition where the kernel image ${hdfile} should be loaded from
(usually in the form 0:1, to mean partition 1 from the disk 0), ${ldaddr}
is the memory address where the kernel should be loaded to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something that is handy, no matter what size your machine has: the use of
ext4 (and, in particular, delayed allocation) with ext{2,3}
filesystems. To use it, just put this in your kernel configuration file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  CONFIG_EXT4_USE_FOR_EXT23=y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support for daemons like avr-evtd, that need access to a serial port (so
that the user can turn off the device by pressing the power button),
enable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  CONFIG_SERIO=y
  CONFIG_SERIO_SERPORT=y
  CONFIG_SERIAL_8250=y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you will always have to ssh into the system, become root, and
issue something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  shutdown -h now
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which is an inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is very important to set the Real Time Clock options right and this may
not be that obvious for some non-x86 platforms. In particular, for a
KuroBox HD, I&#39;m using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  CONFIG_RTC_CLASS=y
  CONFIG_RTC_HCTOSYS=y
  CONFIG_RTC_HCTOSYS_DEVICE=rtc0
  CONFIG_RTC_INTF_SYSFS=y
  CONFIG_RTC_INTF_PROC=y
  CONFIG_RTC_INTF_DEV=y
  CONFIG_RTC_DRV_RS5C372=y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last option is, perhaps, the tricky one, and varies from system to
system. Knowing which one to enable is a matter of knowing the specs of
your system and, if not known, discovery by trial-and-error. (For x86
systems, usually &lt;code&gt;CONFIG_RTC_DRV_CMOS=y&lt;/code&gt; is sufficient).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-08-22</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-08-22/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-08-22/</link>



	<category>algorithms</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:38:33Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Learned today that the &quot;Four Russians&#39; Method&quot; applied to dynamic
programming is able to achieve a complexity of $O(n&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;/log n)$, which
is a theoretical improvement over the classic dynamic programming
method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would guess that a person from a distant country can make you
happier than most people from your own country?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-07-27</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-27/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-27/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:28:43Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;lame&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Debian packaging a little
bit. Now it correctly reports version 3.92. This closed a bug in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/lame/&quot;&gt;sourceforge&lt;/a&gt;. Some other changes are
on the pipeline (like getting rid of the dreaded &lt;code&gt;rpath&lt;/code&gt;, with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel/2002/debian-devel-200207/msg01792.html&quot;&gt;a recipe&lt;/a&gt;
I got from &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel/&quot;&gt;debian-devel&lt;/a&gt;).
The only thing remaining is to test it on x86 and powerpc before I
commit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked a little bit (well, not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; little) on my Master&#39;s
thesis, fixing the beginnings of chapter 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-07-07</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>macosx</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:23:45Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Woke up quite early with that kernel panic bugging me. I read the
documentation and the fix for it was to reboot MacOS 9 (which
wasn&#39;t as simple as it should, since MacOS X apparently de-blessed
MacOS 9&#39;s System Folder). Anyway, after reusing XPostFacto, the
PowerMac booted with MacOS X! Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, seeing this OS booting on this old computer is quite cool.
Well,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=33385&amp;amp;cid=3607384&quot;&gt;apart from some severe usability problems&lt;/a&gt;
and slowness, MacOS X is an amazing operating system. The problem
is: it &lt;strong&gt;is slow&lt;/strong&gt;. It is slow with a G3 600MHz (100MHz of bus)
with 128MB of RAM and, obviously, much more so with a dual 604e
180MHz with only 64MB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, MacOS X isn&#39;t able to use both processors when it is booted
with XPostFacto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW#2, XFree86&#39;s native driver for Mach64 doesn&#39;t include support
for the XVideo extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also used the client-side of NFS and SMB on MacOS X, which is quite
easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-07-06</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>macosx</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:20:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Took the day to see how things regarding the old PowerMac
9500/180MP were with a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~branden/&quot;&gt;newer XFree86&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xfree86.org/&quot;&gt;XFree86 4.2&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t support the XVideo
extension for the &lt;code&gt;imst&lt;/code&gt;t adapter, which is quite a pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that I am not able to use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xine.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Xine&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mplayerhq.hu/&quot;&gt;Mplayer&lt;/a&gt;
to efficiently play videos on this computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see some things that make this computer slow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a modest amount of RAM for today&#39;s standards (64MB,
which is particularly little for PowerPC);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s RAM chips are in an interleaved
configuration or not;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it had a faster/better supported video card (say, like a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com/&quot;&gt;ATI&lt;/a&gt; Mach64), things would perhaps be better,
but this is just a guess. I don&#39;t know if the Mach64 sports XVideo
support under PowerPC, but perhaps the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gatos.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Gatos&lt;/a&gt; project might help here;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea why this computer, while having a SCSI interface
and drive, is so slow while it is using the disk. I see two things:
it freezes most things the user (that&#39;s me!) whenever it is writing
(reading?) anything to (from?) the disk and the transfer speeds are
quite sloooow. I wonder if this is a problem of the Linux SCSI
infra-structure, if it is a problem of the hardware or if it is a
problem of configuration. It probably isn&#39;t a problem with Linux,
since I also see the slowness with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt;
Classic (8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Anyway, just for fun, I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X 10.1&lt;/a&gt; on this old computer.
The catch is that MacOS X can&#39;t be installed on anything this old.
Well, at least, that&#39;s what Apple says. I had to grab a copy of
MacOS 9 (in German!) just to bootstrap the system. Then, using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://eshop.macsales.com/OSXCenter/XPostFacto/&quot;&gt;XPostFacto&lt;/a&gt;, the
installation was quite smooth (and slow). But with one gotcha at
the first reboot: a kernel panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-04-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-04-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-04-04/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>harware</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:12:33Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;How can life change so quickly from bad to good? Amazing, ain&#39;t it?
Had a great time at my SO&#39;s place. It was nice to see her get
happier, which made &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to talk to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~jose/&quot;&gt;my advisor&lt;/a&gt;
and see that he (mostly) likes my work. Oh, how I needed those
positive, encouraging comments from him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dreamtheater.net/&quot;&gt;Dream Theater&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s bootleg at
Beacon, with the full version of &quot;Six Degrees of Inner Turbulence&quot;,
on my usual FTP server. New music. Good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 3.0&lt;/a&gt; is finally launched. It looks
so amazing that I can&#39;t believe my eyes (err, the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://kde.org/screenshots/kde300shots.html&quot;&gt;screenshots&lt;/a&gt;). A big
plus for me is the built-in support for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webdav.org/&quot;&gt;WebDAV&lt;/a&gt;, which is used by
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mac.com/&quot;&gt;iTools&#39; iDisk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, it seems that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megadeth.com/&quot;&gt;Megadeth&lt;/a&gt;
is no more. Quite sad, as I like(d) them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openoffice.org/&quot;&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt; 641d, the last version
before the 1.0 release, is
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists2.suse.com/archive/suse-ppc/2002-Mar/0079.html&quot;&gt;already available&lt;/a&gt;
for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/ports/powerpc/&quot;&gt;PPC/Linux&lt;/a&gt;. By the way,
OpenOffice is a Free and free alternative for Microsoft&#39;s Office.
It is also available for Microsoft Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackdown.org/&quot;&gt;Blackdown&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Java
is available for Linux, including PPC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-29</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-29/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-29/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>harware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>python</category>

	<category>sadness</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I could sleep better, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also read a tiny little bit about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.docbook.org/&quot;&gt;DocBook&lt;/a&gt;. Some things still aren&#39;t clear
on my mind regarding SGML and DocBook, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to have &lt;a href=&quot;http://avifile.sf.net/&quot;&gt;avifile&lt;/a&gt; enter woody,
which means that now I can use it on PPC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad news of the day is that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iname.com/&quot;&gt;Iname/Mail.com&lt;/a&gt; will not be forwarding
mails, starting early next month. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;Yahoo!&lt;/a&gt;
is joining them, which means that I&#39;ll have to seriously consider
using my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mac.com&quot;&gt;Mac.com&lt;/a&gt; addresses for POP3/IMAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;Which&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perl.com/&quot;&gt;programming&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/&quot;&gt;language&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.objective-c.org/&quot;&gt;should&lt;/a&gt; I learn? To be sincere, I
don&#39;t know. I&#39;m under the impression that the combo
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jython.org/&quot;&gt;Jython&lt;/a&gt;
is what offers me the greatest effort/satisfaction ratio, for many
different values of satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-18</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-18/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>ibook</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>mac</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Typed the remaining bits of the first lecture on the
&lt;em&gt;Theory of Matroids&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read about how one makes a bootable CD for Newworlds with mkisofs:
apparently, the needed things are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;create a folder with &lt;code&gt;yaboot&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;yaboot.conf&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;vmlinux&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;root.bin&lt;/code&gt;.
I&#39;m not sure if &lt;code&gt;boot-floppy-hfs.img&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ofboot.b&lt;/code&gt; are necessary. I
also don&#39;t have an idea of how OpenFirmware knows that it is
supposed to load yaboot during the boot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkisofs -hfs -map &amp;lt;file\&amp;gt; -part -hfs-bless &amp;lt;folder\&amp;gt; -r -o &amp;lt;isoimage.iso\&amp;gt; &amp;lt;root-of-cd\&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sent an e-mail to the bastards at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxjournal.com/&quot;&gt;Linux Journal&lt;/a&gt;, complaining that I&#39;m
not receiving my issues as I should (and my subscription is far
from being expired).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com.br/&quot;&gt;Apple Brasil&lt;/a&gt; is selling
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ibook/&quot;&gt;iBooks&lt;/a&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/br/appleensino/&quot;&gt;a promotion for education users&lt;/a&gt;.
Damn!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
