<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged apple</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/apple/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/apple/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/apple/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2017-11-06T07:18:18Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>User-Agent strings and privacy</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2015-02-22_user-agent_strings_and_privacy/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2015-02-22_user-agent_strings_and_privacy/"/>






	<category term="android" />

	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="browsers" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T06:28:31Z</updated>
	<published>2015-02-22T23:54:27Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I just had my hands on some mobile devices (a Samsung&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samsung_Galaxy_Tab_S_8.4&quot;&gt;Galaxy Tab S 8.4&quot;&lt;/a&gt;,
an Apple&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPad_Mini_3&quot;&gt;iPad mini 3&lt;/a&gt;, and my no-name tablet that runs Android).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got curious to see how the different browsers identify themselves to the
world via their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User%20agent&quot;&gt;User agent&lt;/a&gt; strings and I must say that each
browser&#39;s string reveals a lot about both the browser makers and their
philosophies regarding user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple table that I compiled with the information that I
collected (sorry if it gets too wide):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;col /&gt;
&lt;col /&gt;
&lt;col /&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;th&gt;Device&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;th&gt;Browser&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;th&gt;User-Agent String&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab S&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Firefox 35.0&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Android; Tablet; rv:35.0) Gecko/35.0 Firefox/35.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab S&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Firefox 35.0.1&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Android; Tablet; rv:35.0.1) Gecko/35.0.1 Firefox/35.0.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab S&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Android&#39;s 4.4.2 stock browser&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Linux; Android 4.4.2; en-gb; SAMSUNG SM-T700 Build/KOT49H) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/1.5 Chrome/28.0.1500.94 Safari/537.36&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab S&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Updated Chrome&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Linux; Android 4.4.2; SM-T700 Build/KOT49H) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/40.0.2214.109 Safari/537.36&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Vanilla tablet&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Android&#39;s 4.1.1 stock browser&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Linux; U; Android 4.1.1; en-us; TB1010 Build/JRO03H) AppleWebKit/534.30 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/4.0 Safari/534.30&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Vanilla tablet&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Firefox 35.0.1&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Android; Tablet; rv:35.0.1) Gecko/35.0.1 Firefox/35.0.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;iPad&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Safari&#39;s from iOS 8.1.3&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (iPad; CPU OS 8_1_3 like Mac OS X) AppleWebKit/600.1.4 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/8.0 Mobile/12B466 Safari/600.1.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Notebook&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Debian&#39;s Iceweasel 35.0.1&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64; rv:35.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/35.0 Iceweasel/35.0.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Moto G4 Plus&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;Firefox Focus 2.2&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mozilla/5.0 (Linux; Android 7.0) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Version/4.0 Focus/2.2 Chrome/61.0.3163.98 Mobile Safari/537.36&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, briefly looking at the table above, you can tell that the stock Android
browser reveals quite a bit of information: the model of the device (e.g.,
&lt;code&gt;SAMSUNG SM-T700&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;TB1010&lt;/code&gt;) and even the build number (e.g.,
&lt;code&gt;Build/KOT49H&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Build/JRO03H&lt;/code&gt;)!  This is super handy for malicious
websites and I would say that it leaks a lot of possibly undesired
information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPad is similar, with Safari revealing the version of the iOS that it is
running.  It doesn&#39;t reveal, though, the language that the user is using via
the UA string (it probably does via other HTTP fields).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/browser/mobile/&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; is similar to the stock Android browser here, but, at least, it
doesn&#39;t reveal the language of the user. It does reveal the version of
Android, including the patch-level (that&#39;s a bit too much, IMVHO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say that the winner respecting privacy of the users among the
browsers that I tested is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/android/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;: it conveys just the bare minimum,
not differentiating from a high-end tablet (Samsung&#39;s Galaxy Tab S with 8
cores) and a vanilla tablet (with 2 cores).  Like Chrome, Firefox still
reveals a bit too much in the form of the patch-level. It should be
sufficient to say that it is version 35.0 even if the user has 35.0.1
installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bonus points with Firefox is that it is also available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/&quot;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;, in
two versions: as &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdid=org.mozilla.firefox&quot;&gt;Firefox itself&lt;/a&gt; and as &lt;a href=&quot;https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdid=org.mozilla.fennec_fdroid&quot;&gt;Fennec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit, 2017-10-19:&lt;/em&gt; Added the User-Agent string of Firefox Focus. Quite
different from regular Firefox, as we can see.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>A Wish: The Ability of Playing MP3 CDs/DVDs created by iTunes with Free Software</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="indexed-metadata" />

	<category term="library" />

	<category term="mp3" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-25T23:34:09Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Apple&#39;s iTunes has a very cool feature that I would like to have and that I
still have not yet noticed in any of the Linux music players (be them
rhythmbox, amarok, quodlibet, audacious etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feature is the following: Apple&#39;s iTunes player has the possibility of
playing CD-DA, with the information about the tracks (in computer jargon,
metadata) taken from on-line databases like Gracenote&#39;s CDDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software that I use doesn&#39;t have problems with this, at least
regarding audio CDs. They check some free on-line databases (like gnudb.org
or freedb.org, which, by the way, have CDs in their catalog that aren&#39;t
available in the commercial CDDB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the nicest feature that iTunes has is the ability to burn MP3/AAC CDs
taken from playlists composed by the user, neatly organized in a filesystem
structure of the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;artist&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;album&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;song&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also generates an XML file with the contents of the MP3 CD in a way that
makes it playable just like a CD-DA, but with remarkable characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it doesn&#39;t need a connection to the Internet to grab metadata (which is,
of course, stored both in the XML file and in some file&#39;s metadata). This
means that no network connection is necessary to have information about
songs and the XML file acts like a cache to avoid the program reading the
whole CD to show the information in a user-friendly fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MP3 CD is treated like a CD-DA, but with a much longer capacity (say,
12 hours, depending on the bitrate of the songs and their lengths).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the songs don&#39;t have to be imported into playlists and not even queued for
playing. Just selecting the first song to be played is enough for it to
start plaing things (and, of course, it is not always that we want to
import songs to our library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think that this would be a great thing for the GNOME
Desktop (and for others too), since it would increase the interoperability
with other Operating Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only iTunes can create such CDs, but it can also create DVDs containing
MP3/AAC files, which, of course, means that the capacity of such &quot;CDs&quot; is
huge compared to that of usual audio CDs and it is also a convenient way to
carry the discs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience and workflow, it would be really nice to be able to play
such CDs/DVDs with rhythmbox/amarok/quodlibet, as it would represent both a
handy feature and a nice interoperability factor (and convenience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of Free Software players, more formats could be considered, of
course, than just MP3 and Low Complexity AAC. Vorbis, Speex, MP2, AC-3 and
other less-known formats would be possible (well, even Window&#39;s WMA files,
as they are playable by a lot of set-top boxes and car players).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, in addition to playing such CDs/DVDs, those programs could also create
such CDs (say, by passing the responsibility to another program), then
everything would be a dream come true and many other friends of mine would
be one step further from being tied to Mac OS X or Windows and closer to
Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this shows to be an improvement for the Free Software Desktop
environments like GNOME and KDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: The same thing applies to Photo CDs created by iPhoto. It would be
really exciting to have them be recognized by F-Spot or other similar Photo
organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Getting things from the iTunes Music Store without iTunes</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="itunesu" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-24T14:11:54Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free%20Software&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; advocate that I am, I want to use as
much Free Software as I can (and spread the world).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: no, I don&#39;t like to call what I use
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open%20Source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.  I prefer the things the RMS way and if you
don&#39;t like the fact that I like his way, I&#39;m afraid that you may miss some
of the things that I have here, even if you don&#39;t necessarily agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I would like to use, see etc., the material that is available
on the Internet, that people has put available for others to see. In
particular, many Universities around the world are making the shift of being
only in the classroom to being present in their students&#39; lifes all the
time. This is accomplished by putting their educational material available
on-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade or two ago, this was usually accomplished by publishing the
so-called &quot;lecture notes&quot; on the website of the course and maintaining
mailing-lists with the currently enrolled students. The lecture notes were
usually taken using the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scribe&quot;&gt;Scribe&lt;/a&gt; method&quot;, where, for each
class, one student is responsible of taking notes of the material, writing
it in a &quot;finished&quot; form and distributing it back for all the other
students. This was made in a round-robin fashion, as a means to spread the
responsibilities among the students taking the course. Also, the most common
tool used to edit the material, especially in Mathematically-oriented
courses, was to typeset everything in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; (or even plain
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TeX&quot;&gt;TeX&lt;/a&gt;, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecturer frequently distributed a template, which the students used and,
this way, all the notes written by the students had the same, uniform look
and style. The work was usually revised by the lecturer and, many times, it
resulted in a kind of a book, published in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device%5Findependent%5Ffile%5Fformat&quot;&gt;DVI&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PostScript&quot;&gt;PostScript&lt;/a&gt; form (latter, it became common to use
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portable%5Fdocument%5Fformat&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, as it is a format more
popular).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it is still quite frequent (and welcome!) to produce such lecture
notes. But, now, things have changed slightly. (I could discuss &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things
have changed the way they have, but it is beyond the scope of these short
notes here.) People have been recording lectures in audio and, after the
technology became more accessible, in video. Now, a new term is used for
distributing those contents: &lt;em&gt;podcasting&lt;/em&gt;. Essentially, a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/podcast&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is a way of publishing, say, audio so that people can
subscribe to your &quot;podcast&quot; (sometimes also said to be a &quot;channel&quot;). It is
very much like a radio program, where people tune in to listen to a given
program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way most people use to distribute the &quot;episodes&quot; of such
programs/podcasts is actually a combination of technologies, but nothing
exactly new: the description of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is available is given in a format
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; (which is a specialization of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt;,
but this isn&#39;t important for our subject matter) and the content is usually
in form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP3&quot;&gt;MP3&lt;/a&gt; files (or some variation of that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough background. Now, there are on-line stores on the Internet that
make available podcasts. Those podcasts are usually free of charge for the
listener. Some of the most prominent stores nowadays are
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple%5FInc%2E&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &quot;iTunes Store&quot; and Amazon&#39;s store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has created its &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes%20Store&quot;&gt;iTunes Store&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to foster the use of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; program and to boost the sales of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iPod&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; digital players (and, also, to make some extra money).
But people in the education field have seen that using a podcast would be a
good way of sharing knowledge and Apple wouldn&#39;t loose this market: they
invented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ITunes%5FStore%23iTunes%5FU&quot;&gt;iTunes U&lt;/a&gt;, which is
a way for Universities around the world to publish their content on &quot;iTunes
Store&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several big Universities have been putting their content on Apple&#39;s
iTunes-U. And, to see the directory of podcasts on iTunes-U, you have (in
theory) to use Apple&#39;s proprietary program iTunes, only available for
proprietary platforms: for Microsoft&#39;s Windows and for Apple&#39;s own
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac%20OS%20X&quot;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. No Free Software alternative is officially
supported, despite the fact that the blurb on the Universities pages say
that only the access to the content has to be via iTunes and that the
content can be used with any MP3 player or with programs other than
iTunes. Yes, this means that the content is playable under
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; and Linux plays a big role in higher education
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, isn&#39;t there a way to access the blogs avoiding the use of proprietary
software? What about people that only want to use Free Software solutions
or, not even a matter of desiring to use Free Software, having only access
to Free Software?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there is. Apple has changed the way that people use to get the
contents from its iTunes store during time, but, now, it seems to be quite
easy to grab it under a 100% Free environment. I have used this recipe for
two Universities only so far, but it has worked perfectly well. The
Universities in question are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford%20University&quot;&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say that you come across a link with the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;itms://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Browse/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a link is &lt;em&gt;usually not&lt;/em&gt; recognized by browsers without the help of
extra software. In platforms where iTunes is available, the browser sends it
to iTunes and iTunes takes the duty of connecting to the &quot;iTunes Music
Store&quot; (that&#39;s where the &quot;itms&quot; thing at the beginning of the URL comes
from, by the way). Pay close attention to the part
&lt;code&gt;mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646&lt;/code&gt;. That is the important part of
the URL here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is quite easy to convert the link above to something that can be
grabbed with a usual browser or, say, a program like wget or curl. Just
write the link as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/DownloadTracksFile/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part up to and including &lt;code&gt;DownloadTracksFile/&lt;/code&gt; is constant. Only the
part after it is changed and taken from the original link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another way of rewriting the link. Its format is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/FeedEnclosure/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646/enclosure.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the middle part of this URL is the actual part that we alluded
to. The rest is simply a constant thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this way, we can get the contents of podcasts with Free Software in an
automated way. That is, until Apple changes its scheme of doing things. But,
by that time, we will already have the things we want and newer solutions
can be devised soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&#39;s fire those wget&#39;s and start to study things (or prozilla&#39;s,
aria2c&#39;s etc, for some speed boost).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-05-08</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-08/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-08/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T07:18:18Z</updated>
	<published>2008-05-08T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Had some programming session on working with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/hfsprogs&quot;&gt;hfsprogs&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s packaging for
Debian. I finally saw how to build a multi-arch building and
introduced some cruft to compile it under amd64 (aka,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X86-64&quot;&gt;x86-64&lt;/a&gt;), since
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s code is
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/436159&quot;&gt;not 64-bit clean&lt;/a&gt;. Ugh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s because they have the guts to show us their source code.
Imagine what a disaster it is to see proprietary software that is
completely closed!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-04-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-30/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="powerpc" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T07:16:54Z</updated>
	<published>2008-04-30T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Upgraded my parent&#39;s computer from
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Feisty (7.10) to Hardy (8.04).
Now, some of the things that I&#39;m used to when using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s sid are available on their
computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I can&#39;t avoid to use this opportunity to complain once more
about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flash.net.br/&quot;&gt;ISP&lt;/a&gt;. If I weren&#39;t doing the
upgrade &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; early in the morning, I wouldn&#39;t have success,
as I am (right now), without signal from them. These outages are
getting on my nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some math related news, I finally saw a proof of the intuitive
fact the determinant of a 2x2 matrix is the signed area of the
parallelogram with vectors given by the column vectors of the
matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my D-Link G122 (I think that that&#39;s the model) doesn&#39;t work
with the &lt;code&gt;rt2500usb&lt;/code&gt; driver that ships with the distribution: I can
see that &lt;code&gt;iwconfig&lt;/code&gt; lists &lt;code&gt;wlan0&lt;/code&gt; as having wireless extensions, I
can set the device, it can see the access point, I can enter the
WEP key, but it doesn&#39;t seem to get a DHCP lease from the router.
&lt;code&gt;:-(&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-04-29</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-29/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-29/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T07:15:15Z</updated>
	<published>2008-04-29T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Spent some time polishing my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;
package for &lt;a href=&quot;http://cr.yp.to/&quot;&gt;qmail&lt;/a&gt;, with the patches managed by
quilt. Now, everything is more maintainable, despite the fact that
separating one monolithic patch into smaller patches was a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got some time to experience
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.org/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s latest distribution on my iBook.
Unfortunately, there seems to be serious problems with the live CD
as X isn&#39;t working correctly. &lt;code&gt;:-(&lt;/code&gt;. I still don&#39;t know what could
be the cause, since the framebuffer was set at 1024x768, but X
insisted on the resolution being 800x600.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-10-19</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-10-19/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-10-19/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="powerpc" />

	<category term="teaching" />

	<category term="work" />


	<updated>2015-01-18T00:43:16Z</updated>
	<published>2005-10-19T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Ok, so, I am almost giving up the hectic mess in which work has
turned to... I need to take a serious time resting a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m so tired and people are so demanding of me and of my creativity
that its hard to even take some time with pleasant things. For
instance, in the little time that I have to sleep, I don&#39;t have the
motivation to study the neat things that I always wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that this means that I&#39;m overworked, without any shadow of
doubt. Being sleepy while at work has never been a common thing for
me, even when I was in the tiring days of my M.Sc. studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, in those days, I thought that I was progressing (and it&#39;s
hard not to feel you&#39;re progressing when you&#39;re being pushed to
your limits), but now, with little time for intellectual
challenges, I see little point in keeping up with the work I&#39;m
doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not particularly exciting to be teaching how to write a for
for the 20th time in less than two years. I guess that if the
concept of iteration doesn&#39;t enter one&#39;s brain as soon as it is
told, then all is hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that I need a significant other to make everything bright
(even those less-than-perfect moments). Someone that truly
understands what I mean, what my ideals are, what my values are and
how I see the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, yes, I am willing to even change some things of me. But please
don&#39;t disillusion me. In some sense, I&#39;m fragile. Even more than
most people think that I am. Despite the tough cover that I may
have, lies a friendly person. Truly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; has released a bunch
of new stuff, with the highlight (for me, at least), being the new
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&quot;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt;s.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-05-28</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-28/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-28/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T13:58:42Z</updated>
	<published>2005-05-28T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I have now, with the help of an oooold
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atitech.ca/&quot;&gt;ATI Mach 64 GX&lt;/a&gt; card (with only 2MB of
VRAM) gotten &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X 10.3.9&lt;/a&gt; to work
on the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everymac.com/systems/apple/powermac/stats/powermac_9500_180mp.html&quot;&gt;PowerMac&lt;/a&gt;.
I then substituted the card with an IMS Twin Turbo card that has
4MB of VRAM. It seems to work well, considering that this machine
has almost 10 years (a PeeCee normally doesn&#39;t last this much). If
I were to upgrade this machine, I would start by the following two
items (perhaps not in this order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Substitude its HD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more RAM to it. MacOS X likes a lot of RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I may get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonnettech.com/&quot;&gt;Sonnet Tech&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonnettech.com/product/tempo_trio.html&quot;&gt;Tempo Trio&lt;/a&gt;
card, which features an IDE controller, a Firewire controller and a
USB 2.0 controller in just one card. Seems like a good deal,
especially for using (faster, modern) IDE HDs, all this being able
to just use a single slot of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-04-12</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-12/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-12/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</updated>
	<published>2005-04-12T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;After installing the NewerTech G3 upgrade card into the PowerMac 9500/180MP,
I had some problems, when I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the sarge floppies would work and I eventually decided to get rid of
any traces of MacOS and installed using the woody floppies. The problem is
that the kernel 2.2.20 that comes with woody ins&#39;t able to see both PCI
buses, especially the one where the video card is sitting on. I had to grab
a kernel from testing&#39;s repository, but I don&#39;t like distribution kernels,
for they are way too bloated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self: when replacing the &lt;code&gt;zImage&lt;/code&gt; on the HFS boot floppy, one
has to use the vmlinux image compressed with &lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt;, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gzip -9 vmlinux
hmount /dev/fd0
hcopy vmlinux.gz :zImage
humount /dev/fd0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other image that I tried worked. But it was nice to (re)-discover how one
makes a boot floppy for an OldWorld Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; announced the next upgrade of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&lt;/a&gt;, code named &quot;Tiger&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-03-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-30/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</updated>
	<published>2005-03-30T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! Finally I received a nice little package with two G3
upgrade cards (and one IMSTT card). This is great news for me to
upgrade the PowerMac 9500/180MP that I have here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiously, only one of its memory sticks (it has 2 32MB sticks) was
being recognized by the system. I had to open it and it took me
quite some time to figure out why (after some tweaking) the system
wouldn&#39;t boot anymore. I have no idea why, but just zapping the
NVRAM worked (i.e., Cmd+Option+P+R).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step now is to see if I can get more memory for this
system, so that I can actually use it after this welcome upgrade.
Then, I will surely be playing with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/sarge&quot;&gt;sarge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
