<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged apple</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/apple/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/apple/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/apple/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2014-02-23T06:15:21Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>A Wish: The Ability of Playing MP3 CDs/DVDs created by iTunes with Free Software</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="indexed-metadata" />

	<category term="library" />

	<category term="mp3" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-25T23:34:09Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Apple&#39;s iTunes has a very cool feature that I would like to have and that I
still have not yet noticed in any of the Linux music players (be them
rhythmbox, amarok, quodlibet, audacious etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feature is the following: Apple&#39;s iTunes player has the possibility of
playing CD-DA, with the information about the tracks (in computer jargon,
metadata) taken from on-line databases like Gracenote&#39;s CDDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software that I use doesn&#39;t have problems with this, at least
regarding audio CDs. They check some free on-line databases (like gnudb.org
or freedb.org, which, by the way, have CDs in their catalog that aren&#39;t
available in the commercial CDDB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the nicest feature that iTunes has is the ability to burn MP3/AAC CDs
taken from playlists composed by the user, neatly organized in a filesystem
structure of the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;artist&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;album&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;song&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also generates an XML file with the contents of the MP3 CD in a way that
makes it playable just like a CD-DA, but with remarkable characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it doesn&#39;t need a connection to the Internet to grab metadata (which is,
of course, stored both in the XML file and in some file&#39;s metadata). This
means that no network connection is necessary to have information about
songs and the XML file acts like a cache to avoid the program reading the
whole CD to show the information in a user-friendly fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MP3 CD is treated like a CD-DA, but with a much longer capacity (say,
12 hours, depending on the bitrate of the songs and their lengths).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the songs don&#39;t have to be imported into playlists and not even queued for
playing. Just selecting the first song to be played is enough for it to
start plaing things (and, of course, it is not always that we want to
import songs to our library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think that this would be a great thing for the GNOME
Desktop (and for others too), since it would increase the interoperability
with other Operating Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only iTunes can create such CDs, but it can also create DVDs containing
MP3/AAC files, which, of course, means that the capacity of such &quot;CDs&quot; is
huge compared to that of usual audio CDs and it is also a convenient way to
carry the discs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience and workflow, it would be really nice to be able to play
such CDs/DVDs with rhythmbox/amarok/quodlibet, as it would represent both a
handy feature and a nice interoperability factor (and convenience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of Free Software players, more formats could be considered, of
course, than just MP3 and Low Complexity AAC. Vorbis, Speex, MP2, AC-3 and
other less-known formats would be possible (well, even Window&#39;s WMA files,
as they are playable by a lot of set-top boxes and car players).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, in addition to playing such CDs/DVDs, those programs could also create
such CDs (say, by passing the responsibility to another program), then
everything would be a dream come true and many other friends of mine would
be one step further from being tied to Mac OS X or Windows and closer to
Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this shows to be an improvement for the Free Software Desktop
environments like GNOME and KDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: The same thing applies to Photo CDs created by iPhoto. It would be
really exciting to have them be recognized by F-Spot or other similar Photo
organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Getting things from the iTunes Music Store without iTunes</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="itunesu" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-24T14:11:54Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free%20Software&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; advocate that I am, I want to use as
much Free Software as I can (and spread the world).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: no, I don&#39;t like to call what I use
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open%20Source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.  I prefer the things the RMS way and if you
don&#39;t like the fact that I like his way, I&#39;m afraid that you may miss some
of the things that I have here, even if you don&#39;t necessarily agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I would like to use, see etc., the material that is available
on the Internet, that people has put available for others to see. In
particular, many Universities around the world are making the shift of being
only in the classroom to being present in their students&#39; lifes all the
time. This is accomplished by putting their educational material available
on-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade or two ago, this was usually accomplished by publishing the
so-called &quot;lecture notes&quot; on the website of the course and maintaining
mailing-lists with the currently enrolled students. The lecture notes were
usually taken using the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scribe&quot;&gt;Scribe&lt;/a&gt; method&quot;, where, for each
class, one student is responsible of taking notes of the material, writing
it in a &quot;finished&quot; form and distributing it back for all the other
students. This was made in a round-robin fashion, as a means to spread the
responsibilities among the students taking the course. Also, the most common
tool used to edit the material, especially in Mathematically-oriented
courses, was to typeset everything in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; (or even plain
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TeX&quot;&gt;TeX&lt;/a&gt;, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecturer frequently distributed a template, which the students used and,
this way, all the notes written by the students had the same, uniform look
and style. The work was usually revised by the lecturer and, many times, it
resulted in a kind of a book, published in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device%5Findependent%5Ffile%5Fformat&quot;&gt;DVI&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PostScript&quot;&gt;PostScript&lt;/a&gt; form (latter, it became common to use
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portable%5Fdocument%5Fformat&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, as it is a format more
popular).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it is still quite frequent (and welcome!) to produce such lecture
notes. But, now, things have changed slightly. (I could discuss &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things
have changed the way they have, but it is beyond the scope of these short
notes here.) People have been recording lectures in audio and, after the
technology became more accessible, in video. Now, a new term is used for
distributing those contents: &lt;em&gt;podcasting&lt;/em&gt;. Essentially, a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/podcast&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is a way of publishing, say, audio so that people can
subscribe to your &quot;podcast&quot; (sometimes also said to be a &quot;channel&quot;). It is
very much like a radio program, where people tune in to listen to a given
program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way most people use to distribute the &quot;episodes&quot; of such
programs/podcasts is actually a combination of technologies, but nothing
exactly new: the description of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is available is given in a format
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; (which is a specialization of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt;,
but this isn&#39;t important for our subject matter) and the content is usually
in form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP3&quot;&gt;MP3&lt;/a&gt; files (or some variation of that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough background. Now, there are on-line stores on the Internet that
make available podcasts. Those podcasts are usually free of charge for the
listener. Some of the most prominent stores nowadays are
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple%5FInc%2E&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &quot;iTunes Store&quot; and Amazon&#39;s store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has created its &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes%20Store&quot;&gt;iTunes Store&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to foster the use of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; program and to boost the sales of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iPod&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; digital players (and, also, to make some extra money).
But people in the education field have seen that using a podcast would be a
good way of sharing knowledge and Apple wouldn&#39;t loose this market: they
invented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ITunes%5FStore%23iTunes%5FU&quot;&gt;iTunes U&lt;/a&gt;, which is
a way for Universities around the world to publish their content on &quot;iTunes
Store&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several big Universities have been putting their content on Apple&#39;s
iTunes-U. And, to see the directory of podcasts on iTunes-U, you have (in
theory) to use Apple&#39;s proprietary program iTunes, only available for
proprietary platforms: for Microsoft&#39;s Windows and for Apple&#39;s own
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac%20OS%20X&quot;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. No Free Software alternative is officially
supported, despite the fact that the blurb on the Universities pages say
that only the access to the content has to be via iTunes and that the
content can be used with any MP3 player or with programs other than
iTunes. Yes, this means that the content is playable under
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; and Linux plays a big role in higher education
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, isn&#39;t there a way to access the blogs avoiding the use of proprietary
software? What about people that only want to use Free Software solutions
or, not even a matter of desiring to use Free Software, having only access
to Free Software?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there is. Apple has changed the way that people use to get the
contents from its iTunes store during time, but, now, it seems to be quite
easy to grab it under a 100% Free environment. I have used this recipe for
two Universities only so far, but it has worked perfectly well. The
Universities in question are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford%20University&quot;&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say that you come across a link with the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;itms://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Browse/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a link is &lt;em&gt;usually not&lt;/em&gt; recognized by browsers without the help of
extra software. In platforms where iTunes is available, the browser sends it
to iTunes and iTunes takes the duty of connecting to the &quot;iTunes Music
Store&quot; (that&#39;s where the &quot;itms&quot; thing at the beginning of the URL comes
from, by the way). Pay close attention to the part
&lt;code&gt;mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646&lt;/code&gt;. That is the important part of
the URL here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is quite easy to convert the link above to something that can be
grabbed with a usual browser or, say, a program like wget or curl. Just
write the link as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/DownloadTracksFile/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part up to and including &lt;code&gt;DownloadTracksFile/&lt;/code&gt; is constant. Only the
part after it is changed and taken from the original link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another way of rewriting the link. Its format is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/FeedEnclosure/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646/enclosure.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the middle part of this URL is the actual part that we alluded
to. The rest is simply a constant thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this way, we can get the contents of podcasts with Free Software in an
automated way. That is, until Apple changes its scheme of doing things. But,
by that time, we will already have the things we want and newer solutions
can be devised soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&#39;s fire those wget&#39;s and start to study things (or prozilla&#39;s,
aria2c&#39;s etc, for some speed boost).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-04-12</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-12/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-12/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-02-23T06:15:21Z</updated>
	<published>2005-04-12T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;After installing the NewerTech G3 upgrade card into the PowerMac 9500/180MP,
I had some problems, when I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the sarge floppies would work and I eventually decided to get rid of
any traces of MacOS and installed using the woody floppies. The problem is
that the kernel 2.2.20 that comes with woody ins&#39;t able to see both PCI
buses, especially the one where the video card is sitting on. I had to grab
a kernel from testing&#39;s repository, but I don&#39;t like distribution kernels,
for they are way too bloated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self: when replacing the &lt;code&gt;zImage&lt;/code&gt; on the HFS boot floppy, one
has to use the vmlinux image compressed with &lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt;, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gzip -9 vmlinux
hmount /dev/fd0
hcopy vmlinux.gz :zImage
humount /dev/fd0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other image that I tried worked. But it was nice to (re)-discover how one
makes a boot floppy for an OldWorld Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; announced the next upgrade of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&lt;/a&gt;, code named &quot;Tiger&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-03-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-30/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-02-23T06:15:21Z</updated>
	<published>2005-03-30T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! Finally I received a nice little package with two G3
upgrade cards (and one IMSTT card). This is great news for me to
upgrade the PowerMac 9500/180MP that I have here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiously, only one of its memory sticks (it has 2 32MB sticks) was
being recognized by the system. I had to open it and it took me
quite some time to figure out why (after some tweaking) the system
wouldn&#39;t boot anymore. I have no idea why, but just zapping the
NVRAM worked (i.e., Cmd+Option+P+R).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step now is to see if I can get more memory for this
system, so that I can actually use it after this welcome upgrade.
Then, I will surely be playing with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/sarge&quot;&gt;sarge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-03-26</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-26/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-26/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="movies" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2014-02-23T06:15:21Z</updated>
	<published>2005-03-26T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Had the pleasant experience of watching &quot;Constantine&quot;. The
comparisons with &quot;The Exorcist&quot; are obvious here, even though this
one is a nice movie. BTW, it seems that after the Matrix series,
Keanu Reeves is doomed to Sci-Fi movies with lots of special
effects. It&#39;s not a bad thing, nor a good thing. Just an
observation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trivia:&lt;/em&gt; It was a pleasant surprise to see (humm, hear actually)
that David Brubeck&#39;s Quarted &quot;Take Five&quot; was on the soundtrack. Oh,
and they insist on putting a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&quot;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; on the movie. That is
simply tempting. This is not the first movie that I see where
something made by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; appears on the big
screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, going to the supermarket after the movie was also quite
nice, if you know what I mean. And the pleasant company was also
highly appreciated. It couldn&#39;t be much better that this (really).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2004-11-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="latex" />

	<category term="phd" />

	<category term="studies" />

	<category term="toefl" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2014-02-07T23:02:59Z</updated>
	<published>2004-11-03T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been quite a long time since I last wrote anything here. In
the mean time, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orkut.com/&quot;&gt;orkut&lt;/a&gt; has changed my life
(for the worse) and it seems that I&#39;m now &quot;up for adoption&quot; again.
Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.newcastle.edu.au/~nbi/&quot;&gt;Oz&lt;/a&gt; isn&#39;t that far
away. Or maybe it is. I still don&#39;t know. The last missing piece
(the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toefl.org/&quot;&gt;Test of English as a Foreign Language&lt;/a&gt;) was
completed and the only problem now is the competition for
scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2004/10/msg00325.html&quot;&gt;packaged&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-sp.iti.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de/software/ppower4/&quot;&gt;PPower4&lt;/a&gt;,
which works perfectly now with all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kaffe.org/&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sablevm.org/&quot;&gt;JVMs&lt;/a&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing/&quot;&gt;Debian&#39;s testing&lt;/a&gt;, which
means that one can depend on even less non-free software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the very reason that Free JVMs entered testing were the
reason for me to pick up &lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;. It seems to
be a nice language and the fact that it doesn&#39;t present a problem
to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; makes it a plausible
addition in my book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also patched iTunes 4.7 to work with iPod Download. The
hard-coded blacklist that Apple put in iTunes isn&#39;t nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt;, on the contrary &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;
nice. Also nice is the fact that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://texcatalogue.sarovar.org/entries/algorithms.html&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;
is now Free (and soon will be back into
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tug.org/tetex/&quot;&gt;teTeX&lt;/a&gt;, which is what ships with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;). I am happy, because this means
that my local home directory will get a tiny bit smaller, with less
cruft. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;The Global Operating System&lt;/a&gt;
even more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/faac/&quot;&gt;faac&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s package made by
Christian Marillat now works with the MP4 wrapper, which means that
now I can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://nostatic.org/grip/&quot;&gt;grip&lt;/a&gt; with AAC files for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipod/&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; and use its space in a slighlyt
more efficient manner (well, at least I hope so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, I hate daylight savings time and it seems that now I&#39;m
back in love with Elementary Number Theory. If only Elementary
Number Theory liked me...&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-07-17</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-17/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-17/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="portuguese" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:25:02Z</updated>
	<published>2002-07-17T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Maldita &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;! Eu os odeio! Odeio $teve
Job$. Vão começar a cobrar um rio de dinheiro pelo iTools, quero
dizer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mac.com/&quot;&gt;.Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-07-07</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hacks" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:23:45Z</updated>
	<published>2002-07-07T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Woke up quite early with that kernel panic bugging me. I read the
documentation and the fix for it was to reboot MacOS 9 (which
wasn&#39;t as simple as it should, since MacOS X apparently de-blessed
MacOS 9&#39;s System Folder). Anyway, after reusing XPostFacto, the
PowerMac booted with MacOS X! Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, seeing this OS booting on this old computer is quite cool.
Well,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=33385&amp;amp;cid=3607384&quot;&gt;apart from some severe usability problems&lt;/a&gt;
and slowness, MacOS X is an amazing operating system. The problem
is: it &lt;strong&gt;is slow&lt;/strong&gt;. It is slow with a G3 600MHz (100MHz of bus)
with 128MB of RAM and, obviously, much more so with a dual 604e
180MHz with only 64MB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, MacOS X isn&#39;t able to use both processors when it is booted
with XPostFacto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW#2, XFree86&#39;s native driver for Mach64 doesn&#39;t include support
for the XVideo extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also used the client-side of NFS and SMB on MacOS X, which is quite
easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-07-06</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hacks" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:20:31Z</updated>
	<published>2002-07-06T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Took the day to see how things regarding the old PowerMac
9500/180MP were with a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~branden/&quot;&gt;newer XFree86&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xfree86.org/&quot;&gt;XFree86 4.2&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t support the XVideo
extension for the &lt;code&gt;imst&lt;/code&gt;t adapter, which is quite a pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that I am not able to use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xine.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Xine&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mplayerhq.hu/&quot;&gt;Mplayer&lt;/a&gt;
to efficiently play videos on this computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see some things that make this computer slow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a modest amount of RAM for today&#39;s standards (64MB,
which is particularly little for PowerPC);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s RAM chips are in an interleaved
configuration or not;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it had a faster/better supported video card (say, like a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com/&quot;&gt;ATI&lt;/a&gt; Mach64), things would perhaps be better,
but this is just a guess. I don&#39;t know if the Mach64 sports XVideo
support under PowerPC, but perhaps the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gatos.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Gatos&lt;/a&gt; project might help here;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea why this computer, while having a SCSI interface
and drive, is so slow while it is using the disk. I see two things:
it freezes most things the user (that&#39;s me!) whenever it is writing
(reading?) anything to (from?) the disk and the transfer speeds are
quite sloooow. I wonder if this is a problem of the Linux SCSI
infra-structure, if it is a problem of the hardware or if it is a
problem of configuration. It probably isn&#39;t a problem with Linux,
since I also see the slowness with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt;
Classic (8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, just for fun, I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X 10.1&lt;/a&gt; on this old computer.
The catch is that MacOS X can&#39;t be installed on anything this old.
Well, at least, that&#39;s what Apple says. I had to grab a copy of
MacOS 9 (in German!) just to bootstrap the system. Then, using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://eshop.macsales.com/OSXCenter/XPostFacto/&quot;&gt;XPostFacto&lt;/a&gt;, the
installation was quite smooth (and slow). But with one gotcha at
the first reboot: a kernel panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-11</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-11/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-11/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="macos" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-11T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Some weeks ago, my uncle that sells and fixes computers,
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:startmicro@uol.com.br&quot;&gt;Isaac&lt;/a&gt;, got a pair of old
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.info.apple.com/applespec/applespec.taf?RID=204&quot;&gt;Power Macintosh 9500/180MP&lt;/a&gt;
from a customer. His customer said that if he fixed one of them,
the other would be his as payment. So he kind of fixed one of them
and lent me the other, which means that I&#39;m now going to play with
both
&lt;a href=&quot;http://download.info.apple.com/Apple_Support_Area/Apple_Software_Updates/English-North_American/Macintosh/System/Mac_OS_8.1_Update/&quot;&gt;MacOS 8.0&lt;/a&gt;
and a Unix-like OS with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came with two PowerPC 604e processors of 180MHz (or so the specs
say), 64MB of RAM (where am I going to get more of it?), an
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com&quot;&gt;ATI&lt;/a&gt; graphics card with 2MB of memory, and a
4-speed CD-ROM. It features two SCSI interfaces, an Ethernet
adapter, a MacOS 8.0 CD, a keyboard and the (in)famous 1-button
mouse from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the first dual-head machine over which I am able to get my
greasy pawls. As welcome additionals, it is also the first time I
get to play with a non-x86 machine in a System Administrator
position (of course, I also use Solaris 2.x with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/&quot;&gt;my University&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; workstations, but that
doesn&#39;t count, since I&#39;m just a luser there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PowerPC machines are actually quite different from their ix86
counterparts. First of all, they don&#39;t have a BIOS setup, but you
can interface with the hardware before any Operating System gets
loaded with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://playground.sun.com/1275/home.html&quot;&gt;Open Firmware&lt;/a&gt;, which is
written in FORTH. You should be able to get into OF pressing
Command-Option-O-F while the machine chimes, or right after it
chimes. But, to be honest, I still couldn&#39;t see the damned OF
prompt, despite my numerous attempts and ways of pressing the
combination of keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the first task to make it work would, obviously, be to
install MacOS 8.0 on this machine. Well, this sounds great, but my
experience with it is a tiny bit different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first of the problems is that the machine doesn&#39;t boot while
the HD is connected to it. Weird, huh? I agree. If, on the other
hand, I disconnect the machine, put the MacOS CD on the CD drive,
let MacOS start loading and &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; plug the power connector
on the HD, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; the machine will boot MacOS and see the HD,
partition it and I am able to install MacOS on it. But on the next
reboot, I am not able to get things working without disconnecting
the power of the HD again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conformed to be working with the machine this way, I downloaded a
huge load of ISO images for it, including the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netbsd.org/Ports/macppc/&quot;&gt;NetBSD port for PPC&lt;/a&gt;, the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/ports/powerpc/&quot;&gt;Debian 2.2r3 port for PPC&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxppc.org&quot;&gt;LinuxPPC 2000 Q4&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yellowdoglinux.com&quot;&gt;Yellow Dog Linux 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. I made sure
the images I downloaded all had the right MD5SUMs and even used
rsync on the images after I had downloaded them, just to make sure
everything got alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, of all those images, the only one that booted on the Apple
was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxppc.org&quot;&gt;LinuxPPC 2000 Q4 image&lt;/a&gt;, which
was quite frustrating. The Debian CDs that I burned (I burned two:
one from a US site and another with non-US programs) didn&#39;t even
boot, including boot floppies generated from them -- quite a shame,
since that is, by far, my preferred operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to LinuxPPC. Seeing the machine boot with a
framebuffer with that little penguin holding a mug of beer and
telling me many things about the hardware that I didn&#39;t even know
is actually quite refreshing (no pun intended). After the kernel
boots, an X installer is started, a little menu appears and
things... ...STOP! That&#39;s right. After investigating a bit, I
discovered that programs are segfaulting consistenly in a reboot,
but in different reboots, the applications that segfault are not
necessarily the same that segfaulted in previous reboots. This may
be a hint that its memory is not OK, although I&#39;m not so sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I subscribed to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/#debian-powerpc&quot;&gt;Debian PowerPC mailing list&lt;/a&gt;
and I have been following it daily, learning a lot of things about
PPC in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My faith is restored now that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://penguinppc.org/~eb/&quot;&gt;Ethan Benson&lt;/a&gt; has posted CVS-snapshots
of the woody boot floppies on his page &lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt;, with them, I &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt;
boot my machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have those problems with the HD, although its days are
counted on this machine: I&#39;ll be soon getting a 2GB SCSI HD for it
(I hope!), so that I can continue my journey of installing Debian
potato/woody (or any other operating system!) on this machine. I
can&#39;t wait to have the beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 2.2&lt;/a&gt;,
the highly anticipated &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; and the
amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qmail.org/&quot;&gt;qmail&lt;/a&gt; running on this machine
(things that this machine designers never dreamt of running on this
old machine).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
