<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged network</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/network/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>2001-03-10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-03-10/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-03-10/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>health</category>

	<category>kde</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>network</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t do many important things today, besides making a brand new
installation of Debian&#39;s sid/unstable to see how things were going
with the bleeding edge. It turned out to be better than I expected
(I had some problems experiencing unstable before, so I was
scared).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the nicest things are that it features XFree86 4.0.2 (with
the RENDER extension, since I have a Matrox G400) and that, coupled
with KDE 2.1/qt 2.3.0, makes it possible to use antialised fonts,
which make one&#39;s surfing experience much more pleasing, for
instance. If you are on the same boat, don&#39;t forget to visit
&lt;a href=&quot;http://keithp.com/~keithp/&quot;&gt;Keith Packard&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, as it
features a handy
&lt;a href=&quot;http://keithp.com/~keithp/fonts/XftConfig&quot;&gt;XftConfig file&lt;/a&gt;. The
only lowpoint of KDE with antialiasing is that if AA is enabled,
then you loose non-scalable fonts with KDE applications, which
means that you can&#39;t make konsole use a 10x20 fixed font anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt;, KDE 2.1 allows one
to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windowmaker.org/&quot;&gt;Windowmaker&lt;/a&gt; Dock
Applications, and this is a very welcome thing as I love wmifs. The
more I use KDE, the more I&#39;m impressed with it, in many respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managed also to find some sites explaining Androgenetic Alopecia
and which are potential treatments for it. Frankly, I&#39;d love to not
have to surf these sites... And keeping with the surfing thing,
found a remarkable program called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vtun.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;vtun&lt;/a&gt;, for setting up encrypted
TCP/IP tunnels. Handy for WANs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&#39;m keeping reading about Multiple Sequence Alignment, which is
getting more exciting day after day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
