<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged audio</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/audio/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/audio/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:32:05 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Android recording audio quality</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-04-20-android_recording_audio_quality/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-04-20-android_recording_audio_quality/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:17:05 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-18T11:32:05Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Roughly sorted by quality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;amr_nb in 3gpp &amp;lt; amr_wb in 3gpp &amp;lt; aac_lc in m4a &amp;lt; aac+ in m4a (only in Android 4.0+) &amp;lt; opus in webm (only in android 5+) &amp;lt; pcm in wav (only in android 4.1+)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking into consideration the compatibility of the codecs (mainly with
Android and with the popular WhatsApp and Telegram messengers), the best
options seem to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;aac_lc in m4a &amp;lt; aac+ in m4a (API &amp;gt;= 16) &amp;lt; vorbis/opus in webm (API &amp;gt;= 21) &amp;lt; pcm in wav (only in android 4.1+)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a device running API 14, we can use something like this
(&lt;code&gt;MediaRecorder.OutputFormat&lt;/code&gt; constants):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For very low quality/very low bitrate/very long recording times, use
AMR-NB in 3GPP container.  Parameters summary: 8kHz and bitrate 12.8kbps
Works pretty much anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For low quality/low bitrate/long recording times, use AAC in MP4
container, with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;m4a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; extension. Works pretty much anywhere. Example
code adapted from:
https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/media/mediarecorder.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;private void startRecording() {
   mRecorder = new MediaRecorder();
   mRecorder.setAudioSource(MediaRecorder.AudioSource.MIC);
   mRecorder.setOutputFormat(MediaRecorder.OutputFormat.MPEG_4); // other?
   mRecorder.setOutputFile(mFileName); // end in m4a, for compatibility
   mRecorder.setAudioEncoder(MediaRecorder.AudioEncoder.AAC); // AAC_HE, if supported


   try {
       mRecorder.prepare();
   } catch (IOException e) {
       Log.e(LOG_TAG, &quot;prepare() failed&quot;);
   }


   mRecorder.start();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Preliminary support for webm in youtube-dl</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/preliminary-support-for-webm-in-youtube-dl/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/preliminary-support-for-webm-in-youtube-dl/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>libraries</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 17:06:18 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-03-12T03:27:55Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I just added some very, very preliminary support for web in &lt;code&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/code&gt; which &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel-changes/2010/05/msg02694.html&quot;&gt;I uploaded&lt;/a&gt; to unstable some minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, at least people will have some material (in, fact, a chance) to play with this format.  I implemented this because, so far, I was only hoping here that a player for this would emerge. I guess that Debian&#39;s ffmpeg/mplayer will take some time, but I was pleased to see that Sebastian Dröge to upload a version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-devel-changes/2010/05/msg02596.html&quot;&gt;something&lt;/a&gt; that could use the new &lt;code&gt;libvpx&lt;/code&gt; codec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that, now, as a side effect of webm being widely available, more people become interested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vorbis.com/&quot;&gt;Vorbis&lt;/a&gt;. More support (no, not &quot;alternative&quot;, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rockbox.org/&quot;&gt;Rockbox&lt;/a&gt;, but straight from the manufacturers) for it in hardware devices will be sweet. Well, I can dream. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:-)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it seems to be time to shape up that local build of mine of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/aoyoume/aotuv/&quot;&gt;aotuv&lt;/a&gt; tuned version of Vorbis with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/aoyoume/&quot;&gt;Aoyumi&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s patches for libvorbis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exciting times in the multimedia world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2009-03-03</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-03-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-03-03/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>audio</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>health</category>

	<category>ipod</category>

	<category>kernel</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>macosx</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>programming</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2009 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T11:53:39Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the &lt;code&gt;m3s.pl&lt;/code&gt; script made by Scott Lawrence, and given
the fact that he doesn&#39;t care anymore about it, I decided to see
what I could do so that I could generate MP3 CDs that will play
well with iTunes (like if they were regular audio CDs, but with
huge capacity and without connecting to the network to fetch
metadata).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the script could really gain some improvements
and that having it up to date has forced me to remember some Perl.
I made a lot of successful, incremental improvements by
encapsulating the code and making it reasonably readable (even with
a language that people say that is only &quot;writeable&quot;, but not
&quot;readable&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I implemented things inserting data into a hash and then using the
name of the types of the fields that have to be in the
ContentsDB.xml file to write the appropriate values, but then I saw
that what I was doing was quite silly and implemented things in an
easier, cleaner way. Taking care to have things encoded in utf-8
and escaping the &amp;amp; character when writing the XML file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original program used the &lt;code&gt;MP3::Info&lt;/code&gt; module to gather
information about the songs. This module isn&#39;t as rich as the
&lt;code&gt;MP3::Tag&lt;/code&gt; module (which is able to get track numbers, track
counts, disc numbers, and disc counts, just off the top of my
head). This &quot;new&quot; module is quite good and more flexible and that&#39;s
what I adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, to traverse the directory tree, I am using &lt;code&gt;File::Find&lt;/code&gt;,
instead of a home-brew solution to the problem. There is only one
thing left for the script to be finished: having it write correctly
the &quot;numerical path&quot;, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; likes to
call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, remembering things about references, compound data
structures, object orientation, the use of modules etc. has made me
gain some interest in Perl again. I think that I will make some
effort and learn it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I just submitted my third patch for the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/&quot;&gt;Linux kernel&lt;/a&gt;: it fixes the compilation
(and recognition) of the MTD device of the Kurobox HD that I have.
Now, I am running a brand new 2.6.29-rc6 kernel (yes, yes, it is
brand new right now, but at the breakneck pace with which the
kernel is moving, it will soon be quite outdated; I will try to
keep the powerpc part of things in shape, though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last, but not least, was the fact that I was submitted to a
biopsy (the original idea was for it to be just a colonoscopy, but
I had some inflammatory process in my elbows and some material had
to be removed for analysis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t really think that I am finished with all these health
things, but I surely made some improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I lied when I said that the biopsy thing was the last one that
I would write about. I am in the process of compressing movies with
the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://divxenc.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;divxenc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xvidenc.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;xvidenc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://h264enc.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;h264enc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; scripts to generate
videos that are appropriate for playing in some set top boxes
&lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; getting smaller files (which means that I will make my
small NAS last a little bit longer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since I discovered how to register myself on the iTunes music
store, I am downloading some German Podcasts. Will I be able to
learn some German? Well, I dearly hope so. My only grief is that I
am desperately running out of space and I will have to rethink my
backup strategy to leave some room for things to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I also played a little with MacOS X Tiger on Intel and the fact
that my e100 card didn&#39;t work with Tiger out-of-the box. I had to
use a special kernel extension for this very purpose. The only
thing that annoys me a lot is that I can trigger kernel panics with
the JaS kernel 10.4.8 in a deterministic manner. Upgrading the
kernel to 10.4.10 made my system not mount some disk images (and
even &quot;real&quot; disks, like my iPod video). I should, perhaps, try
Leopard here to see how things are structured and to see the
changes that Apple has provided to the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding some cutting-edge programs, I saw that some programs were
removed from Debian after the release of lenny, since upstream is
inactive or dead. Too bad. But the nice side of things is that
snapshot.debian.net is a terrific service to the community and I&#39;ve
compiled things from there and got excellent results. I think that
I may even create a non-official repository with some multimedia
programs (and this includes, say, a newer, multithreaded version of
mplayer and newer libraries). I think that I will submit some more
bugreports (like the Real Video files from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aduni.org/&quot;&gt;ArsDigita University&lt;/a&gt; that
can&#39;t be played).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one last thing: (this one is really the last thing that I will
comment now) is that I finally will re-record my audio (and video)
things on digital media, so that I can preserve it without the loss
of magnetic media. This is a time-consuming activity, but I think
that it is worth the effort, especially if I use an automated setup
like Audacity&#39;s noise removal tool. Or is it better to use sox for
this task? I guess that I will have to experiment a little.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2009-02-03</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-02-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-02-03/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>ipod</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few days, I did quite a good amount of things. One of
the things that took most of my mind was to convert some videos in
a proper format for the iPod. At first, I thought that the format
of the videos would have to have an H.264 encoded video with
resolution 320x240 (without using cabac, which increases the
compression factor of the video) and audio in the AAC format with
bitrates up to 160kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, using Apple&#39;s Quicktime Pro 7, I exported a video from the
Dutch band called After Forever, which had the resolution bigger
than 320x240. This made me revisit Apple&#39;s site where the
specifications of videos meant to be played on iPods. It seems
that, now, with the latest firmware update, the iPod that I have
can play H.264 videos encoded with resolutions up to 640x480 (the
standard VGA resolution). Also, the bitrate doesn&#39;t need to be
restricted to 768kbps: some of the videos produced by Quicktime
(and which the iPods can play) have bitrates of up to 1500kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that I can now encode some of my videos that are in the
nasty WMV format to formats that can be supported in a decent
manner by Free Software system. I have, for instance, the
BBC-produced DVD called &quot;The Codebreakers&quot;, whose audio is in pure
DVD LPCM format (that is, uncompressed) and the space that it takes
on my hard disk is considerable (approx. 1GB).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2009-01-28</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-01-28/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-01-28/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a very unusual day: it was quite active and I didn&#39;t have
a day like today for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had slept quite late, since I was waiting for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Quicktime 7 Pro for Windows (on my
girlfriend&#39;s computer) to finish the conversion of a video from one
of Cynic&#39;s show from their reunion. It was a show that was webcast
by the Norwegian company nhk.no (if I&#39;m not mistaken) and the show
is superb (it was from 2007 and they even played a, then,
unreleased song called &quot;Evolutionary Sleeper&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing of it all is that even though we where using a
x86-based machine (actually, a Duron 1.3GHz on a board with a SiS
730 chipset), which supported even SSE, things were quite slow. In
fact, the show took 1 day and some hours to be completely
&quot;exported&quot; in the iPod format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that was noteworthy was that my GF had some CDs that
she had burned and that contained some audio files from a course
that she took some time ago. Since those classes are quite
important and they interest me, I would like to listen to them. The
&quot;problem&quot; is that they are in IMA ADPCM format which most car
players don&#39;t play. The solution, in this case, will be to use lame
with libsndfile1 as input and convert the files to the MP3 format,
so that I can neatly tag the files and listen to them on my (and
her) car player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is only the beginning of the story, since two of her CDs
were not readable on my iBook G3, dammit. I, then, took the time to
download dvdisaster on her Windows computer (first, the stable
version; then, the more feature-full development version) and I
left the CDs being read. Unfortunately, it seems that even
dvdisaster is having a hard time reading many sectors of the CD-RWs
(and, yes, I did wash the discs with abundant water and used a very
soft towel to get them dry).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, another thing that I&#39;ve learned was that uTorrent is very
featureful. Apparently, much more featureful than Transmission. I&#39;d
say that its features are on par with Azureus (even though I have
not used Azureus for a loooong time, as it is Java-based and my
machines don&#39;t have enough horsepower for programs that are not
natively compiled).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the torrent to grab Ubuntu&#39;s jaunty alpha 3, so that I can
experiment with things to come (and the new notification system
that Mark has proposed. I actually liked it very much, but I am
eager to see it working). The only catch is that my GF&#39;s connection
is only 150kbps and things are &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; slow here, but I&#39;m getting
the image anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, I went to the proctologist. After that, I went to
see a friend of mine from the high-school days, that is now a
neuro-cirugeon, I had lost contact with him, but I sincerely hope
to get back in touch frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I went with my GF to the bank where she has her account to
see if he had some residual money from a nation-wide program called
FGTS. She did have, but some documents were missing. The worker
that received us told her that she could mail some of the missing
documentation via e-mail and we scanned the necessary
documentation, but the mails bounced. Bummer. At least, the trip to
the bank wasn&#39;t completely useless, since I saw that I have some
money on this FGTS thing and it was a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latter, I went to the local theater and saw that professors are
able to have a 50% discount on the entrance to see the movies,
given that we prove that we are actually active. This is a very
nice thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also saw the price of a new, Classic 120GB iPod. It wasn&#39;t
available on the store that I went to, but other store of the same
name has some units. I guess that I should see one. I was only
surprised to see that the 160GB model doesn&#39;t seem to be sold
anymore. Any reason for that? That left me puzzled, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the electronics store, I also saw a netbook from HP that was
sweet. Soooo small, so cute. I guess that I need one. It has a very
small form factor and it features a 1.2GHz VIA C7M processor. The
only things that made the red alert lights blink for me were the
Broadcom network interfaces: both wired and wireless, and Broadcom
is know to not be exactly that helpful with the Free Software
Movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to get a haircut and my girlfriend told me that
it was good. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latter, before going to her place, we went to my home just for a
little while so that I could see how the torrents for MIT&#39;s &quot;The
Structure and Interpretation of Computer Program&quot; MPEG1 videos were
going. Not good at all. Everything is stalled. I guess that I will
need to use this uTorrent thing (at least, experiment with it) so
that I can see if the downloads are slightly better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also did something unusual: scanned a 3x4 (centimeters, of
course!) photo of mine (which is needed here in Brazil for quite a
lot of documents) and collated it in 3 rows, in a way that I will
have 9 pics. I will print two of them (and have 18 pictures) for
R$0.69 each, which is not a bad deal. My girlfriend liked the idea
and I will do the same thing for her, since she will need many
photos for her id&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we got the vacuum cleaner to clean up her place (mostly
the TV room) and I cleaned her fan (which was quite dusty).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, the day will be quite full and I will have a lot of
things to do in this endless saga. I hope to write more about this
hectic (but pleasant) week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-09-24</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-09-24/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-09-24/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Now I am officially a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/changelogs/pool/main/d/debian-maintainers/current/changelog#versionversion1.45&quot;&gt;Debian Maintainer&lt;/a&gt;.
I&#39;m very happy now. This means that I can upload my own packages to
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, without pestering
&lt;a href=&quot;http://alfie.ist.org/&quot;&gt;Rhonda&lt;/a&gt; about them. But I still want her
opinions on some packages, given the experience that she has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it seems that I&#39;ll be part of another project,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/lossywav&quot;&gt;lossyWAV&lt;/a&gt;, given the current
discussions on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hydrogenaudio.org/forums/index.php?showtopic=65499&amp;amp;st=50&amp;amp;gopid=589938&quot;&gt;hydrogenaudio forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and only today I realized that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&#39;s Intrepid Ibex&lt;/a&gt; alpha 6 was
released. Time to go downloading things to use on my most recent
purchase...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more musically related note, Symphony X
&lt;a href=&quot;http://whiplash.net/materias/news_883/077645-symphonyx.html&quot;&gt;will be coming here&lt;/a&gt;
to São Paulo, which is a nice thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-07-20</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-20/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-20/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Just discovered that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com/&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt; (or would it be
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roadrunnerrecords.com/&quot;&gt;Roadrunner Records&lt;/a&gt;?) has
released a version of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watershed_(Opeth_album)&quot;&gt;Watershed with extra tracks and with a DVD documentary&lt;/a&gt;.
They have also released another special version that has
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cKx5zrb0Z_0&quot;&gt;Porcelain Heart&lt;/a&gt;
played with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mellotron&quot;&gt;Mellotron&lt;/a&gt;
(which brings orgasms to all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_rock&quot;&gt;progressive rock&lt;/a&gt;
fans, like myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also got my parents to sit in front of my old, trusty
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duron&quot;&gt;Duron&lt;/a&gt;-based &lt;code&gt;dumont&lt;/code&gt; (in
honor of Brazilian pioneer
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santos_Dumont&quot;&gt;Alberto Santos-Dumont&lt;/a&gt;).
It is interesting to note that, while the Level 2
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CPU_cache&quot;&gt;cache&lt;/a&gt; of the Duron system
is small for a low-cost processor (in reference to its rival
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celeron&quot;&gt;Celeron&lt;/a&gt; processor, that had
a bigger Level 2 cache), it has a much bigger
(128&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KiB&quot;&gt;KiB&lt;/a&gt;) Level 1 cache than
what I have in a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentium_D&quot;&gt;Pentium D&lt;/a&gt; machine: only
16KB for each core (at least for data; that&#39;s what my &lt;code&gt;dmesg&lt;/code&gt;
says). Surprising to say the least. And this explains why
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AMD&quot;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; stood on the front of the
race during the Athlon (Thunderbird) days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding other architectures (I have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerPC&quot;&gt;PowerPC&lt;/a&gt; in mind here), I&#39;m
not especially happy with them: my
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerPC_G3&quot;&gt;PowerPC G3&lt;/a&gt; lacks
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_processor&quot;&gt;vector instructions&lt;/a&gt;,
which means that playing multimedia files (read: movies) is
something painful. The problem is that I &lt;strong&gt;quite&lt;/strong&gt; like the iBook&#39;s
form factor and I have not yet seen anything that matches it yet.
Comments are welcome here. Yes, it seems that I am not alone here,
given all the frenziness about the surge of netbook computers, like
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASUS_Eee_PC&quot;&gt;Eee PC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I setup my old sound gear on what is my main (desktop)
computer. It is nice to have a good sound whenever I am working
(well, whenever I am working lightly, as I need sound to be absent
when I&#39;m working hard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, BTW, just found a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vindaci.members.sonic.net/cbreak/projects/autotools/&quot;&gt;superb autotools tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
that starts with the egregious &lt;code&gt;&quot;Hello, World!&quot;&lt;/code&gt; application. This
is a perfect point for reading more advanced documents on this
matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-07-19</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-19/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-19/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Have been
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/lame/lame/doc/html/history.html?revision=HEAD&quot;&gt;working quite a bit&lt;/a&gt;
on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; project to have the best MP3
encoder around. It&#39;s been all a learning exercise dealing with all
the magic behind
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lrde.epita.fr/~adl/autotools.html&quot;&gt;autotools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there are some areas where we can fix with just a
working knowledge of C and computer architecture, like fixing the
interface to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Sound_System&quot;&gt;Open Sound System&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ABX_test&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;abx&lt;/code&gt; tool&lt;/a&gt; that comes with
lame (in the &lt;code&gt;misc&lt;/code&gt; directory), as well as the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endianness&quot;&gt;endianness&lt;/a&gt; problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-07-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-07-04/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>mp3</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME 3.98 final&lt;/a&gt; was released.
Unfortunately, I missed the boat and didn&#39;t commit all the changes
that I had, but I will continue working on it nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2008-05-23</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-23/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-23/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Gave a second talk to the group of &quot;Error Correcting Codes&quot;. This
time, I carried my &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S1MP3&quot;&gt;S1MP3&lt;/a&gt;
player/recorder and recorded the talk. The nice thing is that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lame.sf.net/&quot;&gt;LAME&lt;/a&gt; with libsndfile1 can read those files
directly, without any kind of conversion first, which automates
things quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the seminar, I talked about algorithm invariants, how to
discover them, how close to mathematical induction they are, gave
examples of some programs, described the bubble sort algorithm in
our native/high level language, talked about its stability, talked
about its invariant, talked about its time and space complexity,
remarked that the algorithm works on any totally ordered set and,
finally, to answer a question from the audience, talked about the
limited precision of &quot;integers&quot; that we use on computers and
multiprecision libraries used to hold values as large as we
please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was also dad&#39;s birthday! Hippie!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
