<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged mooc</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/mooc/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 16:34:54 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Quick tip #1</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-10-18-bittorrent_with_webseed/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2013-10-18-bittorrent_with_webseed/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>quick-tip</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 12:49:09 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-19T19:34:54Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote the following as part of a post to an discussion forum (I can&#39;t
remember which one), and people told me that they liked this information and
said that others would profit from it if I posted it on my blog, which I now
decided to post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The context: for homework of one &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MOOC&quot;&gt;MOOC&lt;/a&gt;, people were trying to
download a large virtual machine image that was offered both via an official
HTTP source, which was slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person volunteered that already had downloaded the image volunteered to
create a bittorrent to help fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other students started saying that the bittorrent download was faster up to
a certain point and, then, things slowed down a lot. Of course, they got
faster to the point where lots of pieces were already well distributed and,
then, only the everybody had already downloaded things and, then, only the
seeder had the missing segments of the torrent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I commented with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your bittorrent client, you can add the original HTTP
download as a &quot;Web seed&quot; and, this way, your client will download &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt;
from the peers and also from the web to fill in parts that are not yet
available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such client is the Free (as in Freedom) &lt;a href=&quot;http://qbittorrent.sf.net/&quot;&gt;qbittorrent&lt;/a&gt;, but I guess that
others also have this option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after that, people started downloading things much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Playing with MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/playing_with_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/playing_with_moocs/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>education</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>git</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>python</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:33:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:07:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Not so much ago, we had a boom of new enterprises offering Massive Online
Open Courses (MOOCs for short).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First were Thrun and Norvig (Artificial Intelligence), with Widom
(Introduction to Databases) and Ng (Machine Learning). Then, these initial
experiments led to the creation of Udacity (founded by Thrun) and Coursera
(founded by Ng and Koller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been keeping an eye on them for some time and, in fact, I have been
contributing to a project similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; (which
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;I package for Debian&lt;/a&gt;), but focused on downloading videos from
Cousera, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jplehmann/coursera&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;coursera-dl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started contributing to &lt;code&gt;coursera-dl&lt;/code&gt; because I wanted to stratch some
itches with downloading with &lt;a href=&quot;http://aria2.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aria2c&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but soon the original
author of the project granted me write permission to the repository and I
have been one of the persons that commits the most, which is strange, since
I was not the original creator of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, from the courses that grant certificates, I have concluded the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part 1 (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Databases (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum Mechanics and Quantum Computation (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Cryptography I (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M101P: MongoDB for Developers (10gen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M102: MongoDB for DBAs (10gen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers (10gen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have to say that this have been a pleasant experience, with some of the
courses being challenging, but not up to what an undergraduate course would
be (and the fears of some people that such courses would threaten the
conventional University-style model are a bit far at this point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, talking about challenging courses, in particular, prof. Umesh
Vazirani&#39;s &quot;Quantum Mechanics and Quantum Computation&quot; had a lot of
(computational) work and this was one of the courses that prompted me to use
a computer algebra system for manipulating some tedious calculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I used a mix of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sagenb.org/&quot;&gt;online SAGE math server&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wolframalpha.com/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Alpha&lt;/a&gt;, whichever I found the syntax to be easier to use for
the problem in question. It is with happiness that I see that there are
efforts to &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~thansen/debian-sage-status.html&quot;&gt;get SAGE again packaged in Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another (positively) surprising course has been Dan Boneh&#39;s &quot;Introduction to
Cryptography I&quot;, which was more theoretical and more serious than what I was
expecting. It even included some nice proof sketches and discussion of
recent results. The last course on cryptography that I took was in 1998 and
&lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of things changed since then, including the way to think about
cryptography. But more on that on a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some other courses that I may be completing soon and that I will
post more about, with some reviews of the good and the bad parts of select
ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
