<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged work</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/work/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>2001-09-18</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-09-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-09-18/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>kde</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;A busy day working -- lots of phone calls helping a customer to get
his Windows 2000 working correctly with IP routing. Then (on the
bright side), made the Linux boxes of another customer&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netlink.psi.br&quot;&gt;ISP&lt;/a&gt; work well with Radius
authentication services. Unfortunately, we could not test it, but
everything there looks good. We&#39;ll see tomorrow if there are any
complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 2.2.1&lt;/a&gt; was released today. That&#39;s
great, since it is a quite advanced Desktop Environment for Linux
available now and is way more polished than
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnome.org/&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; is, at least IMO. It will hit
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/sid/&quot;&gt;sid&lt;/a&gt; in some days and soon
will be in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/woody/&quot;&gt;woody&lt;/a&gt; (I
hope).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of new things in the Debian incoming repository: KDE 2.2.1,
KOffice 1.1, Broadcast 2000, dillo, and Java 1.3. Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-02-05</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-02-05/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-02-05/</link>


	<category>study</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I didn&#39;t go to my customer today, as I expected. I received a
call telling me that they wouldn&#39;t be able to receive me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I think that today was a modestly productive day: I spent a
lot of time sending e-mails dealing with bureaucratic matters (like
the English proficiency exam, my quest in trying to get a financial
support for my studies and a status update to advisor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m really, really crossing my fingers to go to IBM&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.research.ibm.com/summerjobs/&quot;&gt;Summer Jobs&lt;/a&gt;, but,
sincerely, I don&#39;t know what they are looking for in people
applying for the positions. I guess that I should study more right
now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-02-04</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-02-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-02-04/</link>


	<category>bind</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:09:53Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I am going to a customer of mine to update his server.
With the BIND breakage, I&#39;ll have some packages to
&lt;code&gt;apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt;. I&#39;ll also put backups in a systematic way and
make time updates with NTP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-09-29</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-29/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-29/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2000 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-12-09T02:51:00Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;An unusual day. First things first, I had the news that one of my
favourite sites, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slashdot.org&quot;&gt;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt; was cracked
(&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; hacked) by some guys from Netherlands. According to the
reports from Slashdot themselves, it was their careless setting
that allowed that and that they&#39;ve now learned the lesson and
secured their boxes. The sad state of computer security. Or
security in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know what happened to my mind, but I cleaned my car. Hell&#39;s
temperature must be getting lower now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I had to return a Celeron 400MHz that I was using to a place
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxcenter.com.br&quot;&gt;where I occasionally work&lt;/a&gt;. It was
my guinea pig and I used it to test Debian&#39;s woody and, when I felt
brave, Linux 2.4 pre-releases. Now, I put my good, old, trustworthy
486 DX/2 66 back to use. It only has 8MB of RAM and a 120MB HD that
is not sufficient for demanding applications people use nowadays,
but I made a minimal install of Debian&#39;s slink and upgraded it to
potato (only 50 megs!), together with a custom compiled kernel.
Soon it will have 2 NICs and I&#39;ll use it as my router/firewall for
an ADSL connection (after Slashdot&#39;s fate, I&#39;m willing to put a lot
of effort in the &quot;firewall&quot; part of it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the time to see what loads it could handle and I&#39;m more or
less satisfied with the results I got. I used it to transfer a 50MB
file to my Pentium MMX via
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cr.yp.to/publicfile.html&quot;&gt;publicfile&lt;/a&gt; many times and it
sustained 550KB/s. While I suspect it will not handle the situation
so gracefully with 2 NICs, it seemed to me that the real bottleneck
for higher speeds was the disk task, which as a router is close to
zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this means that I have no idea what I can expect from it. Oh,
well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
