<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged browsers</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/browsers/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/browsers/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/browsers/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2011-03-12T03:52:56Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>(Some) Solutions with Chromium</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/some_solutions_with_chromium/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/some_solutions_with_chromium/"/>






	<category term="browsers" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="extensions" />

	<category term="free-software" />


	<updated>2011-03-12T03:52:56Z</updated>
	<published>2011-03-09T17:33:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/browsers/../../posts/problems_with_chromium/&quot;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I was pointing out some of
my frustrations with Chromium/Chrome.  A very kind reader, Timo Juhani
Lindfors, gave me answers to many of the problems that I pointed out and got
me straight on some issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can disable full zoom in Iceweasel (i.e., I only want to zoom the text,
not the images). According to Chromium&#39;s project BTS, it seems that this
will be a &lt;code&gt;WONTFIX&lt;/code&gt; bug, despite many people asking for it (and it having
a lot of duplicates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timo told me that there is an extension called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ombpcpigmndepfckcifdblemkabaoihk&quot;&gt;&quot;Font Size Increase&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
(ID: ombpcpigmndepfckcifdblemkabaoihk) that adds a button on the side of the
URL bar that you can click to increase the size of the text, without
affecting the size of the images. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that I need this one as much as &quot;Font Size Increase&quot;, but there is also
a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mpajngnpcmjjeoflljdjpnehcfaldcia&quot;&gt;&quot;Font Size Decrease&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (ID: mpajngnpcmjjeoflljdjpnehcfaldcia) that,
as the name implies, decreases the size of the text. It is nice to have this
one when you clicked on the button to increase the size of the font one or
two times too many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I have a way (without resorting to many extensions or
hackish solutions) to use the equivalent of Firefox&#39;s &quot;View &gt; Page Style &gt;
No Style&quot; (i.e., to ignore any CSS sheet that the document author may have
specified on the page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timo also told me that there is a very cool extension called
&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ddpkgkegfklikkmfmneldonhldahhacb&quot;&gt;&quot;Chrome Page Style&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (ID: ddpkgkegfklikkmfmneldonhldahhacb) that
allows you to alternate between stylesheets provided by the page (see Joey
Hess&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://ikiwiki.info/css_market/&quot;&gt;ikiwiki&#39;s CSS Market&lt;/a&gt; for an example of that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also has the possibility of disabling all the CSS&#39;es that a page may
have, which, in many cases around the web &lt;em&gt;actually improves&lt;/em&gt; the
readability of the pages, for many &quot;fancy&quot; things detract from readability,
especially if you have poor eyesight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I had said that I didn&#39;t want to resort to extensions, this was a
simple solution enough that made me consider revisit my requirements.  I do,
though, wonder why some frequently used extensions are not built into the
programs from stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I can press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Q&lt;/code&gt; and make the damn browser quit, instead
of me having to use the mouse/trackpad/pointing device. This is probably a
lack of my understanding on how to associate key bindings to Chromium, but
the problem still stands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Timo also set me straight and told me about &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shift+Q&lt;/code&gt; for
that purpose, which I had missed completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, when there is only one tab open, pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; in Chromium
does not close the tab (say, presenting me a blank tab or the list of most
visited sites), nor it closes the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a poor writing of my part, &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; does close the tabs. But when there
is only one tab present, it doesn&#39;t close the window. I&#39;m OK with that,
since I now know the way to close the window. Thanks again Timo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one point that may not be known by many is that using &lt;code&gt;about:flags&lt;/code&gt;
in Chrome does something analogue to Firefox&#39;s &lt;code&gt;about:config&lt;/code&gt; (even with the
warning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And tweaking with it you can try to see if you can enable hardware
acceleration of some parts of your pages, as present in newer releases of
Chromium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there I am: way more satisfied than with earlier with Chromium, but
still having Firefox/Iceweasel as my primary browser. Good to have two
usable browsers now.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>My problems with Chromium</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/problems_with_chromium/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/problems_with_chromium/"/>






	<category term="browsers" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="extensions" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="launchpad" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2011-03-12T03:52:56Z</updated>
	<published>2011-02-26T14:55:06Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Given that Chromium/Chrome is used more and more (as became apparent
&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.debian.org/debian-release/2010/09/msg00610.html&quot;&gt;with the discussion of including it in Debian&#39;s squeeze&lt;/a&gt;), I decided to
give it some tries, mainly Giuseppe Iuculano&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.qa.debian.org/c/chromium-browser.html&quot;&gt;version&lt;/a&gt;. I occasionally
install Chromium from Fabien Tassin&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~chromium-daily/+archive/ppa&quot;&gt;daily builds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, to be honest, I have also contributed a good amount (about 400) of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~rbrito/+karma&quot;&gt;translated strings&lt;/a&gt; to the Brazilian Portuguese part of Chromium. As a
matter of fact, I have even done some &quot;activism&quot; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~savanabifulco&quot;&gt;incentivated&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~bifulcojunior&quot;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~victor.westmann/+karma&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; to create their accounts on Launchpad and help with
the projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I always come back to Iceweasel/Firefox, especially with Mike Hommey&#39;s
frequently updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozilla.debian.net/&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are my reasons for staying with Iceweasel, and not with Chromium?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can disable full zoom in Iceweasel (i.e., I only want to zoom the text,
not the images). According to Chromium&#39;s project BTS, it seems that this
will be a &lt;code&gt;WONTFIX&lt;/code&gt; bug, despite many people asking for it (and it having
a lot of duplicates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can, in Iceweasel, set my preferred fonts without resorting to hacks on
the system level, like say, having to lie with fontconfig or other stuff.
And I really want Deja Vu Sans, not a serifed font.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, a middle mouse click on &quot;an inactive portion&quot; of the page
makes me go to the URL that is the system clipboard, just like pasting
stuff in X, in general, works.  I guess that there may be some way to
enable this in Chromium, but, so far, I have not found it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I have a way (without resorting to many extensions or
hackish solutions) to use the equivalent of Firefox&#39;s &quot;View &gt; Page Style &gt;
No Style&quot; (i.e., to ignore any CSS sheet that the document author may have
specified on the page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, my personal data is encrypted before being synced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I can press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Q&lt;/code&gt; and make the damn browser quit, instead
of me having to use the mouse/trackpad/pointing device. This is probably a
lack of my understanding on how to associate key bindings to Chromium, but
the problem still stands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, when there is only one tab open, pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; in Chromium
does not close the tab (say, presenting me a blank tab or the list of most
visited sites), nor it closes the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I would be satisfied if any of the above were fixed or better documented,
but it seems that some of those are, at best, going to wait a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
