<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged math</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/math/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>Music, Group Actions, Quilt and Debian Packages</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/music-group-actions-quilt-and-debian-packages/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/music-group-actions-quilt-and-debian-packages/</link>


	<category>abstract-algebra</category>

	<category>class-equation</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>group-actions</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>quilt</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 02:08:51 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T07:19:57Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;These are some short notes on what I&#39;ve doing these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there isn&#39;t much to talk about. I think that one of the most
relevant things that I did was to resurrect one of my best
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital%5Faudio%5Fextraction&quot;&gt;audio-extracting&lt;/a&gt; CD-ROM
drives: just opened the case of my computer, took off the CD drive, opened,
cleaned its lens, lubricated the moving parts and everything is back to
normal operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sense of &quot;getting something for nothing&quot; is hard to explain to those
who have not experienced it already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things that I did was to grab some old CDs that I had laying here
(Radiohead&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OK%20Computer&quot;&gt;OK Computer&lt;/a&gt;, Pantera&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Far%5FBeyond%5FDriven&quot;&gt;Far Beyond Driven&lt;/a&gt;, the tribute to Queen called &quot;Dragon
Attack&quot;, and Gentle Giant&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free%20Hand&quot;&gt;Free Hand&lt;/a&gt;, among others). Dream
Theater&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systematic%5FChaos&quot;&gt;Special Edition of Systematic Chaos&lt;/a&gt;
is quite good, but unfortunately I don&#39;t have a 5.1 system at my disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also selected some material for further studies. I&#39;m right now studying
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/group%20actions&quot;&gt;group actions&lt;/a&gt; (or G-sets as some seem to prefer). Soon, I
will be finishing the basics of Group Theory (hey, really, why is the &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conjugacy_class&quot;&gt;&quot;Class Equation&quot;&lt;/a&gt; of
groups that &quot;famous&quot;? It is just a matter of saying that $|X| = \sum_{x\in
X} 1$, but with cardinality of orbits instead of with one&#39;s and with a
transversal of the orbits in place of $X$ itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, if the orbits of the elements of the $G$-set $X$ consist of just
one element, then the equation above is the &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Group_action&quot;&gt;&quot;Class Equation&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (what
some people would call $\mathop{\mathrm{Fix}}(X)$, I would call the &quot;orbits
being trivial&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burnside%27s_lemma&quot;&gt;Burnside&#39;s
lemma&lt;/a&gt; (which actually seems to be wrongly attributed, since it seems to
be discovered independently by Cauchy and Frobenius) for counting orbits of
a given action of a $G$-set has nice implications in combinatorics and it
should be, at least, mentioned in any self-respecting introduction to Group
Theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I almost forgot one of the major things that I did today (2007-06-12): I
finally learned how to manipulate the &lt;a
href=&quot;http://savannah.nongnu.org/projects/quilt&quot;&gt;quilt patch-system&lt;/a&gt;
(initiated by &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Morton_%28computer_programmer%29&quot;&gt;Andrew
Morton&lt;/a&gt;). The crucial point that is not written anywhere: the patches, by
default, are applied with &lt;code&gt;-p1&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;-p0&lt;/code&gt;. This
took me quite some time to get, as the documentation isn&#39;t explicit about
it. Installation of quilt in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS
X&lt;/a&gt; system is not trivial, due to the demand of &lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt; tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I can keep some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; packages
of mine in a better shape than if I were just applying a single monolithic
patch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Random Points on Group Theory</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/random-points-on-group-theory/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/random-points-on-group-theory/</link>


	<category>abstract-algebra</category>

	<category>group-theory</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>quotient-groups</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 14:07:11 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T07:19:57Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;It is not a surprise for anyone that I&#39;m reviewing a little bit of Abstract
Algebra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Fraleigh&#39;s book is proving to be quite a good refresher, especially
since my short-term goal is to study &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coding%20Theory&quot;&gt;Coding Theory&lt;/a&gt; and the
finer aspects of Coding Theory do involve Algebra (actually, one could say
that the finer aspects of Coding Theory, especially Error Correcting Codes,
depend quite a lot on Algebra).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, while studying Group Theory, one can&#39;t avoid to be amazed by some
results that are not exactly that intuitive. For instance, I just discovered
that the additive group $\mathbb Z[X]$ of univariate polynomials with
integer coefficients is isomorphic to the multiplicative group $\mathbb Q^+$
of positive rationals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that this was a relatively easy exercise until I posed the problem
to a very competent friend of mine and he had some problems trying to come
up with the isomorphism. His failure maybe tells me that this is not as
obvious as I once thought and I think that this exercise should be better
known, as it can show that very differently looking algebraic structures can
be &quot;the same&quot; and the most surprising fact here is that &lt;em&gt;we are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;
dealing with any pathologically &quot;made up&quot; example&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that maybe is hard for students to grasp is the concept of a
factor group. Knowing that a subgroup is normal iff it is the kernel of some
homomorphism of groups is a handy way to memorize and &quot;see&quot; what a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/normal%20subgroup&quot;&gt;normal subgroup&lt;/a&gt; is. And students should be shown that there
are some quite special (&quot;natural&quot;?) normal subgroups of a group: the &lt;em&gt;center
of the group&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;commutator subgroup&lt;/em&gt;, just as two examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter one, together with a good explanation of what does it mean for
taking &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quotient%20group&quot;&gt;factor groups&lt;/a&gt; (i.e., taking the
elements of the normal subgroup and equating them to the unity), leads to a
better understanding of quotient/factor groups. A nice thing to prove (that
is short and shows the &quot;mechanics&quot; of factor groups) is the fact that a
quotient group is abelian iff the normal group used as the &quot;denominator&quot;
contains the commutator subgroup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that is worth doing is proving that a normal subgroup $N$ is
maximal in a group $G$ iff $G/N$ is simple. The proof of this fact is
analogous to the proof of the quotient of a ring being a field iff a ring is
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Factor%20ring&quot;&gt;factored&lt;/a&gt; by a maximal ideal (and that we
get an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/integral%20domain&quot;&gt;integral domain&lt;/a&gt; if the ideal is only prime instead of
maximal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, two groups that I feel that should merit way more attention than what
I perceive as being given in a first course are the dihedral groups $D_3$
and $D_4$. Asking the students to draw the lattice of subgroups of such
groups is quite enlightening, as they are &quot;natural&quot; groups that are not
abelian (but with &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the proper subgroups being abelian). Nice examples
to have in mind, without any shadow of doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>On teaching Groups before Rings in Abstract Algebra</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/on-a-first-course-in-abstract-algebra/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/on-a-first-course-in-abstract-algebra/</link>


	<category>abstract-algebra</category>

	<category>math</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2007 17:46:52 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about how one should teach &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_algebra&quot;&gt;Abstract Algebra&lt;/a&gt;
and it seems to me that John B. Fraleigh&#39;s book &quot;A First Course in Abstract
Algebra&quot; is exactly what I would write if I confidently knew the subject and
if the book were not written yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, &lt;strong&gt;there is&lt;/strong&gt; room for improvement (and I think that I may have
alternative proofs; in fact, I&#39;m fond of multiple different proofs for a
given fact, as they shed a different light on the matter being discussed)
and I would change some demonstrations or condense some of them, but the
general outline of the book is superb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the choice (and order) of subjects is quite adequate, contrary
to many people that think that students should be exposed to &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ring_%28mathematics%29&quot;&gt;Rings&lt;/a&gt; before
being exposed to &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Group_%28mathematics%29&quot;&gt;Groups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, I think that, to foster the abstract thinking of students
that may not yet have the so-called &quot;mathematical maturity&quot;, one should give
them &quot;poor&quot; algebraic structures (satisfying just a few axioms) and then
deducing things almost &quot;mechanically&quot;. This &quot;mechanic thinking&quot; and &quot;dealing
with the unknown&quot; is quite important to dissociate the meaning that students
are used to assign to objects that they already know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, what is the &quot;fun&quot; (or even the motivation) of proving that 1
is greater than 0 on the integers? The students, quite correctly, assert
that this is &quot;obviously true&quot;, for they can &quot;draw&quot;, say, a ball on a sheet
of paper and no ball on another an say that &lt;em&gt;indeed&lt;/em&gt;, given their
intuitive knowledge of what an order relation is, that there is no need to
prove anything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only when presented with structures where this is not true is that one would
appreciate the fact that there exists an example of an infinite integral
domain (with unique factorization, which is also not to take for granted!)
is that the proof of such a fact is perceived to be important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, if &quot;everything is normal&quot;, one could think that &quot;intuitive&quot; facts
are indeed true and even disregard the necessity of proofs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning an abstract algebra book for freshmen or sophomores that had only
&quot;computational&quot; courses on Calculus up to that point (what an unfortunate
fact!) with a discussion of groups and spending a good amount of time with
proofs on elementary facts, leads the students to develop the frequently
cited prerequisite &quot;mathematical maturity&quot; needed for understanding anything
non-trivial that needs a good amount of abstraction (and this includes the
&lt;strong&gt;proper&lt;/strong&gt; programming of computers, of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should not be interpreted as an attack on texts that cover rings before
groups (or weaker structures). It just means that I think that, as a
pedagogical tool, using rings first may not be as &quot;eye-opening&quot; (for the
abstract world, and, therefore, for &lt;em&gt;Real Mathematics&lt;/em&gt;) as other
approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is completely understadable for a graduate (or even advanced
undergraduate) text to provide a &quot;fresh&quot; view on Rings (and the pathological
cases &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be included), say, by giving, as motivation, the problem
of writing primes as sums of two squares (which can be viewed as a problem
of factorization on the Gaussian Integers integral domain).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that other instructors actually read this and stop to think about the
possibilities, even if they don&#39;t agree with my views (just causing thought
is enough for me).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-10-26</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-26/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-26/</link>


	<category>complexity-theory</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-20T01:06:20Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I had the &quot;midterm&quot; today. I thought that while the subjects
covered were well chosen, it was not very well planned regarding
time. I mean, only 1h40min for all those proofs? A comfortable
period would be, say, 3h or 4h, but, then, maybe I&#39;m a
perfectionist. Maybe I&#39;m slow. Maybe both.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-10-25</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-25/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-25/</link>


	<category>complexity-theory</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-20T01:06:20Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&#39;ll have the &quot;midterm&quot; of Combinatorial Optimization.
It&#39;s not exactly a midterm, since it is considerably skewed towards
the end of the semester and I&#39;ll have 3 other tests until the
course is finished, but I guess that having this many tests is
actually better than having only two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m terribly tired, sad (I&#39;m not emotionally very well) and without
much motivation to study for my test. I have a reasonbly good grasp
of the theory, but some details of the subject didn&#39;t &quot;sink in&quot; up
till now and I&#39;m not very much optimistic regarding what I can do
until tomorrow. In particular, finding negative cycles efficiently
(i.e., in polynomial time) is still a mystery for me. I have some
intuition of why the O(nm) algorithm works, but I have still to sit
down and write a complete, detailed a proof. I wish I had time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-10-24</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-24/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-24/</link>


	<category>complexity-theory</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-08T12:14:58Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Whew! One of the longest homeworks that I&#39;ve ever had was finished
today. Programmning Turing Machines takes time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-10-16</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-16/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-16/</link>


	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2000 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-08T12:13:34Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;After a lot of time doing this Combinatorial Optimization homework,
I found out that a lot of my colleagues didn&#39;t even bother to prove
that their algorithms worked, while I&#39;ve spent a lot of time
finding algorithm invariants and proving that they were actually
maintained from interation to iteration. This is the Right
Thing(tm) to do, but it also takes a lot of time. What should I do
next time?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-08-31</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-08-31/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-08-31/</link>


	<category>internet</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2000 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-08T12:05:41Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;rant&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
Ugh! Discovered that the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.speedy.com.br&quot;&gt;ADSL service I was planning to sign&lt;/a&gt;
blocks incoming calls to SMTP and HTTP ports -- since I don&#39;t trust
anyone to receive and manage my e-mails, I had a plan of setting up
my own e-mail server. Fsck! If the providers can&#39;t get their
freaking job done The Right Way (tm), why do they prevent their
customers from doing it themselves?? It costs them absolutely
nothing. I mean &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also discovered that I&#39;ll have a class of &quot;Probabilistic Method&quot;
during my birthday and only this class. This means that I&#39;ll have
to endure hours of traffic just to get here to see the class and
then more painful hours to go back home.
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/rant&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2000-08-30</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-08-30/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-08-30/</link>


	<category>life</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2000 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-08T12:04:42Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Humm... I fear that I won&#39;t be able to handle this
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~yoshi/mac5775/&quot;&gt;&quot;Probabilistic Method&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
course at all. I haven&#39;t felt this lost in classes for quite some
time (the last time, as I recall, was when I was just entering the
University). Let&#39;s see what happens as things progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
