<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged emacs</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/emacs/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 15:17:42 -0200</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Problems with Emacs 24.4</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-11-24-emacs_bug/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-11-24-emacs_bug/</link>



	<category>bug</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>git</category>

	<category>github</category>

	<category>mate-desktop</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 15:16:58 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-11-24T17:17:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This is, essentially, a call for help, as I don&#39;t really know which program
is at a fault here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Emacs&#39;s upstream
&lt;a href=&quot;http://permalink.gmane.org/gmane.emacs.devel/176760&quot;&gt;converted their repository from bzr to git&lt;/a&gt;, all the commits in
mirror repositories became &quot;invalid&quot; in relation to the official repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean in practical terms, in my case? Well, bear with me while
I try to report my steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;noticingaregressionandreportingabug&quot;&gt;Noticing a regression and reporting a bug&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a regression with Emacs 24.4 relative to 24.3, which I discovered
after Emacs 24.4 &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.qa.debian.org/e/emacs24/news/20141025T214023Z.html&quot;&gt;became available in Debian&#39;s sid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regression in particular is that Emacs 24.4 doesn&#39;t seem to respect my
Xresources, while 24.3 does (and this is 100% reproducible: I kept the
binary packages of version 24.3 of emacs24 and I can install and reinstall
things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href=&quot;http://debbugs.gnu.org/18902&quot;&gt;reported this to upstream&lt;/a&gt;, I received a reply that it worked fine
with another person that was using XFCE with unstable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;testingvariousdesktopenvironments&quot;&gt;Testing various Desktop environments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I am using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mate-desktop.org/&quot;&gt;MATE desktop environment&lt;/a&gt;, I proceeded to test this
assertion by installing XFCE. Emacs 24.4 read my Xresources. I went ahead
and installed LXDE. It worked again.  I tried once more with GNOME 3, but
&quot;regular&quot; GNOME 3 just crashed. I tried with GNOME 3 Classic and Emacs 24.4
just worked again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;goingdeepintotherabbitshole&quot;&gt;Going deep into the rabbit&#39;s hole&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I got more curious and I tried to see why things worked the way that
they did and given that there was a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emacs-mirror/emacs/&quot;&gt;mirror of the Emacs repo on github&lt;/a&gt;, I cloned it and started
to &lt;code&gt;git bisect&lt;/code&gt; to find the first problematic commit (I have no idea if
&lt;code&gt;bzr&lt;/code&gt; even offers something like &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s &lt;code&gt;bisect&lt;/code&gt; and I wouldn&#39;t really know
how to do it as quickly as I do with &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cut short a long story, after many recompiles, many wasted hours, a lot
of wasted electrical energy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emacs-mirror/emacs/commit/15e14b165dcbc6566a0459b0d5e66f89080f569e&quot;&gt;I found a bad commit&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://debbugs.gnu.org/cgi/bugreport.cgi?bug=18902#14&quot;&gt;reported it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received no response after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thenewrepoentersinaction&quot;&gt;The new repo enters in action&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all my hard work bisecting things was completely invalidated
after the transition to the new repository went live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things relevant again, I used the awesome powers of &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;,
restricting the changes of the newly cloned repository to the e-mail of the
committer in question (Chong Yidong) and, from there, I proceeded to another
painful process of git bisects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, sure enough, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://git.savannah.gnu.org/cgit/emacs.git/commit/?id=aac2b673c3083ab612bcd57fbcd9d370078bd8da&quot;&gt;first bad commit&lt;/a&gt; was the same one that I
found with the previous tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semi-blindly reverting this commit, and also semi-blindly resolving the
conflicts make Emacs&#39;s from master work again on my system, but I highly
suspect that (given the way that I did it), it would not really be
appropriate for upstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But given also that I failed to receive feedback after my original report, I
am not too confident that this bug can be solved soon (even if it doesn&#39;t
qualify for being fixed in Debian 8).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all this, I don&#39;t really know what else to do. I even
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=770781&quot;&gt;filed a bug report&lt;/a&gt; (more like a request for help) to the Debian
MATE maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I would have filed a bug to upstream MATE, but it is not
really clear what the proper procedure to report bugs to them is---they seem
to use github&#39;s issues system, but given that they have separate
repositories for each component of the project, and that I don&#39;t know
precisely what repository to report to (or even if it applies to MATE after
all), I am more or less paralyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;asidenote&quot;&gt;A side note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say that the conversion was well done by Eric Raymond, because the
whole &lt;code&gt;.git&lt;/code&gt; repository of the new repo is only about 200MB, with history
going back to 1985, while the other repository had about 800GB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Changing Some Configuration from Defaults</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/changing-some-configuration-from-defaults/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/changing-some-configuration-from-defaults/</link>



	<category>configuration</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>productivity</category>

	<category>readline</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 20:36:42 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-15T02:20:59Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Two of my most frequently used tools are, hands down, Emacs and bash.
Having a pleasant configuration of one&#39;s toolbox is necessary for long-term
productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, newer versions of the programs (any programs) don&#39;t always have
good, comfortable defaults. That is the case with Emacs 23 and bash 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Emacs 23, by default, the scratch buffer shows some text that, if you
want to quickly enter text to be saved, has to be deleted. This can be
tolerated for some invocations of the editor. But at some point, it gets on
one&#39;s nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, Emacs is so fully customizable that this is not a problem, unless
you have to hunt down the right knobs and you are an e-lisp illiterate. That
is my case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading an admittedly small amount of documentation, some good lines
that ought to be put into one&#39;s &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(setq inhibit-startup-echo-area-message &quot;rbrito&quot;)
(setq initial-scratch-message nil); show an empty scratch buffer
(setq inhibit-startup-message t); remove splash screen
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another line that may make things more comfortable (especially if you, like
me, use Emacs&#39;s dired as a filemanager to navigate your folders):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defalias &#39;yes-or-no-p &#39;y-or-n-p)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But configuring Emacs is not always that hard. Seeing a change of behaviour
with your shell is scarier. When bash 4 was released, one thing that got
implemented is the echo of some characters from the terminal to the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice and with my usage pattern, this meant that whenever I was typing
a command line, changed my mind and pressed &lt;code&gt;C-c&lt;/code&gt;, I got a &lt;code&gt;^C&lt;/code&gt; printed on
the screen, usually overwriting one or two characters of what I had typed.
And this prevented me from automatically copying and pasting the command
that I had typed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for an answer to that was much harder than to see how to change a
parameter on Emacs: every search that I tried on Google with the words
&quot;bash&quot; and &quot;Ctrl-C&quot; or some variants of that eventually lead me to &quot;how do I
trap a Ctrl-C on my shell script?&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decided to see what changed, I read the documentation of readline. It didn&#39;t
help, because I was reading something from version 5. I, then, downloaded
the source code and started looking for &lt;code&gt;SIGINT&lt;/code&gt;. Then, perusing the code
(and the changelog), I saw that with bash 4 and readline 6, a new
configuration option was introduced: the &lt;code&gt;echo-control-characters&lt;/code&gt; option of
readline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, after knowing this, stopping the undesired behaviour was a simple
matter of inserting &lt;code&gt;set echo-control-characters off&lt;/code&gt; in my &lt;code&gt;.inputrc&lt;/code&gt; and
think about how much time I spent with that uncomfortable behaviour in some
of my preferred tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an addendum to the previous paragraphs (written on February of this year,
but only now published), the Debian package of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/NEWS.23.2&quot;&gt;Emacs 23.2&lt;/a&gt;, the newest
version as of this writing, comes with some configuration that makes it
ignore the settings that are used with fontconfig. I did not spend any time
trying to see the cause of the problem, but adding a simple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Emacs*font:         Mono
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to my &lt;code&gt;.Xdefaults&lt;/code&gt; file did the trick and restored back the ability to use
DejaVu Sans Mono at the right size on my system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Migrate from RCS to git</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/migrate-from-rcs-to-git/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/migrate-from-rcs-to-git/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>git</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>revision-control</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 05:39:37 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-03-12T03:53:18Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have been keeping my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; files under version control since I was
introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/&quot;&gt;AUCTeX&lt;/a&gt; and I realized that a good way to approach the
&quot;evolutionary&quot; approach to software (this includes text) is to use a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revision_control&quot;&gt;revision control system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started using that with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; 21 (the first version of Emacs that I
used was Emacs 19.something which I can&#39;t remember) and the revision system
that was most easily available was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/rcs/&quot;&gt;RCS&lt;/a&gt;. Its integration with Emacs
was very good and also easy to use: type &lt;code&gt;C-x v-v&lt;/code&gt; and a check in is
performed (or a check out, depending on the state of the file). You would be
asked for a changelog for that file and that was it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on the other hand, there is a myriad of options and one that looks very
nice to me (apart from not dealing with metadata, but that&#39;s OK with me for
the moment) is Linus Torvald&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The very nice thing with &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;
(or many other such systems) is that the interface with Emacs is exactly the
same: &lt;code&gt;C-x v-v&lt;/code&gt;. That&#39;s the only thing you need to remember to work well
with, say, your text project. (I don&#39;t actually know very much of the
management workflow under Emacs, but I also use the command line a good
amount and it serves me well so far).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how can I convert my RCS &quot;repositories&quot; to a proper &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; repository?
Well, git comes with a subcommand called &lt;code&gt;cvsimport&lt;/code&gt;, meant to be used with
CVS and this does help, since a CVS repository is essentially just a
collection of RCS files. As many people have migrated along the path from
RCS to CVS to Subversion to git, and I did not intend to convert the
repository in multiple steps, I am documenting what I did here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you have the &lt;code&gt;,v&lt;/code&gt; files that RCS generates (the &quot;repository&quot; files
for each file tracked by RCS) spread in a tree and you would like to convert
that tree to a git repository for replication, backup and &quot;time
machine-like&quot; support, you can mimic a basic CVS repository that can be
converted easily with the following simple steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new directory hierarchy somewhere, denoted here by
&lt;code&gt;cvs-source-dir&lt;/code&gt;. This will play the role of a CVS repository which &lt;code&gt;git
cvsimport&lt;/code&gt; will convert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under &lt;code&gt;cvs-source-dir&lt;/code&gt;, create the directory tree as you would like it to
be visible by &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an immediate subdirectory of &lt;code&gt;cvs-source-dir&lt;/code&gt;, create a directory named
&lt;code&gt;CVSROOT&lt;/code&gt;, that is &lt;code&gt;cvs-source-dir/CVSROOT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each immediate subdirectory of &lt;code&gt;cvs-source-dir&lt;/code&gt; will play the role of a
CVS module. Just think of that as a project under control of the version
control system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about the &lt;code&gt;,v&lt;/code&gt; files as your regular files and put them under the
&lt;code&gt;cvs-source-dir&lt;/code&gt; tree, as you would like them to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the directory where your git repository will reside, denoted here
by &lt;code&gt;git-repo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;git cvsimport -v -a -A -k -m -d cvs-source-dir -C git-repo cvs-module&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it. It seems to perform a very good job of changing a very old system
to something that is modern and with many features (and is distributed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also want to read about the way to convert the ids of commits that
RCS/CVS register to proper (people) names, which git uses. Read the
&lt;code&gt;git-cvsimport&lt;/code&gt; manpage for more details on this and other options mentioned
above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-11-20</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-20/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-20/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>free-software</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:09:53Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; impressed with the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/emacs-snapshot-gtk&quot;&gt;recent improvements&lt;/a&gt;
in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emacswiki.org/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;
that I am sincerely considering using it as my &quot;default operating
system&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people say that joking, but the new features along with a more
user-friendly, really make that an interesting option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use, by the way, the following extra packages from
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rbrito@dumont:~&amp;#036; COLUMNS=88 dpkg -l | grep -- -el
ii  debian-el        26.3-1           Emacs helpers specific to Debian users
ii  emacs-goodies-el 26.3-1           Miscellaneous add-ons for Emacs
ii  gettext-el       0.14.5-2         Emacs po-mode for editing .po files
ii  post-el          2004.07.23-2     emacs major mode for editing mail
rbrito@dumont:~&amp;#036;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-04-10</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-04-10/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-04-10/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>tex</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2004 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-24T06:53:04Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;The more I use the combo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emacswiki.org/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;, the more I like them. It is
amazing how much complexity they have below their surface and how
much they can accomplish. Unfortunately, I still don&#39;t know enough
to call myself neither a LaTeX literate nor a Emacs literate, but I
sure hope to fill the holes in my education soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One package that I recently discovered for Emacs is
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ecb.sf.net/&quot;&gt;ECB&lt;/a&gt;, which provides many of the features
found in other development programs, like Microsoft&#39;s Visual
Studio. And the included speedbar (and the newer speedbar-beta,
already included in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/sarge/&quot;&gt;sarge&lt;/a&gt; is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also amazing are the packages
&lt;a href=&quot;http://preview-latex.sf.net/&quot;&gt;preview-latex&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/&quot;&gt;AUCTeX&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://zon.astro.uva.nl/~dominik/Tools/reftex/&quot;&gt;RefTeX&lt;/a&gt;. They all
make life with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tug.org/&quot;&gt;TeX&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emacswiki.org/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-03-19</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-19/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-03-19/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>emacs</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-09-22T21:41:34Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Discovered the amazing
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mirrors.sunsite.dk/auctex/www/auctex/&quot;&gt;AUCTeX&lt;/a&gt;. I just
can&#39;t get enough of it and I&#39;m looking everywhere to find things
that I can typeset with LaTeX, just to use AUCTeX. I don&#39;t know how
I have lived without it this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote a bit more of my Master&#39;s thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
