<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged debian-planet</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian-planet/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian-planet/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/debian-planet/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2013-06-05T08:25:51Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Some experiences with ZFS</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/some_experiences_with_zfs/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/some_experiences_with_zfs/"/>






	<category term="compression" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="debian-planet" />

	<category term="deduplication" />

	<category term="filesystems" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="zfs" />


	<updated>2012-09-09T02:48:33Z</updated>
	<published>2012-09-09T02:42:24Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Continuing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/117659222649141007981/posts/T3BcxA7wKjK&quot;&gt;ZFS evaluation journey&lt;/a&gt; (which I will summarize here with
the things that I learned), I was able to fit about 2.5TB of data on a
single 2TB drive, with deduplication enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, even &lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt; files around in ZFS (which you would think
would be a cheap operation) takes ages. Removing files also takes ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; unloaded Phenom II X4 910 system running Linux 3.5.2
(actually, from Debian&#39;s experimental), and zfsonlinux version
0.6.0.71-0ubuntu1~precise1 (recompiled from source to work with my Debian
system), I tried to remove a subdirectory that had about 4000
files. According to time, it took:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;real    42m51.487s
user    0m0.188s
sys     0m16.769s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is a bit too slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just (read: &quot;yesterday&quot;) upgraded this machine from 4GB to 6GB of RAM
(well, I would have updated it to 8GB of RAM as that is what I ordered, but
it one of the RAM chips arrived dead here and I simply took one of the new
4GB card and one of the older 2GB card).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, honestly, I don&#39;t see change in upgrading the RAM from 4GB to 6GB and,
unless something magic happens with 2GB more, I wouldn&#39;t expect a whole
different story with 8GB of RAM. Oh, no swap is being used (well, it is an
unloaded machine after all), and the Linux kernel swappiness knob is at its
default of 60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; see, though, is that even for a single file removal, the disk is
thrashing a lot. I mean &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; crazy and that is, of course, the prime
suspect of the bad performance (of course, of course). So, there must be
some really crazy metadata churning going on here and I guess that the
people from the LLNL would like to know of their modules producing this
behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep tuned for some future impressions.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>NOT Trying out AdSense</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense_not/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense_not/"/>






	<category term="adsense" />

	<category term="advertisements" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="debian-planet" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="funding" />

	<category term="google" />


	<updated>2013-06-05T08:25:51Z</updated>
	<published>2012-09-07T16:16:18Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;On the 3rd of September, I applied to Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; program, as I
told in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog/posts/trying_out_adsense/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that was a short-lived experience. On the 5th of September, I received
the following e-mail, which, sincerely, is as uninformative as it could get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Date: Wed, 05 Sep 2012 16:52:22 -0000
From: adsense-noreply@google.com
To: rbrito@gmail.com
Subject: Google AdSense Support

Hello,

As mentioned in our welcome email, we conduct a second review of your
AdSense application once AdSense code is placed on your site(s). As a
result of this review, we have disapproved your account for the following
violation(s):

Issues:

- Site does not comply with Google policies


---------------------

Further detail:


Site does not comply with Google policies: We&#39;re unable to approve your
AdSense application at this time because we feel that your site does not
comply with Google AdSense policies or webmaster quality guidelines. It&#39;s
our goal to provide our advertisers sites that offer rich and meaningful
content, receive organic traffic, and allow us to serve well-targeted ads
to users. We believe that currently your site does not fulfill this
criteria. 

For more details, please read the webmaster quality guidelines at
http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=35769 and
the AdSense program policies at
http://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?answer=48182,
https://support.google.com/adsense/bin/topic.py?topic=1271507

(...)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I went on and read &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the documentation on program policies
etc.  I investigate each point here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invalid clicks and impressions: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouraging clicks: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content guidelines: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copyrighted material: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmaster guidelines: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic sources: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad behavior: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad placement: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site behavior: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive ads and services: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google advertising cookies: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, I RTFM and did everything correctly. So, dear
lazyweb, what would my options be to fund a tiny bit of my software
contributions?&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Trying out AdSense</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/"/>






	<category term="adsense" />

	<category term="advertisements" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="debian-planet" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="funding" />


	<updated>2012-09-03T23:16:51Z</updated>
	<published>2012-09-03T23:12:42Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I have been having quite costly experiments with &lt;a href=&quot;http://buffalo.nas-central.org/wiki/LS_Hardware_and_Software_information&quot;&gt;(embeded) hardware&lt;/a&gt; in
the last few weeks/months. To cover at least part of the expenses, I am
trying out to use Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; with my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on blogging more frequently with the results of the experiments, but
it will take me a few days, as I want to offer people only the &quot;meat&quot; of
what I actually did, pointing out some pitfalls that made me waste a lot of
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to AdSense, one interesting thing about trying it is that I
applied to be part of the program for 3 or 4 times late in August and, due
to unspecified reasons, my application was rejected for &quot;not complying with
their policies&quot;.  I read the policies from left to side, from up and down
and nowhere I saw anything that my blog infringed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I tried once again and I&#39;m now in a sort of &quot;probation period&quot;
for AdSense, which is progress I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I only put one advertisement at the top of my pages, but I am
curious to know how &quot;targeted&quot; those ads would be to a blog that has
articles that were written more than a decade ago, with posts in at least
two languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that this is a weaker version of what &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaelhertzog.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël Hertzog&lt;/a&gt; is trying
to do with his funding campaigns, except that I only expect to cover the
costs of my hardware (even if I am skeptical that I will actually manage to
reach that point of self-sufficiency).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
