<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged handbrake</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/handbrake/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/handbrake/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 01:58:09 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>I am not going to DebConf 12</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</link>



	<category>debconf</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>fonts</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>handbrake</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 01:59:42 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-06-07T04:58:09Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Due to some real life impediments (including a beautiful one with just over
2 months of life called Daniel), I will not be able to go to this year&#39;s
DebConf, even though it seems that this DebConf will exceed many
expectations with the support that the governement of Nicaragua just
offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thingsthatiwouldliketohaveworkedon&quot;&gt;Things that I would like to have worked on&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this means that I will not be working with some fellows that
may be there, like people from the &lt;code&gt;pkg-multimedia&lt;/code&gt; team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, as I am working on some packages that are not that well
suited to distributions (especially regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://handbrake.fr/&quot;&gt;HandBrake&lt;/a&gt;), it would be
highly productive to have a hacking session or two with other people
interested in having this popular and easy-to-use video ripper/transcoder on
Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to be able to talk in person with other people (including
&lt;a href=&quot;http://joeyh.name/blog/&quot;&gt;Joey Hess&lt;/a&gt;) about controversial packaging of some programs, like GNU
Parallel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/parallel&quot;&gt;which I maintain in Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things else that I would love to work on, besides helping a
bit with some of the still pending transitions of the the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;, meeting friends and other social
stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, well. I guess that working at home will be the solution for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
