<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged meego</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/meego/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/meego/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 15:31:46 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Installing Meego on the N900</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/installing_meego_on_the_n900/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/installing_meego_on_the_n900/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>meego</category>

	<category>n900</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 03:55:50 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-02-24T18:31:46Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;My last cellphone was a dumb phone. I seem to remember that it was called
something like Samsung Voicer. It didn&#39;t have those hip things like SIM
cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK. Fast forward to December of 2010, and after a long hiatus, I decided to
get a new phone.  It was this shiny Nokia N900. The biggest thing that made
me want this one was that some people at DebConf 10 were praising it for
having a Debian-like distribution in it, and that it worked very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw that Phil Hands was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://gallery.debconf.org/v/debconf10/album/album_004/41-20100801T020944.JPG.html&quot;&gt;enthusiastically talking about the bargain of getting one in New York&lt;/a&gt;
and that it would have cost him many pounds in the UK and, so, he was happy
with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otávio Salvador also got one in NY and during
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tiagovaz/4870648124/in/set-72157624676953084&quot;&gt;one of the nights of that DebConf&lt;/a&gt; with him, Tiago Vaz, Daniel Baumann,
and Chris Lamb, I asked him to call my parents here in Brazil and he let me
use his N900. I had more time with it and played a little bit with the
command line, opened the stock media player and played a beautiful trailer
of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/9_%282009_film%29&quot;&gt;9 (2009 film)&lt;/a&gt;, leaving me a very good impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought one, and, indeed, it is a very good machine that can even make
phone calls. The ability to run Linux on it (even if it contains some
non-free pieces of software) was decisive in me getting it.  It runs this
distribution called &lt;a href=&quot;http://maemo.org/&quot;&gt;Maemo 5&lt;/a&gt; which is loosely based on Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, Maemo is not the &quot;cool thing&quot; to run, regarding Linux on these
portable devices. &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.meego.com/ARM/N900&quot;&gt;Meego&lt;/a&gt; is. But with the advent of many Internet forums
has brought many people writing some long, convoluted howto documents for
things that would be better done as, say, providing a script or, better yet,
preparing a package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of getting Meego running on the N900, only three things are
required:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;uboot-pr13&lt;/code&gt; while in Maemo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uncompress the &lt;a href=&quot;http://repository.maemo.org/meego/n900-de/archive/1.2.0.90.6.20110630.4.DE.2011-07-01.1/images/mg-handset-armv7nhl-n900-ce-stable/&quot;&gt;MeeGo 1.2 Community Edition for Nokia N900&lt;/a&gt; image to a
µSD card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn the phone off, plug in the µSD card, and &lt;strong&gt;PUT THE BACK COVER&lt;/strong&gt; on
the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last bit of the third step is crucial, as, otherwise, the SD card won&#39;t
be detected and you will get kernel panics with the device trying to mount
the root filesystem from a device that is not there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, the official documentation tells us one should uncompress the
available pre-made images and write them with &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; to the device. In my
experience, it is completely unnecessary to use it and, in fact, it is so 6
times slower than using a simple shell redirection. That is, instead of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bzip2 -d &amp;lt; mg-handset-armv7nhl-n900-whateverwhatever-mmcblk0p.raw.bz2 | dd bs=4096 of=/dev/mmcblk0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can get better results with the simpler:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bzip2 -d &amp;lt; mg-handset-armv7nhl-n900-whateverwhatever-mmcblk0p.raw.bz2 &amp;gt; /dev/mmcblk0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually used &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/lbzip2&quot;&gt;lbzip2&lt;/a&gt; instead of bzip2, but that shouldn&#39;t matter. The use
of the small block size for the &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; command is probably the culprit, but I
don&#39;t see the need to write the uncompressed data in chunks this small. If
there is a problem, I would love to be informed of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As trying it with &lt;code&gt;uboot&lt;/code&gt; and a µSD card doesn&#39;t mess with your &quot;safe&quot; Maemo
installation, this is a good way to play with the successor of Maemo.
Perhaps, if we give good feedback to the project, we can influence the
direction that it is taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will surely be nice to learn about this new &quot;consumer-oriented&quot;
distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
