<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>Working with CVS via Git</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/working_with_cvs_via_git/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/working_with_cvs_via_git/</link>


	<category>cvs</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>git</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>lame</category>

	<category>revision-control</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 04:49:56 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-11T07:57:38Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;The easiest way of using git locally to commit to a CVS repository is to
have &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; a git clone of the CVS repository &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a CVS checkout of your
repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Initial steps that Work for Me (TM)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create your git clone of the CVS repository:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; git cvsimport -v -a -A /tmp/lame-authors.txt -k -m -d \
     :ext:rbrito@lame.cvs.sourceforge.net:/cvsroot/lame lame&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt; The command above will create your clone of the CVS repository in the
 current directory which we suppose, for the sake of this discussion, is
 &lt;code&gt;/tmp/gitified&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; If want to specify a directory different than what you&#39;re in, then you
 should add the option &lt;code&gt;-C /path/to/git/repository&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a checkout of the CVS repository for CVS work stuff (I&#39;m checking
out things under &lt;code&gt;/tmp&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  cvs -z3 -d:ext:rbrito@lame.cvs.sourceforge.net:/cvsroot/lame checkout lame&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create your CVS checkout on the directory &lt;code&gt;/tmp/lame&lt;/code&gt;, assuming
that you are working under &lt;code&gt;/tmp&lt;/code&gt;, as I do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Doing real work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to your git clone (&lt;code&gt;/tmp/gitified&lt;/code&gt;) and start hacking, committing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it is time to send your patches to the CVS repo, you have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; export GIT_DIR=/tmp/gitified/.git
 cd /tmp/lame
 git cherry origin master | sed -n &#39;s/^+ //p&#39; | xargs -l1 git cvsexportcommit -c -p -v&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;  This will automatically check in all the commits that you have made in
  step 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Continuing your work afterwards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, discard your commits in your git repository, so that you don&#39;t get
further problems with &lt;code&gt;git cvsimport&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update your git repository with the current contents of the CVS repo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; cd /tmp/gitified
 git cvsimport -v -a -A /tmp/lame-authors.txt -k -m -d \
     :ext:rbrito@lame.cvs.sourceforge.net:/cvsroot/lame lame&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update your CVS repository with the current contents of the CVS repo too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; cd /tmp/lame
 cvs update&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I would prefer a simpler, leaner workflow. If you happen to have
one, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Lack of cooperation from Ubuntu?</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/lack_of_cooperation_from_ubuntu/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/lack_of_cooperation_from_ubuntu/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>kfreebsd</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 22:46:26 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-05T08:25:20Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/117659222649141007981/posts/C2vY4nD4CD6&quot;&gt;posted the following on Google+&lt;/a&gt;, but it is important enough to be
reproduced on Planet. I&#39;m editing it a bit, as it is a followup to my
previous post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog/posts/debian_activities/&quot;&gt;improving the packaging of MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;, there was one thing that
caught my attention: that Ubuntu
&lt;a href=&quot;http://changelogs.ubuntu.com/changelogs/pool/universe/m/mongodb/mongodb_2.0.4-1ubuntu2.1/changelog&quot;&gt;had already done some of the embedded/convenience libraries work&lt;/a&gt;, but
they had &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; pushed that work to Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, discovered this only after I started working on the improvements
of the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What gives, Ubuntu people?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I saw is that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/mongodb/1:2.2.4-0ubuntu1/+build/4470136&quot;&gt;they have patches enabling mongodb working on armhf&lt;/a&gt;. Again, they did
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; push those to Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why this lack of cooperation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I saw is that they had packages for version 2.2 (more
precisely, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.ubuntu.com/raring/mongodb&quot;&gt;raring has 1:2.2.4-0ubuntu1&lt;/a&gt;), while Debian sid
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/changelogs/pool/main/m/mongodb/mongodb_2.4.1-2/changelog.html&quot;&gt;just had 2.0&lt;/a&gt; until very recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why not push this work and avoid duplication of work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By being a good downstream, I intend to push some of the patches to MongoDB
upstream (if they want it), so that we (Debian) have a smaller delta. This
will benefit you Ubuntu guys. Why not join forces and help have a
world-class set of packages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, be good netizens and share the work that you have.  I firmly believe
that the armhf people will be happy to have one of the fancy &quot;cloud&quot;
software available on ARM, especially since the prospects of having ARM
machines on datacenters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, just for the record, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/mongo-debian/pull/2&quot;&gt;kFreeBSD people have sent their contribution&lt;/a&gt; and I would love to see
(if possible) this running on the HURD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Some recent Debian activities</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/debian_activities/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/debian_activities/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>linux</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 04:29:23 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-30T17:15:33Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have been occasionally working on some Debian-related tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Chrony&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those was to get chrony is a slightly better shape, by using, at
least, a patch system (indeed, I &quot;modernized&quot; its packaging with the format
&quot;3.0 (quilt)&quot;), put it in &lt;a href=&quot;http://anonscm.debian.org/gitweb/?p=users/rbrito-guest/chrony.git&quot;&gt;a git repository&lt;/a&gt; and would like to receive some
comments on what I have so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bug &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/694690&quot;&gt;Debian bug #694690&lt;/a&gt; contains a very brief description of my
intentions and of the problems that I see in the current package. IMVHO, it
is a very nice NTP client and server and it could even be used as the
default for Debian, once it gets in shape.  There is at least another
high-profile distribution, namely Fedora, that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Features/ChronyDefaultNTP&quot;&gt;switched to chrony as its default NTP software&lt;/a&gt;. We can certainly take a
look at what they are doing and join forces here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;MongoDB&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another package where I spent some time was with &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.qa.debian.org/mongodb&quot;&gt;mongodb&lt;/a&gt;:
MongoDB is a tricky package that is only built for 2 arches: amd64 and
i386.  The version in unstable for i386 was 2.0.x (roughly the same as for
wheezy), which the version in unstable for amd64 was 2.4.1, which has many
features that 2.0 lacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The packaging of it is a bit tricky, since the source tree has bazillion
embedded/convenience libraries (e.g., Google&#39;s v8, Mozilla&#39;s spidermonkey,
BOOST, Google&#39;s Snappy, PCRE 3 etc.). Up to version 2.4.1-2, it used all
these convenience copies, which is of course, a problem for a distribution
like Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.qa.debian.org/m/mongodb/news/20130417T171917Z.html&quot;&gt;I changed&lt;/a&gt; part of the build process to use the libraries that we
already have in Debian and, as Antonin Kral uploaded this newer version,
unsurprisingly the binary packages are smaller (especially if you take into
account that a handful of the libraries may already be installed on the
system).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few hours later, Antonin uploaded a new upstream version, which means that
we now have better MongoDB packages to play with.  I am, in fact, really
playing with MongoDB as my first NoSQL database, since
&lt;a href=&quot;https://education.10gen.com/courses/10gen/M101/2012_Fall/about&quot;&gt;10gen is giving an introductory course&lt;/a&gt; on how it works and my
motivation was to get what we have in Debian in shape for the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can say that I am a firm believer of the &quot;eat your own dogfood&quot;
principle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding MongoDB only being built for i386 and amd64, the BTS
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/703061&quot;&gt;has a patch&lt;/a&gt; to enable building for kFreeBSD, but the patch is for the
2.0 series and the code has changed so drastically in relation to the 2.4
series that there is no hope of it applying.  It would be super nice to have
MongoDB working on kFreeBSD and on HURD also, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;nocache&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a very nice command line program called &lt;code&gt;nocache&lt;/code&gt; that was packaged
by Dmitry Smirnov (and just approved by the FTP masters!) whose packaging I
briefly reviewed per Dmitry&#39;s request and this is an amazing utility whose
purpose is to bypass/minimize file system caching for a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially useful when you are making backups (reading lots of files
that would, otherwise, fill the filesystem cache, even if they are not used
frequently) or if you are just streaming one file (possibly larger than the
system&#39;s RAM) to another computer and you have no need to use the file
immediately after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It performs its job by using the &lt;code&gt;LD_PRELOAD&lt;/code&gt; mechanism and using
&lt;code&gt;posix_fadvise&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s flag &lt;code&gt;POSIX_FADV_DONTNEED&lt;/code&gt; for the files that will be
touched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Post note&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, just one aside: for the readers of Debian Planet and other aggregation
services which are not Debian Developers/Maintainers, I contributed to these
packages without being the maintainer of them, just scratching some itches
and contributing back what I produced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Looking for (Free) a Video Editor</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/dear_lazyweb_what_is_a_good_free_video_editor/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/dear_lazyweb_what_is_a_good_free_video_editor/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>lazyweb</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 22:16:07 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-01-30T00:16:17Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s suppose that you went to a show of your favourite some time ago and
you were able to sneak in a camera (well, in those times, cell phones
weren&#39;t able to record much more than 176x144 pixels at 12fps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, then, you suddenly found that some people uploaded (short) fragments of
that very same show to youtube and, collecting those, you may be able to
create a &quot;multi-camera&quot; version of the video that you can record to keep of
your memorable concert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The multi-camera, in the sense above, is not the same as
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DVD-Video#Chapters_and_angles&quot;&gt;multiple angles&lt;/a&gt; (like some DVDs), but something like a TV broadcast,
where the stage is filmed by cameras positioned at some places and the image
that is broadcast is switched from time to time according to that who is
singing, or playing etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Dear Lazyweb, do we happen to have any Free Software (preferably already
packaged in Debian) that is able to help with the task of &quot;aligning&quot; (in
time) videos from various (different) sources so as to produce one
multi-camera video?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would my options be? I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e7IPeuK1tQ&amp;amp;lc=Zwz7xq5ANT43j64jh8zLRYCMVRnJQgINcgSOhf-5Ozg&quot;&gt;asked this&lt;/a&gt; on youtube for a person that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e7IPeuK1tQ&quot;&gt;did exactly what I want&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0e7IPeuK1tQ&amp;amp;lc=Zwz7xq5ANT6jkGhCF9g1RzmZAsFIGmYzChDJwqwovNc&quot;&gt;their answer&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sony_Vegas_Pro&quot;&gt;Sony Vegas&lt;/a&gt;,
which I fear that does not exactly would be allowed in Debian. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any comments are welcome, thanks, and if I am successful, I will upload the
final video. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Another meme: The Geek test</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/another_meme_the_geektest/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/another_meme_the_geektest/</link>


	<category>meme</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 02:32:23 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-11-01T04:39:22Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I was with some spare time a few days ago and I took one of those stupid
tests that are so popular in the Internet. Well, here are the results,
saying that I am, indeed, a Geek, which does not surprise me that much. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nerdtests.com/ft_nt2.php&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nerdtests.com/images/badge/nt2/df3f970a39bfebc3.png&quot; alt=&quot;NerdTests.com says I&#39;m a Cool Nerd King.  Click here to take the Nerd Test, get geeky images and jokes, and write on the nerd forum!&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did expect my Math score to be higher than everything else (I&#39;m only in
the 90th percentile with respect to this), while I am high on the Computer
side of things (in the 97th percentile).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that I should devote myself to more Mathematics and writing less
code. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Some experiences with ZFS</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/some_experiences_with_zfs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/some_experiences_with_zfs/</link>


	<category>compression</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>debian-planet</category>

	<category>deduplication</category>

	<category>filesystems</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>zfs</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 23:42:24 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-09T02:48:33Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/117659222649141007981/posts/T3BcxA7wKjK&quot;&gt;ZFS evaluation journey&lt;/a&gt; (which I will summarize here with
the things that I learned), I was able to fit about 2.5TB of data on a
single 2TB drive, with deduplication enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, even &lt;em&gt;moving&lt;/em&gt; files around in ZFS (which you would think
would be a cheap operation) takes ages. Removing files also takes ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;em&gt;completely&lt;/em&gt; unloaded Phenom II X4 910 system running Linux 3.5.2
(actually, from Debian&#39;s experimental), and zfsonlinux version
0.6.0.71-0ubuntu1~precise1 (recompiled from source to work with my Debian
system), I tried to remove a subdirectory that had about 4000
files. According to time, it took:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;real    42m51.487s
user    0m0.188s
sys     0m16.769s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is a bit too slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just (read: &quot;yesterday&quot;) upgraded this machine from 4GB to 6GB of RAM
(well, I would have updated it to 8GB of RAM as that is what I ordered, but
it one of the RAM chips arrived dead here and I simply took one of the new
4GB card and one of the older 2GB card).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, honestly, I don&#39;t see change in upgrading the RAM from 4GB to 6GB and,
unless something magic happens with 2GB more, I wouldn&#39;t expect a whole
different story with 8GB of RAM. Oh, no swap is being used (well, it is an
unloaded machine after all), and the Linux kernel swappiness knob is at its
default of 60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; see, though, is that even for a single file removal, the disk is
thrashing a lot. I mean &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; crazy and that is, of course, the prime
suspect of the bad performance (of course, of course). So, there must be
some really crazy metadata churning going on here and I guess that the
people from the LLNL would like to know of their modules producing this
behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep tuned for some future impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>NOT Trying out AdSense</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense_not/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense_not/</link>


	<category>adsense</category>

	<category>advertisements</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>debian-planet</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>funding</category>

	<category>google</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 13:16:18 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-05T08:24:59Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;On the 3rd of September, I applied to Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; program, as I
told in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog/posts/trying_out_adsense/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that was a short-lived experience. On the 5th of September, I received
the following e-mail, which, sincerely, is as uninformative as it could get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Date: Wed, 05 Sep 2012 16:52:22 -0000
From: adsense-noreply@google.com
To: rbrito@gmail.com
Subject: Google AdSense Support

Hello,

As mentioned in our welcome email, we conduct a second review of your
AdSense application once AdSense code is placed on your site(s). As a
result of this review, we have disapproved your account for the following
violation(s):

Issues:

- Site does not comply with Google policies


---------------------

Further detail:


Site does not comply with Google policies: We&#39;re unable to approve your
AdSense application at this time because we feel that your site does not
comply with Google AdSense policies or webmaster quality guidelines. It&#39;s
our goal to provide our advertisers sites that offer rich and meaningful
content, receive organic traffic, and allow us to serve well-targeted ads
to users. We believe that currently your site does not fulfill this
criteria. 

For more details, please read the webmaster quality guidelines at
http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=35769 and
the AdSense program policies at
http://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?answer=48182,
https://support.google.com/adsense/bin/topic.py?topic=1271507

(...)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I went on and read &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the documentation on program policies
etc.  I investigate each point here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invalid clicks and impressions: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encouraging clicks: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content guidelines: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copyrighted material: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmaster guidelines: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic sources: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad behavior: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad placement: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site behavior: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive ads and services: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google advertising cookies: No violation here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, I RTFM and did everything correctly. So, dear
lazyweb, what would my options be to fund a tiny bit of my software
contributions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Trying out AdSense</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/trying_out_adsense/</link>


	<category>adsense</category>

	<category>advertisements</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>debian-planet</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>funding</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 20:12:42 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-03T23:16:51Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have been having quite costly experiments with &lt;a href=&quot;http://buffalo.nas-central.org/wiki/LS_Hardware_and_Software_information&quot;&gt;(embeded) hardware&lt;/a&gt; in
the last few weeks/months. To cover at least part of the expenses, I am
trying out to use Google&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/adsense&quot;&gt;AdSense&lt;/a&gt; with my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on blogging more frequently with the results of the experiments, but
it will take me a few days, as I want to offer people only the &quot;meat&quot; of
what I actually did, pointing out some pitfalls that made me waste a lot of
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to AdSense, one interesting thing about trying it is that I
applied to be part of the program for 3 or 4 times late in August and, due
to unspecified reasons, my application was rejected for &quot;not complying with
their policies&quot;.  I read the policies from left to side, from up and down
and nowhere I saw anything that my blog infringed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, I tried once again and I&#39;m now in a sort of &quot;probation period&quot;
for AdSense, which is progress I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I only put one advertisement at the top of my pages, but I am
curious to know how &quot;targeted&quot; those ads would be to a blog that has
articles that were written more than a decade ago, with posts in at least
two languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that this is a weaker version of what &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaelhertzog.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël Hertzog&lt;/a&gt; is trying
to do with his funding campaigns, except that I only expect to cover the
costs of my hardware (even if I am skeptical that I will actually manage to
reach that point of self-sufficiency).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>American accent meme</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/american_accent_meme/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/american_accent_meme/</link>


	<category>meme</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:04:57 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-08-27T03:18:10Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the result of an old meme, but it is still quite interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&quot;width: 320px; border: 1px solid gray; font: normal 12px sans-serif; background-color: white;&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;background: white; color: black; padding: 5px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;b style=&quot;font: bold 20px serif; display: block; margin-bottom: 8px;&quot;&gt;
What American accent do you have?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 4px;&quot;&gt;
Your Result: &lt;b&gt;The Northeast&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 200px; background: white; border: 1px solid black;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 66%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 10px; border: none; background: white; color: black;&quot;&gt;
Judging by how you talk you are probably from north Jersey, New York City, Connecticut or Rhode Island.  Chances are, if you are from New York City (and not those other places) people would probably be able to tell if they actually heard you speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 66%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;Boston&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 62%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;The Inland North&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 52%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;North Central&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 50%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;The South&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 38%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;The West&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 36%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;color: black; background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;The Midland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;background: white; padding: 3px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; background: white; border: 1px solid black; margin-top: 4px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 30%; background: red; font-size: 8px; line-height: 8px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center; padding: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gotoquiz.com/what_american_accent_do_you_have&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;What American accent do you have?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gotoquiz.com/&quot;&gt;Quiz Created on GoToQuiz&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;



</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>I am not going to DebConf 12</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/i-am-not-going-to-debconf-12/</link>


	<category>debconf</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>fonts</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>handbrake</category>

	<category>multimedia</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 01:59:42 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-06-07T04:58:09Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Due to some real life impediments (including a beautiful one with just over
2 months of life called Daniel), I will not be able to go to this year&#39;s
DebConf, even though it seems that this DebConf will exceed many
expectations with the support that the governement of Nicaragua just
offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Things that I would like to have worked on&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this means that I will not be working with some fellows that
may be there, like people from the &lt;code&gt;pkg-multimedia&lt;/code&gt; team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, as I am working on some packages that are not that well
suited to distributions (especially regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://handbrake.fr/&quot;&gt;HandBrake&lt;/a&gt;), it would be
highly productive to have a hacking session or two with other people
interested in having this popular and easy-to-use video ripper/transcoder on
Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to be able to talk in person with other people (including
&lt;a href=&quot;http://joeyh.name/blog/&quot;&gt;Joey Hess&lt;/a&gt;) about controversial packaging of some programs, like GNU
Parallel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/parallel&quot;&gt;which I maintain in Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things else that I would love to work on, besides helping a
bit with some of the still pending transitions of the the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;, meeting friends and other social
stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, well. I guess that working at home will be the solution for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
