<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged study</title>
<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/study/"/>
<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/study/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/study/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2013-04-18T21:08:06Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>2005-11-19</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2005-11-19/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2005-11-19/"/>






	<category term="books" />

	<category term="lisp" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T21:08:06Z</updated>
	<published>2005-11-19T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Purchased some books at discount prices. Nice. Now I can learn
Lisp. Let&#39;s see how I like this new thing of macros &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-01-31</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2001-01-31/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2001-01-31/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T21:04:51Z</updated>
	<published>2001-01-31T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Happy New Millennium! So many things have happened since the last
time I&#39;ve updated my diary and I guess that since I can&#39;t summarize
everything accurately, I&#39;ll just list what I think are the
remarkable facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have now put my new computer (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amd.com&quot;&gt;Duron&lt;/a&gt;
600MHz with a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asus.com&quot;&gt;Asus&lt;/a&gt; A7V motherboard)
to actual use. Of course, I made a backup of my older computer, so
that I was prepared for worst (read on);
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;Linux 2.4.0&lt;/a&gt; has finally been released and
it includes a lot of new goodies. While I think that it is still
not the right time to switch to the new version, it is indeed quite
tempting (but I&#39;ll resist that temptation, since I&#39;ve read a lot of
people complaining of data corruption with the new IDE drivers when
used with VIA chipsets -- and my motherboard features, guess what,
a VIA chipset, of course).
At the time of this writing (Feb 4th), Linux 2.4.1 was already
released, with many minor fixes;
A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing&quot;&gt;new version&lt;/a&gt; of the
Linux Distribution that I use,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org&quot;&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt; is now getting more and
more functionality. It is ready for the new Linux 2.4.0 kernel, but
still under development (read: prone to break). Oh, why can&#39;t new
software be stable? In the mean time, I&#39;m using Debian&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/potato&quot;&gt;potato&lt;/a&gt;.
One week after I have started to use my new computer, my 40GB
Samsung drive broke. Ouch. Fortunately, I had taken backups of
everything from my old computer and any new data that I had on my
new computer was still readable. So, now, I&#39;m using a new 30GB
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quantum.com&quot;&gt;Quantum&lt;/a&gt; drive and everything seems to be
working fine again. Nice.
I am now reading more and more things about my Mastership work. It
will be in a sub-area of computer science called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/study/../compbio/index.html&quot;&gt;Computational (Molecular) Biology&lt;/a&gt;. In
particular, I&#39;m studying now alignments of multiple sequences. The
theory is quite general and applies to alignments of sequences over
any alphabets, but the biological motivation is to study and
compare (sub)sequences of DNA and of proteins;
I must confess that while I was reading slowly in the beginning,
without much motivation, now I&#39;m quite excited about the subject.
It has really grown on me and now I see how much I still have to
catch up to read bleading edge papers (it is also surprising that
this area of knowledge has evolved so much in so little time, but I
guess that this is natural whenever there are economic interests in
a given field). Now, I want to learn more!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-12-05</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-05/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-12-05/"/>






	<category term="complexity-theory" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T21:01:13Z</updated>
	<published>2000-12-05T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;The last day of classes of Computational Complexity. I&#39;m both happy
and sad. I&#39;m happy because it was quite demanding, with loads of
homework. But on the other hand, the subject is so cool and I&#39;ll
certainly miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to buy Papadimitrou&#39;s book &quot;Computational Complexity&quot;, but I
must be sincere here and say that I&#39;m quite scared of the sheer
amount of typos and small errors that this book contains. Indeed if
you ignore those errors, then the book is really good. I guess that
it needs a beta-testing phase as it is feature complete.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-10-30</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-30/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-30/"/>






	<category term="music" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:55:02Z</updated>
	<published>2000-10-30T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t have any classes today and it was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to see what to do with my huge amount of MP3 files.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-10-26</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-26/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-26/"/>






	<category term="complexity-theory" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:54:03Z</updated>
	<published>2000-10-26T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I had the &quot;midterm&quot; today. I thought that while the subjects
covered were well chosen, it was not very well planned regarding
time. I mean, only 1h40min for all those proofs? A comfortable
period would be, say, 3h or 4h, but, then, maybe I&#39;m a
perfectionist. Maybe I&#39;m slow. Maybe both.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-10-25</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-25/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-25/"/>






	<category term="complexity-theory" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:53:36Z</updated>
	<published>2000-10-25T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&#39;ll have the &quot;midterm&quot; of Combinatorial Optimization.
It&#39;s not exactly a midterm, since it is considerably skewed towards
the end of the semester and I&#39;ll have 3 other tests until the
course is finished, but I guess that having this many tests is
actually better than having only two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m terribly tired, sad (I&#39;m not emotionally very well) and without
much motivation to study for my test. I have a reasonbly good grasp
of the theory, but some details of the subject didn&#39;t &quot;sink in&quot; up
till now and I&#39;m not very much optimistic regarding what I can do
until tomorrow. In particular, finding negative cycles efficiently
(i.e., in polynomial time) is still a mystery for me. I have some
intuition of why the O(nm) algorithm works, but I have still to sit
down and write a complete, detailed a proof. I wish I had time.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-10-24</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-24/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-24/"/>






	<category term="complexity-theory" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:50:59Z</updated>
	<published>2000-10-24T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Whew! One of the longest homeworks that I&#39;ve ever had was finished
today. Programmning Turing Machines takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-10-16</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-16/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-10-16/"/>






	<category term="math" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:50:59Z</updated>
	<published>2000-10-16T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;After a lot of time doing this Combinatorial Optimization homework,
I found out that a lot of my colleagues didn&#39;t even bother to prove
that their algorithms worked, while I&#39;ve spent a lot of time
finding algorithm invariants and proving that they were actually
maintained from interation to iteration. This is the Right
Thing(tm) to do, but it also takes a lot of time. What should I do
next time?&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-09-24</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-09-24/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-09-24/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:50:59Z</updated>
	<published>2000-09-24T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Still doing homework.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-09-23</title>

	<id>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-09-23/</id>

	<link href="http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/2000-09-23/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T20:50:59Z</updated>
	<published>2000-09-23T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Spent a good part of the day doing homework. Two of &#39;em, in fact.
One, due Monday. The other, due Tuesday. I&#39;m more enthusiastic
about Combinatorial Optimization than programming Turing Machines,
but both classes I&#39;m attending are cool. For someone that enjoys
theoretical Computer Science, that is. Amazingly, the theory is not
far from the Real World (tm).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
