<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged study</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/study/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>Playing with MOOCs</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/playing_with_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/playing_with_moocs/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>education</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>git</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>python</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:33:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-07-04T12:25:16Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Not so much ago, we had a boom of new enterprises offering Massive Online
Open Courses (MOOCs for short).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First were Thrun and Norvig (Artificial Intelligence), with Widom
(Introduction to Databases) and Ng (Machine Learning). Then, these initial
experiments led to the creation of Udacity (founded by Thrun) and Coursera
(founded by Ng and Koller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been keeping an eye on them for some time and, in fact, I have been
contributing to a project similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; (which
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/sid/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;I package for Debian&lt;/a&gt;), but focused on downloading videos from
Cousera, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jplehmann/coursera&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;coursera-dl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started contributing to &lt;code&gt;coursera-dl&lt;/code&gt; because I wanted to stratch some
itches with downloading with &lt;a href=&quot;http://aria2.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aria2c&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but soon the original
author of the project granted me write permission to the repository and I
have been one of the persons that commits the most, which is strange, since
I was not the original creator of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, from the courses that grant certificates, I have concluded the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part 1 (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Databases (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum Mechanics and Quantum Computation (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Cryptography I (Coursera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M101P: MongoDB for Developers (10gen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M102: MongoDB for DBAs (10gen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers (10gen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have to say that this have been a pleasant experience, with some of the
courses being challenging, but not up to what an undergraduate course would
be (and the fears of some people that such courses would threaten the
conventional University-style model are a bit far at this point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, talking about challenging courses, in particular, prof. Umesh
Vazirani&#39;s &quot;Quantum Mechanics and Quantum Computation&quot; had a lot of
(computational) work and this was one of the courses that prompted me to use
a computer algebra system for manipulating some tedious calculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I used a mix of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sagenb.org/&quot;&gt;online SAGE math server&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wolframalpha.com/&quot;&gt;Wolfram Alpha&lt;/a&gt;, whichever I found the syntax to be easier to use for
the problem in question. It is with happiness that I see that there are
efforts to &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~thansen/debian-sage-status.html&quot;&gt;get SAGE again packaged in Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another (positively) surprising course has been Dan Boneh&#39;s &quot;Introduction to
Cryptography I&quot;, which was more theoretical and more serious than what I was
expecting. It even included some nice proof sketches and discussion of
recent results. The last course on cryptography that I took was in 1998 and
&lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of things changed since then, including the way to think about
cryptography. But more on that on a future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some other courses that I may be completing soon and that I will
post more about, with some reviews of the good and the bad parts of select
ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2005-11-19</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-19/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-11-19/</link>


	<category>books</category>

	<category>lisp</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:09:53Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Purchased some books at discount prices. Nice. Now I can learn
Lisp. Let&#39;s see how I like this new thing of macros &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-12-04</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-04/</link>


	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Um dia um pouco inútil. Acordei mais tarde do que o usual (17h) e
fui ler os sites de costume (&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/&quot;&gt;slashdot.org&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/daily/&quot;&gt;LWN Daily Updates&lt;/a&gt; e
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agestado.com.br/agestado/?rf&quot;&gt;Agência Estado&lt;/a&gt;). A
propósito, eu gosto tanto do Agência Estado (principalmente da
cobertura econômica, dos comentários acessíveis ao público leigo em
economia e do uso de poucos plugins nas páginas -- muito melhor do
que a &lt;a href=&quot;http://noticias.uol.com.br/ultnot/&quot;&gt;concorrência&lt;/a&gt;) que uma
das coisas que eu mais gostaria de ver seria um canal de RSS com as
notícias para eu usar em algum cliente
(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ximian.com/images/screenshots/ximian_evolution/summary.png&quot;&gt;Evolution&lt;/a&gt;,
junto com a temperatura e resumos de outros sites) e não perder
mais tempo na Web do que eu já perco. Entretanto, achar algo como
isto em algum site não é muito fácil em geral, até mesmo nos sites
que &lt;em&gt;fornecem&lt;/em&gt; os canais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solução é, portanto, fazer um script em
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perl.com&quot;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt; para transformar a página de notícias
em um canal e, daí, usar o resultado. Fiz dois scripts, um para o
UOL e outro para o Agência Estado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acho que eu tenho uma relação de amor e ódio com Perl. Hoje foi um
dia de amor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anunciei &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~rbrito/listas/bio/&quot;&gt;a lista&lt;/a&gt;,
comecei uma leitura (desordenada) de coisas sobre Alinhamentos de
Várias Seqüências e me toquei de uma coisa bem elementar mas muito
legal a respeito do algoritmo de programação dinâmica (que eu acho
que já deveria ter percebido há algum tempo -- como é bom
estudar).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-09-17</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-09-17/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-09-17/</link>


	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, the text that I have been writing for some time now was
submitted for the Qualifying Examination of my Master&#39;s Degree!
This is a landmark in my career and many doors may be open for me
now, with many more professional possibilities. It also means that
I&#39;ll soon be having to present my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have already downloaded the whole
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openoffice.org&quot;&gt;OpenOffice suite&lt;/a&gt; for Linux, which
enables me to make presentations compatible with Microsoft&#39;s
Powerpoint without ever touching Microsoft software. OpenOffice has
already reached the beta status and I think that now is the time to
give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Went to the shopping mall and later to the supermarket with my
sweet girlfriend and bought CDs that I found in the bargain bin for
only R$ 2.80 a piece. Got Paul Dianno&#39;s solo CD in the bunch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-16</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-16/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-16/</link>


	<category>blind-guardian</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>netbsd</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Busy day. Woke up as soon as possible to see
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~jose/&quot;&gt;my advisor&lt;/a&gt; and decide the furture
of my Master&#39;s degree. Then, at almost 4pm, had a ridicule lunch,
met my girlfriend and went to a shopping mall with her. While I was
there, I was attacked by the capitalist bug and had to buy me
something. I was looking for some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ora.com&quot;&gt;O&#39;Reilly&lt;/a&gt;
books, but they were way too expensive (I was expecting to get a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://perl.ora.com&quot;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt; book or
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/lpython/&quot;&gt;Learning Python&lt;/a&gt;, but
decided not to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to the salesman and asked if he had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csse.monash.edu.au/~damian/&quot;&gt;Damian Conway&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com/Conway/&quot;&gt;Object Oriented Perl&lt;/a&gt;, but he told
me &lt;em&gt;&quot;the printing was cancelled&quot;&lt;/em&gt;. I told him that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com&quot;&gt;Manning Publications&lt;/a&gt; wasn&#39;t told about
that and got some garbage as a response that I didn&#39;t even make an
effort to save in any part of my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had the mission to buy myself something, I got me
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blind-guardian.com&quot;&gt;Blind Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &quot;Nightfall in
Middle Earth&quot;. Wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish my day, I went to my uncle&#39;s store and got another SCSI
HD for the Powermac, but it was also defective. But now I&#39;m a lot
more confident that the problem isn&#39;t with the mac itself, but with
the HDs (the mac would boot with the HD attached and see it while
in MacOS 8, but trying to install it on the HD evidenced that the
head was hitting the platters -- tomorrow I&#39;ll be getting another
SCSI HD). Let me cross my fingers. If I actually install Linux on
it, I&#39;ll grab &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.penguinppc.org/~benh/&quot;&gt;BenH&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s 2.4.6
Linux and get &quot;my&quot; mac a fresh kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, NetBSD 1.5.1
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netbsd.org/Releases/formal-1.5/NetBSD-1.5.1.html&quot;&gt;is released&lt;/a&gt;.
I still can&#39;t get ISO images, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-14</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-14/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-14/</link>


	<category>movies</category>

	<category>opeth</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a day! I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; tired that I woke up at (almost) 5pm.
And, surprise: no light. Yes, a power outage. Anyway, my parents
weren&#39;t at home and I found a note that mom left on my computer&#39;s
keyboard telling me that they were shopping around. Then, I
discovered two new boxes at home: a brand new TV set and a new VCR.
The first time in 5 or 6 months that would be able to see my
amazing tape of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt; playing at Milwaukee
Metalfest. Woohoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But without power, my main concern was to be able to &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; anything
before the day became too dark. After half an hour (or was it an
hour?) trying to find some candles and fire, my parents arrived and
two hours later, I was watching &quot;As Good As It Gets&quot;. Cool movie,
BTW. Excellent acting of both Helen Hunt and Jack Nicholson (mom
told me that I act like him most of the time -- is that
compliment?).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-13</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-13/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-13/</link>


	<category>life</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t really got decent sleep (I actually went to bed at 6am+, no
kidding) and woke up by 12pm to bring
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~cris/&quot;&gt;my supervisor&lt;/a&gt; all the student&#39;s
programs. After everything was finished, I felt like a slave seeing
light and being free. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Went to my girlfriend&#39;s place (after renting two movies -- one
whose name I can&#39;t remember but that had Bruce Willis and Michelle
Pfeiffer on the leading roles and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thematrix.com&quot;&gt;&quot;The Matrix&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which she hadn&#39;t seen)
and watched half a movie. Came home to (try to) sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-07-12</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-12/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-12/</link>


	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Spent all day reading and rating some exercises and programs of
Analysis of Algorithms, since I&#39;m the oh-so-great TA. All day. All
night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-05-18</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-05-18/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-05-18/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a long time since I last updated my diary. Let&#39;s see if I
can get things up to date (and let me see if I can keep me
organized and productive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the day started quite a bit messy: my computer, for some
reason, didn&#39;t want to turn on. It was beeping with my monitor
telling me to check the signal cable. &quot;Humm... Time to buy another
graphics card&quot; (and just the thought of having to choose from among
one less manufacturer of video cards scared me). I checked my
mainboard manual and it confirmed that the beeps I heard were
indeed problems with my graphics card (it&#39;s obvious that I didn&#39;t
want to believe the unfortunate situation of buying another card).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to use my computer anyway, I just removed my card from its
slot, and installed it again. Luckily, things started working
again. Whew! That was close! Anyway, I&#39;m now watching this card
closely. Very closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learned how to set up cookies with CGI scripts. Found out about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.recipesource.com/&quot;&gt;an site with recipes (for cooking)&lt;/a&gt;
while having my daily dose of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slashdot.org/&quot;&gt;Slashdot.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps due to lousy system administrators,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iname.com/&quot;&gt;Iname&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mail.com/&quot;&gt;Mail.com&lt;/a&gt; is
not delivering my e-mails. AGAIN. Enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, I have to finish a take home exam on Approximation
Algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>2001-03-10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-03-10/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-03-10/</link>


	<category>debian</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>health</category>

	<category>kde</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>network</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2001 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t do many important things today, besides making a brand new
installation of Debian&#39;s sid/unstable to see how things were going
with the bleeding edge. It turned out to be better than I expected
(I had some problems experiencing unstable before, so I was
scared).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the nicest things are that it features XFree86 4.0.2 (with
the RENDER extension, since I have a Matrox G400) and that, coupled
with KDE 2.1/qt 2.3.0, makes it possible to use antialised fonts,
which make one&#39;s surfing experience much more pleasing, for
instance. If you are on the same boat, don&#39;t forget to visit
&lt;a href=&quot;http://keithp.com/~keithp/&quot;&gt;Keith Packard&#39;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;, as it
features a handy
&lt;a href=&quot;http://keithp.com/~keithp/fonts/XftConfig&quot;&gt;XftConfig file&lt;/a&gt;. The
only lowpoint of KDE with antialiasing is that if AA is enabled,
then you loose non-scalable fonts with KDE applications, which
means that you can&#39;t make konsole use a 10x20 fixed font anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, talking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt;, KDE 2.1 allows one
to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windowmaker.org/&quot;&gt;Windowmaker&lt;/a&gt; Dock
Applications, and this is a very welcome thing as I love wmifs. The
more I use KDE, the more I&#39;m impressed with it, in many respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managed also to find some sites explaining Androgenetic Alopecia
and which are potential treatments for it. Frankly, I&#39;d love to not
have to surf these sites... And keeping with the surfing thing,
found a remarkable program called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vtun.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;vtun&lt;/a&gt;, for setting up encrypted
TCP/IP tunnels. Handy for WANs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&#39;m keeping reading about Multiple Sequence Alignment, which is
getting more exciting day after day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
