<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged computers</title>
<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//tags/computers/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>A Wish: The Ability of Playing MP3 CDs/DVDs created by iTunes with Free Software</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/a-wish--the-ability-of-playing-mp3-cds-dvds-created-by-itunes-with-free-software/</link>


	<category>apple</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>indexed-metadata</category>

	<category>library</category>

	<category>mp3</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 20:34:09 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:55:12Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&#39;s iTunes has a very cool feature that I would like to have and that I
still have not yet noticed in any of the Linux music players (be them
rhythmbox, amarok, quodlibet, audacious etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feature is the following: Apple&#39;s iTunes player has the possibility of
playing CD-DA, with the information about the tracks (in computer jargon,
metadata) taken from on-line databases like Gracenote&#39;s CDDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software that I use doesn&#39;t have problems with this, at least
regarding audio CDs. They check some free on-line databases (like gnudb.org
or freedb.org, which, by the way, have CDs in their catalog that aren&#39;t
available in the commercial CDDB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the nicest feature that iTunes has is the ability to burn MP3/AAC CDs
taken from playlists composed by the user, neatly organized in a filesystem
structure of the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;artist&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;album&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;song&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also generates an XML file with the contents of the MP3 CD in a way that
makes it playable just like a CD-DA, but with remarkable characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it doesn&#39;t need a connection to the Internet to grab metadata (which is,
of course, stored both in the XML file and in some file&#39;s metadata). This
means that no network connection is necessary to have information about
songs and the XML file acts like a cache to avoid the program reading the
whole CD to show the information in a user-friendly fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MP3 CD is treated like a CD-DA, but with a much longer capacity (say,
12 hours, depending on the bitrate of the songs and their lengths).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the songs don&#39;t have to be imported into playlists and not even queued for
playing. Just selecting the first song to be played is enough for it to
start plaing things (and, of course, it is not always that we want to
import songs to our library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In particular, I think that this would be a great thing for the GNOME
Desktop (and for others too), since it would increase the interoperability
with other Operating Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only iTunes can create such CDs, but it can also create DVDs containing
MP3/AAC files, which, of course, means that the capacity of such &quot;CDs&quot; is
huge compared to that of usual audio CDs and it is also a convenient way to
carry the discs around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience and workflow, it would be really nice to be able to play
such CDs/DVDs with rhythmbox/amarok/quodlibet, as it would represent both a
handy feature and a nice interoperability factor (and convenience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of Free Software players, more formats could be considered, of
course, than just MP3 and Low Complexity AAC. Vorbis, Speex, MP2, AC-3 and
other less-known formats would be possible (well, even Window&#39;s WMA files,
as they are playable by a lot of set-top boxes and car players).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, in addition to playing such CDs/DVDs, those programs could also create
such CDs (say, by passing the responsibility to another program), then
everything would be a dream come true and many other friends of mine would
be one step further from being tied to Mac OS X or Windows and closer to
Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this shows to be an improvement for the Free Software Desktop
environments like GNOME and KDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: The same thing applies to Photo CDs created by iPhoto. It would be
really exciting to have them be recognized by F-Spot or other similar Photo
organizers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Getting things from the iTunes Music Store without iTunes</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/getting-things-from-the-itunes-music-store-without-itunes/</link>


	<category>apple</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>itunesu</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 11:11:54 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:55:12Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free%20Software&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; advocate that I am, I want to use as
much Free Software as I can (and spread the world).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: no, I don&#39;t like to call what I use
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open%20Source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.  I prefer the things the RMS way and if you
don&#39;t like the fact that I like his way, I&#39;m afraid that you may miss some
of the things that I have here, even if you don&#39;t necessarily agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I would like to use, see etc., the material that is available
on the Internet, that people has put available for others to see. In
particular, many Universities around the world are making the shift of being
only in the classroom to being present in their students&#39; lifes all the
time. This is accomplished by putting their educational material available
on-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade or two ago, this was usually accomplished by publishing the
so-called &quot;lecture notes&quot; on the website of the course and maintaining
mailing-lists with the currently enrolled students. The lecture notes were
usually taken using the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scribe&quot;&gt;Scribe&lt;/a&gt; method&quot;, where, for each
class, one student is responsible of taking notes of the material, writing
it in a &quot;finished&quot; form and distributing it back for all the other
students. This was made in a round-robin fashion, as a means to spread the
responsibilities among the students taking the course. Also, the most common
tool used to edit the material, especially in Mathematically-oriented
courses, was to typeset everything in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; (or even plain
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TeX&quot;&gt;TeX&lt;/a&gt;, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecturer frequently distributed a template, which the students used and,
this way, all the notes written by the students had the same, uniform look
and style. The work was usually revised by the lecturer and, many times, it
resulted in a kind of a book, published in
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Device%5Findependent%5Ffile%5Fformat&quot;&gt;DVI&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PostScript&quot;&gt;PostScript&lt;/a&gt; form (latter, it became common to use
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portable%5Fdocument%5Fformat&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, as it is a format more
popular).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it is still quite frequent (and welcome!) to produce such lecture
notes. But, now, things have changed slightly. (I could discuss &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; things
have changed the way they have, but it is beyond the scope of these short
notes here.) People have been recording lectures in audio and, after the
technology became more accessible, in video. Now, a new term is used for
distributing those contents: &lt;em&gt;podcasting&lt;/em&gt;. Essentially, a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/podcast&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; is a way of publishing, say, audio so that people can
subscribe to your &quot;podcast&quot; (sometimes also said to be a &quot;channel&quot;). It is
very much like a radio program, where people tune in to listen to a given
program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way most people use to distribute the &quot;episodes&quot; of such
programs/podcasts is actually a combination of technologies, but nothing
exactly new: the description of &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is available is given in a format
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; (which is a specialization of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt;,
but this isn&#39;t important for our subject matter) and the content is usually
in form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP3&quot;&gt;MP3&lt;/a&gt; files (or some variation of that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough background. Now, there are on-line stores on the Internet that
make available podcasts. Those podcasts are usually free of charge for the
listener. Some of the most prominent stores nowadays are
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple%5FInc%2E&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &quot;iTunes Store&quot; and Amazon&#39;s store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has created its &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes%20Store&quot;&gt;iTunes Store&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to foster the use of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iTunes&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; program and to boost the sales of its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/iPod&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; digital players (and, also, to make some extra money).
But people in the education field have seen that using a podcast would be a
good way of sharing knowledge and Apple wouldn&#39;t loose this market: they
invented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ITunes%5FStore%23iTunes%5FU&quot;&gt;iTunes U&lt;/a&gt;, which is
a way for Universities around the world to publish their content on &quot;iTunes
Store&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several big Universities have been putting their content on Apple&#39;s
iTunes-U. And, to see the directory of podcasts on iTunes-U, you have (in
theory) to use Apple&#39;s proprietary program iTunes, only available for
proprietary platforms: for Microsoft&#39;s Windows and for Apple&#39;s own
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac%20OS%20X&quot;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. No Free Software alternative is officially
supported, despite the fact that the blurb on the Universities pages say
that only the access to the content has to be via iTunes and that the
content can be used with any MP3 player or with programs other than
iTunes. Yes, this means that the content is playable under
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; and Linux plays a big role in higher education
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, isn&#39;t there a way to access the blogs avoiding the use of proprietary
software? What about people that only want to use Free Software solutions
or, not even a matter of desiring to use Free Software, having only access
to Free Software?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there is. Apple has changed the way that people use to get the
contents from its iTunes store during time, but, now, it seems to be quite
easy to grab it under a 100% Free environment. I have used this recipe for
two Universities only so far, but it has worked perfectly well. The
Universities in question are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford%20University&quot;&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say that you come across a link with the format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;itms://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Browse/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a link is &lt;em&gt;usually not&lt;/em&gt; recognized by browsers without the help of
extra software. In platforms where iTunes is available, the browser sends it
to iTunes and iTunes takes the duty of connecting to the &quot;iTunes Music
Store&quot; (that&#39;s where the &quot;itms&quot; thing at the beginning of the URL comes
from, by the way). Pay close attention to the part
&lt;code&gt;mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646&lt;/code&gt;. That is the important part of
the URL here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is quite easy to convert the link above to something that can be
grabbed with a usual browser or, say, a program like wget or curl. Just
write the link as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/DownloadTracksFile/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part up to and including &lt;code&gt;DownloadTracksFile/&lt;/code&gt; is constant. Only the
part after it is changed and taken from the original link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another way of rewriting the link. Its format is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/FeedEnclosure/mit.edu.1330383747.01330383754.1330693646/enclosure.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the middle part of this URL is the actual part that we alluded
to. The rest is simply a constant thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this way, we can get the contents of podcasts with Free Software in an
automated way. That is, until Apple changes its scheme of doing things. But,
by that time, we will already have the things we want and newer solutions
can be devised soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&#39;s fire those wget&#39;s and start to study things (or prozilla&#39;s,
aria2c&#39;s etc, for some speed boost).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Music, Group Actions, Quilt and Debian Packages</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/music-group-actions-quilt-and-debian-packages/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/music-group-actions-quilt-and-debian-packages/</link>


	<category>abstract-algebra</category>

	<category>class-equation</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>group-actions</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>quilt</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 02:08:51 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T07:13:17Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;These are some short notes on what I&#39;ve doing these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there isn&#39;t much to talk about. I think that one of the most
relevant things that I did was to resurrect one of my best
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital%5Faudio%5Fextraction&quot;&gt;audio-extracting&lt;/a&gt; CD-ROM
drives: just opened the case of my computer, took off the CD drive, opened,
cleaned its lens, lubricated the moving parts and everything is back to
normal operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sense of &quot;getting something for nothing&quot; is hard to explain to those
who have not experienced it already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things that I did was to grab some old CDs that I had laying here
(Radiohead&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OK%20Computer&quot;&gt;OK Computer&lt;/a&gt;, Pantera&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Far%5FBeyond%5FDriven&quot;&gt;Far Beyond Driven&lt;/a&gt;, the tribute to Queen called &quot;Dragon
Attack&quot;, and Gentle Giant&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free%20Hand&quot;&gt;Free Hand&lt;/a&gt;, among others). Dream
Theater&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systematic%5FChaos&quot;&gt;Special Edition of Systematic Chaos&lt;/a&gt;
is quite good, but unfortunately I don&#39;t have a 5.1 system at my disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also selected some material for further studies. I&#39;m right now studying
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/group%20actions&quot;&gt;group actions&lt;/a&gt; (or G-sets as some seem to prefer). Soon, I
will be finishing the basics of Group Theory (hey, really, why is the &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conjugacy_class&quot;&gt;&quot;Class Equation&quot;&lt;/a&gt; of
groups that &quot;famous&quot;? It is just a matter of saying that $|X| = \sum_{x\in
X} 1$, but with cardinality of orbits instead of with one&#39;s and with a
transversal of the orbits in place of $X$ itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, if the orbits of the elements of the $G$-set $X$ consist of just
one element, then the equation above is the &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Group_action&quot;&gt;&quot;Class Equation&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (what
some people would call $\mathop{\mathrm{Fix}}(X)$, I would call the &quot;orbits
being trivial&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burnside%27s_lemma&quot;&gt;Burnside&#39;s
lemma&lt;/a&gt; (which actually seems to be wrongly attributed, since it seems to
be discovered independently by Cauchy and Frobenius) for counting orbits of
a given action of a $G$-set has nice implications in combinatorics and it
should be, at least, mentioned in any self-respecting introduction to Group
Theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I almost forgot one of the major things that I did today (2007-06-12): I
finally learned how to manipulate the &lt;a
href=&quot;http://savannah.nongnu.org/projects/quilt&quot;&gt;quilt patch-system&lt;/a&gt;
(initiated by &lt;a
href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Morton_%28computer_programmer%29&quot;&gt;Andrew
Morton&lt;/a&gt;). The crucial point that is not written anywhere: the patches, by
default, are applied with &lt;code&gt;-p1&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;-p0&lt;/code&gt;. This
took me quite some time to get, as the documentation isn&#39;t explicit about
it. Installation of quilt in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS
X&lt;/a&gt; system is not trivial, due to the demand of &lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt; tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I can keep some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; packages
of mine in a better shape than if I were just applying a single monolithic
patch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Debian Switching to EGLIBC</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/debian-switching-to-eglibc/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/debian-switching-to-eglibc/</link>


	<category>computers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>embedded</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 23:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:55:12Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Having been playing with some new things in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, like the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/magicfilter&quot;&gt;magicfilter&lt;/a&gt; package, which is a superb, lightweight solution to
all my printing problems: to use a PCL 3 printer. I think that I will also
&quot;manufacture&quot; a solution with a metapackage of a live CD that includes the
environment that I use frequently, with the packages that I use (this is
probably quite leaner than what &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; has done with their
distribution, since I will mainly use some lighter packages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, talking about lighter packages, I see that Debian has adopted a new C
library, namely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eglibc.org/&quot;&gt;EGLIBC&lt;/a&gt;, which stands for Embedded LIBC. Finally, it
seems that Debian will focus a bit more on smaller systems (which is a good
thing, because computing resources are limited).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Happy News: A new Kurobox</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/happy-news-a-new-kurobox/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/happy-news-a-new-kurobox/</link>


	<category>computers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>embedded</category>

	<category>kurobox</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>nas</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2007 23:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:55:12Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I was pleasantly surprised that the Kurobox that &lt;a href=&quot;http://suihkulokki.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Riku Voipio&lt;/a&gt; sent
me has arrived!  From the looks of it, it is a Kurobox HG, which, compared
to my Kurobox HD, has a faster processor (it runs at 266MHz, instead of
200MHz), has more RAM (128MB, instead of 64MB), and has a faster network
connection (an 1Gbps instead of 100Mbps interface).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m trying to see if I will be able to use a SATA drive with this Kurobox,
as we can&#39;t find large IDE/PATA drives in the market today (almost). And the
bigger capacity ones are only available with SATA interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Playing with Package Proxies</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/playing-with-package-proxies/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/playing-with-package-proxies/</link>


	<category>approx</category>

	<category>apt-move</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>embedded</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>proxy</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 23:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:55:12Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Have been playing with the great idea of &lt;a
href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2009/03/msg00210.html&quot;&gt;caching&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/Articles/318658/&quot;&gt;deb&lt;/a&gt; packages. I finally
settled for the option of using &lt;code&gt;&lt;a
href=&quot;http://git.debian.org/?p=pkg-ocaml-maint/packages/approx.git&quot;&gt;approx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;,
which does a really nice job of caching packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it fullfils quite a lot of requirements and even surpasses some of my expectations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It supports multiple architectures (in fact, this is important for me, as
I use &lt;code&gt;i386&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;amd64&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;powerpc&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can support multiple distributions (both different versions of the same
distribution and completely different distributions, as long as they use a
repository like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s, as is the
case of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It keeps its directory hierarchy neatly organized, like that of Debian, in
a package pool, which saves space and makes everything easier and faster
to find (and has the advantage of being fast with filesystems that don&#39;t
cope well with many entries in one directory).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The transition wasn&#39;t painless from &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/apt%2Dmove&quot;&gt;apt-move&lt;/a&gt;, since apt-move
moves the files, but renames them in a way that they don&#39;t keep epochs in
their names, which makes &lt;code&gt;approx-import&lt;/code&gt; moan about the packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For places where I am too lazy to import the packages, I just filled the
cache redownloading the packages with something approximately like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  apt-get -d --reinstall install $(dpkg -l | grep &quot;^ii&quot; | cut -d &quot; &quot; -f 3)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I hope that this experience happens to be useful for other people, so
that they can benefit from it. Rebuilding packages with a package cacher is
much more pleasant, especially if the package has a lot of
build-dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Sourceforge, SSH keys, Free audiobooks, DVD&#x27;s</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/sourceforge-ssh-keys-free-audiobooks-dvds/</guid>

	<link>http://rb.doesntexist.org/blog//posts/sourceforge-ssh-keys-free-audiobooks-dvds/</link>


	<category>audiobooks</category>

	<category>computers</category>

	<category>descartes</category>

	<category>dvds</category>

	<category>hashes</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>opeth</category>

	<category>pain-of-salvation</category>

	<category>public-domain</category>

	<category>security</category>

	<category>ssh</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2007 23:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2012-09-07T06:55:12Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Found out about &quot;The Right Way (TM)&quot; to hash an existing SSH&#39;s &lt;code&gt;known_hosts&lt;/code&gt;
file (&lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen -H&lt;/code&gt;) and how to remove a hashed host entry from your
&lt;code&gt;known_hosts&lt;/code&gt; file: &lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen -H -R host.name&lt;/code&gt;.  I needed this for newer
checkouts of LAME&#39;s CVS repository at &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/&quot;&gt;Sourceforge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, just to save myself the trouble of looking it up again, here is the
link to the place where sourceforge keeps their &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.sourceforge.net/trac/sitedocs/wiki/SSH%20key%20fingerprints&quot;&gt;SSH key fingerprints&lt;/a&gt;.
I&#39;m always lost trying to find it, so I thought that it would be best to
record it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also discovered a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; amazing thing: a &lt;a href=&quot;http://librivox.org/&quot;&gt;free source of audiobooks&lt;/a&gt;
in podcast format, while I was looking for René Descartes&#39; &quot;The Method&quot;.
While surfing the net, I also found that there is this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dominiopublico.gov.br/pesquisa/DetalheObraForm.do?select_action=&amp;amp;amp;co_obra=2274&quot;&gt;very same text&lt;/a&gt;
in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dominiopublico.gov.br/&quot;&gt;Brazilian site&lt;/a&gt; backed by the government that hosts works in the
public domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still downloading Pain of Salvation&#39;s Acoustic set. Now, I finally had some
time to watch the somewhat incomplete VOBs and it, indeed, has the show. And
it is an amazing piece of music. Recommended for all fans of good music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
