<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged life</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2018-04-17T09:27:25Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>JUnit 5</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-10_junit_5/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-10_junit_5/"/>






	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2017-11-10T05:45:16Z</updated>
	<published>2017-11-10T05:21:06Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;If you want to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://junit.org/junit5/&quot;&gt;JUnit 5&lt;/a&gt;, the latest release of &lt;a href=&quot;http://junit.org/&quot;&gt;JUnit&lt;/a&gt;, from
Eclipse, then you have to change your import from &lt;code&gt;import org.junit.Test;&lt;/code&gt;
to &lt;code&gt;import org.junit.jupiter.api.Test;&lt;/code&gt;. Notice the &lt;code&gt;jupiter.api&lt;/code&gt; there in
the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the test runner will complain and tell you that you don&#39;t have
tests in your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The not-so-minimal test that I created was the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;package test;

import static org.hamcrest.CoreMatchers.*;
import static org.junit.Assert.*;

import org.junit.jupiter.api.Test;

class FirstTest {
    @Test
    void test() {
        assertThat(1+1, is(equalTo(2)));
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Some activities of the day</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-06_random_notes/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-06_random_notes/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="parenting" />


	<updated>2018-03-23T02:13:07Z</updated>
	<published>2017-11-07T00:52:59Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I printed the first draft of the first chapter when my little boy
was here and he was impressed with this strange object called a &quot;printer&quot;.
Before I printed what I needed, I fired up LibreOffice and chose the biggest
font size that was available and let him type his first name by himself.
He was quicker than I thought with a keyboard. After seeing me print his
first name, he was jumping up and down with joy of having created something
and even showed grandma and grandpa what he had done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, then, wanted more and I taught him how to use that backspace key, what
it meant and he wanted to type his full name. I let him and taught him that
there is a key called space that he should type every time he wants to start
a new word and, in the end, he typed his first two names. To my surprise, he
memorized the icon with the printer (which I must say that I have to hunt
every time, since it seems so similar to the adjacent ones!) and pressed
this new key called &quot;Enter&quot;. When he pressed, he wasn&#39;t expecting the
printer on his right to start making noises and printing his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was so excited and it was so nice to see his reaction full of joy to get
a job done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of getting a spare computer, building it with him and for him,
so that he can call it his computer every time he comes to see daddy. As a
serendipitous situation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/&quot;&gt;Packt Publishing&lt;/a&gt; offered yesterday their
title &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.packtpub.com/application-development/python-projects-kids&quot;&gt;&quot;Python Projects for Kids&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, he does
not yet know how to read, but I guess that the right age is coming soon,
which is a good thing to make him be educated &quot;the right way&quot; (that is, with
the best support, teaching and patience that I can give him).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I printed the first draft of the first chapter and today I have to
turn it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I am &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/tools/vms/&quot;&gt;downloading a virtual machine from Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; to
try to install Java on it. Let me see if it works. I have none of the
virtualization options used, tough the closest seems to be virtualbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me cross my fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I updated some of the tags of very old posts of this blog,
and I am seriously thinking about switching from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ikiwiki.info/&quot;&gt;ikiwiki&lt;/a&gt; to another
blog platform. It is &lt;em&gt;slow&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;very slow&lt;/em&gt; on my system with the repositories
that I have, especially on my armel system. Some non-interpreted system
would be best, but I don&#39;t know if such a thing even exists. But the killer
problem is that it doesn&#39;t support easily the typing of Mathematics (even
though a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bk/ikiwiki-plugin-mathjax&quot;&gt;3rd party plugin&lt;/a&gt; for MathJax exists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I just received &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/telegram/status/927470283094499329&quot;&gt;an answer on twitter&lt;/a&gt; from @telegram and
it was nice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello, Telegram supports bold and italic. You can type &lt;code&gt;**bold**&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;__italic__&lt;/code&gt;. On mobile, you can also highlight text for this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is nice that this works with &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/telegram-desktop&quot;&gt;telegram-desktop&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I filed some bugs on Debian&#39;s BTS, responded to some issues on
my projects on GitHub (I&#39;m slowly getting back on maintaining things) and
file &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bk/ikiwiki-plugin-mathjax/issues/3&quot;&gt;wishlist bugs on some other projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I grabbed a copy of &quot;Wonder woman&quot; (&quot;Mulher Maravilha&quot;) and
&quot;Despicable Me 3&quot; (&quot;Meu Malvado Favorito 3&quot;) dubbed in Brazilian Portuguese
for my son. I have to convert the audio from AAC-LC in 6 channels to AC3 or
to stereo. Otherwise, my TVs have problem with the videos (one refuses to
play the entire file and another plays the audio with sounds of hiccups).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; After converting the VirtualBox image taken from Microsoft, I
could easily use &lt;code&gt;qemu&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;kvm&lt;/code&gt; to create screenshots of the installation of
Java.  The command that I used (for future reference) is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
qemu-system-x86_64 -enable-kvm -m 4096 -smp 2 -net nic,model=e1000 -net user -soundhw ac97 -drive index=0,media=disk,cache=unsafe,file=win7.qcow2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Fixed some typos.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>The importance of flexible deadlines in MOOCs</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="mooc" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2014-04-04T16:49:20Z</updated>
	<published>2014-04-04T16:48:59Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I have always thought that having flexible deadlines in MOOCs is important,
despite not having used them too much. Until last night, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course in question is Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://statlearning.class.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning&lt;/a&gt; and they
adopted a policy of letting the students complete all the assignments of the
10 week course until the last day of the course, in March 21. Then, they
graciously extended the deadline to April 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it not for such an extension, I would not have completed the course. I
sent them a message on the course forums this morning to thank them for
this, as this, in my experience, is not so common with MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reproduce below the message that I posted on the forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Thank you also for the EXTENSION of the deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Dear professors and staff,&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you (of course) for the course, as many others have
  already. Despite not liking edX platform too much (preferring the UI of,
  say, Coursera), your course was an exception, interesting enough (and funny
  enough) that I sticked to it until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But I would like to bring attention here to a point that many may not have
  appreciated (or, perhaps, not expressed as clearly as I thought that it
  deserved), namely, the extension of the deadlines (and a uniform deadline
  for all homeworks).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, due to some unfortunate facts of my personal life, I could
  not work on the course at all in the past few weeks. In fact, I completed
  units 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 in the last 3 or 4 days and submitted my
  last quiz a few hours before today&#39;s midnight (at my local time, UTC-0300),
  and I still got a passing grade(!).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Even with my desire to finish the course, this would not have been
  possible if you had not graciously allowed for the deadline extension. I am
  sure that I may not be alone here in appreciating this extension (even
  though I think that I may be many standard deviations from the mean, doing
  the homework and R programs of 7 weeks in only 4 days).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Thank you so very much for everything (including this extension!),&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Rogério Brito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/"/>






	<category term="android" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="mooc" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2014-03-03T05:35:23Z</updated>
	<published>2014-03-03T05:35:11Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2009-02-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-02-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-02-03/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="ipod" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:27:25Z</updated>
	<published>2009-02-03T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;In the past few days, I did quite a good amount of things. One of
the things that took most of my mind was to convert some videos in
a proper format for the iPod. At first, I thought that the format
of the videos would have to have an H.264 encoded video with
resolution 320x240 (without using cabac, which increases the
compression factor of the video) and audio in the AAC format with
bitrates up to 160kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, using Apple&#39;s Quicktime Pro 7, I exported a video from the
Dutch band called After Forever, which had the resolution bigger
than 320x240. This made me revisit Apple&#39;s site where the
specifications of videos meant to be played on iPods. It seems
that, now, with the latest firmware update, the iPod that I have
can play H.264 videos encoded with resolutions up to 640x480 (the
standard VGA resolution). Also, the bitrate doesn&#39;t need to be
restricted to 768kbps: some of the videos produced by Quicktime
(and which the iPods can play) have bitrates of up to 1500kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that I can now encode some of my videos that are in the
nasty WMV format to formats that can be supported in a decent
manner by Free Software system. I have, for instance, the
BBC-produced DVD called &quot;The Codebreakers&quot;, whose audio is in pure
DVD LPCM format (that is, uncompressed) and the space that it takes
on my hard disk is considerable (approx. 1GB).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2009-01-28</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-01-28/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-01-28/"/>






	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:22:33Z</updated>
	<published>2009-01-28T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Today was a very unusual day: it was quite active and I didn&#39;t have
a day like today for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had slept quite late, since I was waiting for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Quicktime 7 Pro for Windows (on my
girlfriend&#39;s computer) to finish the conversion of a video from one
of Cynic&#39;s show from their reunion. It was a show that was webcast
by the Norwegian company nhk.no (if I&#39;m not mistaken) and the show
is superb (it was from 2007 and they even played a, then,
unreleased song called &quot;Evolutionary Sleeper&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing of it all is that even though we where using a
x86-based machine (actually, a Duron 1.3GHz on a board with a SiS
730 chipset), which supported even SSE, things were quite slow. In
fact, the show took 1 day and some hours to be completely
&quot;exported&quot; in the iPod format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that was noteworthy was that my GF had some CDs that
she had burned and that contained some audio files from a course
that she took some time ago. Since those classes are quite
important and they interest me, I would like to listen to them. The
&quot;problem&quot; is that they are in IMA ADPCM format which most car
players don&#39;t play. The solution, in this case, will be to use lame
with libsndfile1 as input and convert the files to the MP3 format,
so that I can neatly tag the files and listen to them on my (and
her) car player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is only the beginning of the story, since two of her CDs
were not readable on my iBook G3, dammit. I, then, took the time to
download dvdisaster on her Windows computer (first, the stable
version; then, the more feature-full development version) and I
left the CDs being read. Unfortunately, it seems that even
dvdisaster is having a hard time reading many sectors of the CD-RWs
(and, yes, I did wash the discs with abundant water and used a very
soft towel to get them dry).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, another thing that I&#39;ve learned was that uTorrent is very
featureful. Apparently, much more featureful than Transmission. I&#39;d
say that its features are on par with Azureus (even though I have
not used Azureus for a loooong time, as it is Java-based and my
machines don&#39;t have enough horsepower for programs that are not
natively compiled).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the torrent to grab Ubuntu&#39;s jaunty alpha 3, so that I can
experiment with things to come (and the new notification system
that Mark has proposed. I actually liked it very much, but I am
eager to see it working). The only catch is that my GF&#39;s connection
is only 150kbps and things are &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; slow here, but I&#39;m getting
the image anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I woke up, I went to the proctologist. After that, I went to
see a friend of mine from the high-school days, that is now a
neuro-cirugeon, I had lost contact with him, but I sincerely hope
to get back in touch frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I went with my GF to the bank where she has her account to
see if he had some residual money from a nation-wide program called
FGTS. She did have, but some documents were missing. The worker
that received us told her that she could mail some of the missing
documentation via e-mail and we scanned the necessary
documentation, but the mails bounced. Bummer. At least, the trip to
the bank wasn&#39;t completely useless, since I saw that I have some
money on this FGTS thing and it was a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latter, I went to the local theater and saw that professors are
able to have a 50% discount on the entrance to see the movies,
given that we prove that we are actually active. This is a very
nice thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also saw the price of a new, Classic 120GB iPod. It wasn&#39;t
available on the store that I went to, but other store of the same
name has some units. I guess that I should see one. I was only
surprised to see that the 160GB model doesn&#39;t seem to be sold
anymore. Any reason for that? That left me puzzled, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the electronics store, I also saw a netbook from HP that was
sweet. Soooo small, so cute. I guess that I need one. It has a very
small form factor and it features a 1.2GHz VIA C7M processor. The
only things that made the red alert lights blink for me were the
Broadcom network interfaces: both wired and wireless, and Broadcom
is know to not be exactly that helpful with the Free Software
Movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to get a haircut and my girlfriend told me that
it was good. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latter, before going to her place, we went to my home just for a
little while so that I could see how the torrents for MIT&#39;s &quot;The
Structure and Interpretation of Computer Program&quot; MPEG1 videos were
going. Not good at all. Everything is stalled. I guess that I will
need to use this uTorrent thing (at least, experiment with it) so
that I can see if the downloads are slightly better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also did something unusual: scanned a 3x4 (centimeters, of
course!) photo of mine (which is needed here in Brazil for quite a
lot of documents) and collated it in 3 rows, in a way that I will
have 9 pics. I will print two of them (and have 18 pictures) for
R$0.69 each, which is not a bad deal. My girlfriend liked the idea
and I will do the same thing for her, since she will need many
photos for her id&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we got the vacuum cleaner to clean up her place (mostly
the TV room) and I cleaned her fan (which was quite dusty).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, the day will be quite full and I will have a lot of
things to do in this endless saga. I hope to write more about this
hectic (but pleasant) week.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-12-17</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-17/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-17/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:20:15Z</updated>
	<published>2008-12-17T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Prepared a surprise party to Sa.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-12-16</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-16/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-16/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:20:07Z</updated>
	<published>2008-12-16T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Today was honey&#39;s birthday and I gave her a gift right when I
arrived at her place. It was nice to bring her to my home to
celebrate such a magic moment.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-12-08</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-08/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-08/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:19:47Z</updated>
	<published>2008-12-08T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Came to the conclusion that I am fortunate enough to have met a
person that I like so much that I had the courage to ask her to be
my girlfriend. I brought her home so that she could know my parents
and both parties were impressed with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so nice to have her here at home.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-12-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-12-03/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:14:39Z</updated>
	<published>2008-12-03T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I had a second meeting with a girl at a local shopping mall. The
initial plan was to go to the movies, but we spent so much time
chatting that the hours flied and we missed the movies. Bah, they
weren&#39;t that interesting anyway. What was interesting, though, was
spending some time in her car, talking about a number of things.
How pleasant it was! And her kisses are wonderful. I think that I&#39;m
falling in love.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
