<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged life</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2013-06-06T21:19:57Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>2005-12-14</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-14/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-14/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2013-04-20T01:06:20Z</updated>
	<published>2005-12-14T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Ich bin müde.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-12-16</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-16/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-16/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2013-06-06T21:19:57Z</updated>
	<published>2001-12-16T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;É duro participar de uma sociedade e o bom funcionamento dela
recair sobre você. É ruim ser o ponto de equilíbrio, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;o único&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
lugar que se verga incessantemente para absorver os problemas.
Causa estresse. Isto quando não frusta. É assim que me sinto.
Triste. Mais triste do que eu deveria estar, mais triste do que o
que eu mereço.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Às vezes, negócios que parecem bons no começo revelam-se muito
custosos com o tempo... Que tristeza!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-12-12</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-12/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-12/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="macos" />

	<category term="perl" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-06-06T21:19:41Z</updated>
	<published>2001-12-12T02:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Lots of things going on. I&#39;m now even more sure that I do want one
of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ibook/&quot;&gt;new and sweet iBooks&lt;/a&gt;. They
are so sweet, come with a long-lasting battery, have a 1024x768 res
LCD, a Firewire port, a 10/100 Ethernet port, a reasonably big HD
and an ATI card. In my opinion, it&#39;s only drawback: it doesn&#39;t have
a PCMCIA slot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added bonus, what could be cooler than Apple now selling its
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;new Operating System&lt;/a&gt; as the
&quot;World&#39;s Most Advanced Operating System&quot;, when, in fact, it is a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/darwin/&quot;&gt;Unix&lt;/a&gt; under the hood?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuxppc.org/&quot;&gt;runs Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! Not only that, but
if I ever get tired of Linux and want MacOS X, I can have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fink.sf.net&quot;&gt;it with the power of Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But well, there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; another drawback. Nothing can be perfect. Of
course. These things are so damn expensive here in my country,
mostly due to the absurd exchange rates and to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.receita.fazenda.gov.br&quot;&gt;huge taxes&lt;/a&gt;. Anything that
isn&#39;t obtained with the welcome, kind help of the &quot;gray markets&quot; is
so damn expensive (to the point of quickly becoming intangible).
Which means that I&#39;ll probably not have one iBook unless I go
travel and come back with one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learned a bit more about Perl. Became a bit scared with the amound
of things it does at run-time. Isn&#39;t there a switch for the
compiler/optimizer to tell it: &quot;perform only what I tell you and
optimize the hell out of this code&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-17</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-17/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-17/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-06-06T21:10:21Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-17T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;This is the day that shouldn&#39;t have happened --- it was bad right
from start. First of all, I couldn&#39;t sleep well because I dreamt
with some perl scripts that didn&#39;t work and they took me almost all
my sleep time (or so it seemed). Then, my kind neighbor started
making lots of noises and I couldn&#39;t keep sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the worst part of the day was still coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to my uncle&#39;s shop to get a new SCSI HD and he lent me a 4GB
one, more than enough to hold both Linux and MacOS 8. I turned the
thing on and it started making noises like the one I used
yesterday, which wasn&#39;t good. Anyway, I left it on and decided to
install MacOS on it. It was progressing nicely and I was getting
happier and happier, but then the whole system froze. I turned the
power off and tried to install Linux. At least this time Linux saw
the HD and all partitions that it had (7, I think).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Linux, I used some CVS bootfloppies that will become
bootfloppies of Debian woody. While trying to make the brand new
ext2 filesystem, I got a kernel panic. I tried again. This time, I
went up to the point of choosing which kernel modules I wanted. I
was getting happy again. But then, when I chose the module for the
ethernet card, a new kernel panic. Ouch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then tried to install MacOS again and a new freeze. Tried again,
new freeze. Then, I noticed that the HD was getting hot and put a
fan near it. I don&#39;t know if it was coincidence or not, but after
that, I could finish the installation of MacOS. Ok, so time to boot
this thing with no CDs in the CD-ROM drive. Nothing. Grrrr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things got strange after I tried to put the Linux PPC CD that I had
burned and it didn&#39;t work. Washed the CD and no boot. But it did
some days ago! It was not scratched, had no fingerprints and was
absolutely clean. But couldn&#39;t boot. I tried using the floppies
again, but this time, another surprise: the HD &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; recognized,
but a partition scan timed out, Linux told that it could not read
read its beginning and that it assumed that the size of the HD was
1GB, and showed &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; partitions on the drive. On the other hand,
MacOS is able to see it just before formatting it, perhaps because
it re-scans the SCSI bus. Changing the SCSI-id of the drive didn&#39;t
help. Is that the reason why it can&#39;t boot from the HD? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my desire of seeing this thing encoding MP3s, using KDE, a
brand new browser and typing some texts with LaTeX seems a bit
farther than what I realized at first. I will still keep trying to
make this damn thing work, but I&#39;m not confident anymore that I&#39;ll
succeed. Well, I&#39;ll talk to my uncle tomorrow, perhaps and see if
the other Mac behaves the same way. Enough for a day already.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-16</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-16/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-16/"/>






	<category term="blind-guardian" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="netbsd" />

	<category term="powerpc" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-05-08T00:27:02Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-16T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Busy day. Woke up as soon as possible to see
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~jose/&quot;&gt;my advisor&lt;/a&gt; and decide the furture
of my Master&#39;s degree. Then, at almost 4pm, had a ridicule lunch,
met my girlfriend and went to a shopping mall with her. While I was
there, I was attacked by the capitalist bug and had to buy me
something. I was looking for some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ora.com&quot;&gt;O&#39;Reilly&lt;/a&gt;
books, but they were way too expensive (I was expecting to get a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://perl.ora.com&quot;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt; book or
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/lpython/&quot;&gt;Learning Python&lt;/a&gt;, but
decided not to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to the salesman and asked if he had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csse.monash.edu.au/~damian/&quot;&gt;Damian Conway&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com/Conway/&quot;&gt;Object Oriented Perl&lt;/a&gt;, but he told
me &lt;em&gt;&quot;the printing was cancelled&quot;&lt;/em&gt;. I told him that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com&quot;&gt;Manning Publications&lt;/a&gt; wasn&#39;t told about
that and got some garbage as a response that I didn&#39;t even make an
effort to save in any part of my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had the mission to buy myself something, I got me
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blind-guardian.com&quot;&gt;Blind Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &quot;Nightfall in
Middle Earth&quot;. Wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish my day, I went to my uncle&#39;s store and got another SCSI
HD for the Powermac, but it was also defective. But now I&#39;m a lot
more confident that the problem isn&#39;t with the mac itself, but with
the HDs (the mac would boot with the HD attached and see it while
in MacOS 8, but trying to install it on the HD evidenced that the
head was hitting the platters -- tomorrow I&#39;ll be getting another
SCSI HD). Let me cross my fingers. If I actually install Linux on
it, I&#39;ll grab &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.penguinppc.org/~benh/&quot;&gt;BenH&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s 2.4.6
Linux and get &quot;my&quot; mac a fresh kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, NetBSD 1.5.1
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netbsd.org/Releases/formal-1.5/NetBSD-1.5.1.html&quot;&gt;is released&lt;/a&gt;.
I still can&#39;t get ISO images, though.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-15</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-15/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-15/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="movies" />


	<updated>2013-05-08T00:24:44Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-15T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Went to my SO&#39;s home to finish watching the unnamed movie and to
see The Matrix. Had a great time with her, her parents, her brother
and one of her sisters.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-13</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-13/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-13/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-05-08T00:22:57Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-13T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t really got decent sleep (I actually went to bed at 6am+, no
kidding) and woke up by 12pm to bring
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~cris/&quot;&gt;my supervisor&lt;/a&gt; all the student&#39;s
programs. After everything was finished, I felt like a slave seeing
light and being free. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Went to my girlfriend&#39;s place (after renting two movies -- one
whose name I can&#39;t remember but that had Bruce Willis and Michelle
Pfeiffer on the leading roles and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thematrix.com&quot;&gt;&quot;The Matrix&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which she hadn&#39;t seen)
and watched half a movie. Came home to (try to) sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-10-01</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-01/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-10-01/"/>






	<category term="elections" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2012-12-09T02:50:17Z</updated>
	<published>2000-10-01T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Watched a tiny bit of the men marathon up to the point were the
African athletes won. This made me sleepy all the day. To make
matters worse, I woke up many times today. Noisy neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Election day today. It&#39;s funny that I thought I&#39;d have problems
standing in huge lines, but it seems that computers can indeed be
helpful to humanity. Everything was fast and no annoyances. I&#39;m
impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow may be a sad day for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.napster.com&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;/a&gt;.
Like they say,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gnutella.wego.com&quot;&gt;&quot;Hope for the best, prepare for worst&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.
This may mean that my ADSL may not be as useful as I&#39;d like it to
be...&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-09-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-30/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="movies" />


	<updated>2012-12-09T02:48:56Z</updated>
	<published>2000-09-30T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Today it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~lymber/&quot;&gt;Alexandre&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s birthday!
Happy birthday, pal! Too bad we&#39;re not together today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally went to catch a flick: &quot;What Lies Beneath&quot; (in Portuguese,
&quot;Premonição&quot;). It was supposed to be scary. Ok. Some parts were.
Came back home rightly after the movie was done (which means that
I&#39;d like to get home not so fast next time).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-09-24</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-24/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-24/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2012-12-09T02:45:06Z</updated>
	<published>2000-09-24T03:00:00Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Still doing homework.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
