<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged life</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:46:32 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>The importance of flexible deadlines in MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 13:48:59 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-04-04T17:27:17Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have always thought that having flexible deadlines in MOOCs is important,
despite not having used them too much. Until last night, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course in question is Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://statlearning.class.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning&lt;/a&gt; and they
adopted a policy of letting the students complete all the assignments of the
10 week course until the last day of the course, in March 21. Then, they
graciously extended the deadline to April 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it not for such an extension, I would not have completed the course. I
sent them a message on the course forums this morning to thank them for
this, as this, in my experience, is not so common with MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reproduce below the message that I posted on the forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Thank you also for the EXTENSION of the deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Dear professors and staff,&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you (of course) for the course, as many others have
  already. Despite not liking edX platform too much (preferring the UI of,
  say, Coursera), your course was an exception, interesting enough (and funny
  enough) that I sticked to it until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But I would like to bring attention here to a point that many may not have
  appreciated (or, perhaps, not expressed as clearly as I thought that it
  deserved), namely, the extension of the deadlines (and a uniform deadline
  for all homeworks).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, due to some unfortunate facts of my personal life, I could
  not work on the course at all in the past few weeks. In fact, I completed
  units 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 in the last 3 or 4 days and submitted my
  last quiz a few hours before today&#39;s midnight (at my local time, UTC-0300),
  and I still got a passing grade(!).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Even with my desire to finish the course, this would not have been
  possible if you had not graciously allowed for the deadline extension. I am
  sure that I may not be alone here in appreciating this extension (even
  though I think that I may be many standard deviations from the mean, doing
  the homework and R programs of 7 weeks in only 4 days).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Thank you so very much for everything (including this extension!),&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Rogério Brito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 02:35:11 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-03-03T05:38:09Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-03-30</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-30/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-30/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-03-13T22:46:32Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been (re-)discovering multimedia and all its wonders. It all
started with me seeing how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macmini/frontrow.html&quot;&gt;Front Row&lt;/a&gt; application
works. Ok, so I am behind the times. I&#39;m fine with that, but
catching up. The world is changing sooooo fast that it is hard to
keep up. Podcasts, wireless networks, media centers, digital video,
digital (still) cameras, megapixels and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add to that the things that &quot;need to be known&quot; by a Computer
Scientist/Mathematician-wannabe and we quickly arrive at the
conclusion that the days are way too short with their current 24
hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It, unfortunately, sucks and the fact that Apple is now &quot;changing
gears&quot; to support their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intel.com/&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macmini/intelcore.html&quot;&gt;Core&lt;/a&gt; processors is a
clear signal that their PowerPC line is dead and only waiting for
its coffin to be burried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the solution to this problem is? Partially, to employ Open
Source technology to leverage this to current standards, using
hardware that is already employed. We can &lt;em&gt;hardly&lt;/em&gt;, expect the new
machines to outnumber the installed resources that we already have.
And have to keep working.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-03-16</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-16/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-16/</link>



	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-03-13T22:46:32Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I resurrected Loreena McKennitt&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mask_and_Mirror&quot;&gt;&quot;The Mask and Mirror&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
and it now plays without skipping in any place. It&#39;s so nice to
have it &quot;back&quot;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m slowly progressing towards a better condition of my throat.
This is taking longer than what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally took some time to go to the police station to register the
damage done to my car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I got some new toys to play with, including a brand new
Firewire enclosure, wireless stuff and some DVD-R&#39;s. Fun ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-03-03</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-03/</link>



	<category>data-structures</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>math</category>

	<category>teaching</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-03-13T22:46:32Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;One good thing to have in mind is that when one is minimally
serious about data structures, then on covering the topic of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table&quot;&gt;hash tables&lt;/a&gt;, it is a
quite good chance to talk about the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birthday_paradox&quot;&gt;&quot;birthday paradox&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.
In the analogy, each day would correspond to a slot in the hash
table and each person would correspond to an item to be inserted
into the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one takes this into account, the analysis of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birthday_paradox#Collision_counting&quot;&gt;collisions&lt;/a&gt;
is meaninful from a probabilistic point of view, which matters a
lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the subject a little, in a replacement that lasted, say,
15 minutes (tops), the cable modem is back again working, which
means that playing with &lt;a href=&quot;http://lartc.org/&quot;&gt;tunneling&lt;/a&gt; under
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; (especially, using the IPSec
interface) is back again a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it seems that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntulinux.org&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/releases&quot;&gt;dapper&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;mom proof&quot;.
Well, at least, she has been learning to use it with some hiccups,
but, then, personal computers aren&#39;t things with which she plays
everyday. She was surprised to know about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikipedia.org/&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and its broad coverage. And,
indeed, it is superb.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-03-02</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-02/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-02/</link>



	<category>isp</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-03-13T22:46:32Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Nice. Let&#39;s see if this MathML thing works as intended:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;math xmlns=&quot;&amp;mathml;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/mfrac&gt;
&lt;/math&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, actually, it does. But only after I changed the extension of
the file from html to xhtml. What a crazy thing is this? What is
the purpose of that damned XML header on this file? Isn&#39;t it to
tell the damn server that this is an XML file? I suppose that the
server here may be broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and talking about broken things, my
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flash.net.br/&quot;&gt;cable modem&lt;/a&gt; just got fried after
today&#39;s thunderstorm. Wow. Nice to have a backup plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-02-24</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-24/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-24/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>photography</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-03-13T22:46:32Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Still trying to learn about digital photography. The subject is
fascinating. Too bad that I lack subjects to take pictures from,
but I guess that this is where the &quot;artistic&quot; part comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the is also the &quot;science&quot; part of the thing, which is
where the knowledge comes in: choosing exposure, knowing what
lenses you should (or should not) use, seeing the appropriate flash
light settings etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, many things are written in market-speak and it is
almost impenetrable for a layman to know exactly what is being
talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I upgraded
&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.matrox.com/pub/mga/archive/bios/2005/setup_258.exe&quot;&gt;the firmware&lt;/a&gt;
of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.matrox.com/&quot;&gt;Matrox&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.matrox.com/mga/support/user_manuals/mill_g400/home.cfm&quot;&gt;G400&lt;/a&gt;
card to version 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I didn&#39;t know why my students were all excited to go home until
I realized that today was the first day of 2006&#39;s carnival.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-02-23</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-23/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-23/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>photography</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>teaching</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-03-13T22:46:32Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Learning a bit more regarding photography in general. For instance,
now I know the difference between
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyphoto.com/journalism/phototip_nine.html&quot;&gt;Slow Synchro&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;nighttime&quot;)&lt;/em&gt;
and
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.storyphoto.com/journalism/phototip_five.html&quot;&gt;Fill&lt;/a&gt; (&quot;forced&quot;)&lt;/em&gt;
flash. It will be nice to be able to use them both when the
situations arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A student of mine has lent me his &quot;Towers of Hanoi&quot; puzzle so that
I can teach recursion for some students. The fact that recursion
works so well for some cases seems to be surprising (like
&lt;a href=&quot;http://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/&quot;&gt;magic&lt;/a&gt; or wizardry, sometimes) for
some students. They are not used to simple and elegant solutions to
some problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much, Victor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-02-22</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-22/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-22/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-05-16T03:48:19Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that dad is with a quite fragile health. I hope very
dearly that he has a better luck than my grandfather and doesn&#39;t
need a surgery (since we would all be scared of that, anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got the material for the first series of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dw-world.de/&quot;&gt;Deutsche Welle&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dw-world.de/dw/0,2142,2595,00.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Deutsch: Warum Nicht?&quot;&lt;/a&gt;
course (which I had already printed) bound. It will be much better
to follow the stories and exercises this way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-02-21</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-21/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-02-21/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>teaching</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2006 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-05-16T03:48:19Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Got sick and went to the hospital. Unfortunately, I could&#39;t go to
work. This has possibly messed with my schedule, but what exactly
could I do? I&#39;m voiceless and the medications that I took gave me
allergic reactions. These times have been a bit unfortunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still have to go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/&quot;&gt;IME&lt;/a&gt; to study Abstract
Algebra (in an undergraduate level, but who cares?), get the last
parcel of my payment and the finals of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~rbrito/verao/2006&quot;&gt;the Summer Course&lt;/a&gt;
(which I have to grade soon).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
