<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged life</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 22:57:39 -0200</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>The importance of flexible deadlines in MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 13:48:59 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-04-04T16:49:20Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have always thought that having flexible deadlines in MOOCs is important,
despite not having used them too much. Until last night, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course in question is Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://statlearning.class.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning&lt;/a&gt; and they
adopted a policy of letting the students complete all the assignments of the
10 week course until the last day of the course, in March 21. Then, they
graciously extended the deadline to April 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it not for such an extension, I would not have completed the course. I
sent them a message on the course forums this morning to thank them for
this, as this, in my experience, is not so common with MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reproduce below the message that I posted on the forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Thank you also for the EXTENSION of the deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Dear professors and staff,&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you (of course) for the course, as many others have
  already. Despite not liking edX platform too much (preferring the UI of,
  say, Coursera), your course was an exception, interesting enough (and funny
  enough) that I sticked to it until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But I would like to bring attention here to a point that many may not have
  appreciated (or, perhaps, not expressed as clearly as I thought that it
  deserved), namely, the extension of the deadlines (and a uniform deadline
  for all homeworks).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, due to some unfortunate facts of my personal life, I could
  not work on the course at all in the past few weeks. In fact, I completed
  units 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 in the last 3 or 4 days and submitted my
  last quiz a few hours before today&#39;s midnight (at my local time, UTC-0300),
  and I still got a passing grade(!).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Even with my desire to finish the course, this would not have been
  possible if you had not graciously allowed for the deadline extension. I am
  sure that I may not be alone here in appreciating this extension (even
  though I think that I may be many standard deviations from the mean, doing
  the homework and R programs of 7 weeks in only 4 days).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Thank you so very much for everything (including this extension!),&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Rogério Brito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 02:35:11 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-03-03T05:35:23Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-01-06</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-01-06/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-01-06/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>kernel</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>programming</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:57:39Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;There is an amazing discussion about compiler optimizations going
on right now at the lkml. It all began with Ingo Molnar&#39;s patches
to improve &lt;code&gt;.text&lt;/code&gt; size with GCC 4 compilers. Really quite
informative to see both the pros and cons of using the &lt;code&gt;inline&lt;/code&gt;
keyword of the C compilers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, by the way, while the discussion reached the consensus that
using &lt;code&gt;inline&lt;/code&gt; in abundance is a problem, it reminded me that
people should use &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; for functions that are meant to be used
only in the compilation unit where they appear. This way, GCC is
even able reduce the size of the generated binaries (not exactly
sure if this would impact the running size of the binaries---I
still have to investigate that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so tired today that I slept for about 16h. I needed that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2006-01-05</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-01-05/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-01-05/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>teaching</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:55:35Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Some amazing new packages are coming into Debian&#39;s testing
distribution. What a great time to live using Free Software only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I &quot;bribed&quot; Alexandre to get him to see one of my classes,
where covered recursion and the Towers of Hanoi Problem. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:-)&quot; /&gt; He
told me that the class was &quot;unusual&quot;. I have yet to ask him what
exactly about it was unusual, but it seems that he thought that it
wasn&#39;t bad. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:-)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-30</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-30/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-30/</link>



	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:54:43Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Had a quite pleasant dinner with a friend of mine and his lovely
wife. It seems that we have countless subjects to talk about and
that we&#39;ll never run out of things to say... Too bad that the days
have only 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-26</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-26/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-26/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>dvds</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:52:28Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Still encoding the videos. It seems that the work will finally be
done today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I discovered that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/&quot;&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt; has some quite interesting
articles; much better (and more informative than
&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/&quot;&gt;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-25</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-25/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-25/</link>



	<category>audio</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>dvds</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:51:10Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Still encoding the videos. Some surprise here, because it seems
that &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/toolame&quot;&gt;toolame&lt;/a&gt; has some bug
when encoding audio in some cases. Had to fix some of the MPEGs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I did that, I took some moments to fix some of the audio
deficiencies with &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/audacity&quot;&gt;audacity&lt;/a&gt;.
Too bad that Audacity doesn&#39;t have a Treeble booster filter built
right into it, but only a generic (and harder to use) Equalization
filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it seems that Christian Marillat has packaged version 1.8.0
of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mjpeg.sf.net/&quot;&gt;mjpegtools&lt;/a&gt;, while I&#39;m still using
version 1.6.2. I don&#39;t want to switch right now, for consistency
purposes with the videos that I already have encoded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, yes, still encoding videos. It is quite slow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-24</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-24/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-24/</link>



	<category>dvds</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:50:38Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;So, we had this Christmas dinner here at home with my mother&#39;s
grandma, two uncles and an aunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grandma wanted to see Bram Stoker&#39;s &quot;Dracula&quot;, but she was asleep
right there in the first few moments...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I&#39;m still encoding the MIT videos. This time it seems that
everything will fit onto exactly one Dual-Layer DVD+R.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-23</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-23/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-23/</link>



	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:49:34Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Went out in a manner that I didn&#39;t before. It was quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-21</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-21/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-21/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>dvds</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>study</category>

	<category>video</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:49:19Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;So, I have finally gotten some free time for my own projects! Wow!
It was a quite hectic semester this one. Fortunately, it&#39;s over
now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As previously hinted, I have now started (&lt;em&gt;slowly&lt;/em&gt;) learling
German, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dw-world.de/&quot;&gt;Deutsche Welle&lt;/a&gt; (and to
a hint given by student of mine; thanks Victor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the subject completely, creating DVDs under Linux is
really, really simple, given the proper tools. Right now, I&#39;m using
the following (quite simple) script to generate the material that
is later processed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdauthor.sf.net/&quot;&gt;dvdauthor&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh

# Chamada: &amp;lt;video_in&amp;gt; &amp;lt;video_out&amp;gt;
#

# video encoding
[ -e stream.yuv ] || mkfifo stream.yuv
mplayer -noframedrop -vo yuv4mpeg -ao pcm &amp;#036;1 &amp;amp;

yuvdenoise -v 0 -r 16 -l 4 &amp;lt; stream.yuv | \
    yuvscaler -v 0 -n n -M BICUBIC -O VCD | \
    mpeg2enc -v 0 -f 8 -b 6000 -K kvcd -g 6 -G 18 -N 1.0 -V 500 -n n -F 4 -a 2 -q 2 -4 1 -2 1 -D 10 -B 160 -o &amp;#036;2.mpv

# audio encoding
toolame -t 2 -b 160 -v -5 audiodump.wav &amp;#036;2.mpa

# multiplexing
mplex -o !!mathjaxbegin-i!! Mi5tcGcgLWYgOCAtViA=
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;!!mathjaxend-i!!2.mpv $2.mpa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# clean-up
rm -f audiodump.wav *.mpv *.mpa stream.yuv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
