<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged life</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 13:49:20 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>The importance of flexible deadlines in MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 13:48:59 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-04-04T16:49:20Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have always thought that having flexible deadlines in MOOCs is important,
despite not having used them too much. Until last night, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course in question is Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://statlearning.class.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning&lt;/a&gt; and they
adopted a policy of letting the students complete all the assignments of the
10 week course until the last day of the course, in March 21. Then, they
graciously extended the deadline to April 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it not for such an extension, I would not have completed the course. I
sent them a message on the course forums this morning to thank them for
this, as this, in my experience, is not so common with MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reproduce below the message that I posted on the forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Thank you also for the EXTENSION of the deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Dear professors and staff,&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you (of course) for the course, as many others have
  already. Despite not liking edX platform too much (preferring the UI of,
  say, Coursera), your course was an exception, interesting enough (and funny
  enough) that I sticked to it until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But I would like to bring attention here to a point that many may not have
  appreciated (or, perhaps, not expressed as clearly as I thought that it
  deserved), namely, the extension of the deadlines (and a uniform deadline
  for all homeworks).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, due to some unfortunate facts of my personal life, I could
  not work on the course at all in the past few weeks. In fact, I completed
  units 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 in the last 3 or 4 days and submitted my
  last quiz a few hours before today&#39;s midnight (at my local time, UTC-0300),
  and I still got a passing grade(!).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Even with my desire to finish the course, this would not have been
  possible if you had not graciously allowed for the deadline extension. I am
  sure that I may not be alone here in appreciating this extension (even
  though I think that I may be many standard deviations from the mean, doing
  the homework and R programs of 7 weeks in only 4 days).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Thank you so very much for everything (including this extension!),&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Rogério Brito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 02:35:11 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-03-03T05:35:23Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-12-14</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-14/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-14/</link>



	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-04-18T21:09:53Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ich bin müde.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-04-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-04/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>teaching</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I hate midterms. I hate finals. I hate preparing them. I hate
scoring them. I have to discover an easier way to evaluate my
student&#39;s acquired abilities without something as painful as
scoring those tests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-04-03</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-03/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>opeth</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo! Finally, I finished the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com/&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt;
bootleg from 2004-02-27. The setlist is absolutely amazing! Beyond
believable!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-04-01</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-01/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-01/</link>



	<category>google</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I hate the &quot;April Fool&#39;s Day&quot;, since one can&#39;t believe in anything
that is broadcast via media. The good news, though, is that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gmail.com&quot;&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt;
has now upgraded the storage it allows for its accounts to 2GB,
which is not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-03-26</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-26/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-26/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>movies</category>

	<category>music</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Had the pleasant experience of watching &quot;Constantine&quot;. The
comparisons with &quot;The Exorcist&quot; are obvious here, even though this
one is a nice movie. BTW, it seems that after the Matrix series,
Keanu Reeves is doomed to Sci-Fi movies with lots of special
effects. It&#39;s not a bad thing, nor a good thing. Just an
observation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trivia:&lt;/em&gt; It was a pleasant surprise to see (humm, hear actually)
that David Brubeck&#39;s Quarted &quot;Take Five&quot; was on the soundtrack. Oh,
and they insist on putting a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&quot;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; on the movie. That is
simply tempting. This is not the first movie that I see where
something made by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; appears on the big
screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, going to the supermarket after the movie was also quite
nice, if you know what I mean. And the pleasant company was also
highly appreciated. It couldn&#39;t be much better that this (really).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-01-06</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-01-06/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-01-06/</link>



	<category>algorithms</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>programming</category>

	<category>teaching</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Started the new Summer Course on Topics on Programming. A great
opportunity to get the things &quot;the right way&quot; and put an
introduction on Mathematical Induction, on Recursion and on
Algorithm/Loop Invariants, since they aren&#39;t covered in details for
novices in any of the books that I know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-12-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-12-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-12-04/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2004 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;No scholarship, no
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.newcastle.edu.au/~nbi/&quot;&gt;Ph.D. in Oz&lt;/a&gt;. Again, why
have things gone so wrong in the last few days?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-12-01</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-12-01/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-12-01/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Santa, I&#39;ve been a good kid for ages. Why can&#39;t I have the
things that I wished for? I&#39;d love to have a SO with stress on the
&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;. Why have things gone &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; wrong nowadays?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, finally, anyway, my TOEFL scores have arrived at the proper
department at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newcastle.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Oz&lt;/a&gt;. Now, only a few
documents are pending to know if I can get a Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than anything else, I&#39;d really like to be happier. But I
am not. Life is painful right now. And to fit my current mood, I&#39;ve
been listening to Monolithe, Shape of Despair, Skepticism and The
3rd and the Mortal. Beautiful music.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
