<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged life</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2014-06-11T14:08:07Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>The importance of flexible deadlines in MOOCs</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-04-04_flexible_deadlines_in_moocs/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="mooc" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2014-04-04T16:49:20Z</updated>
	<published>2014-04-04T16:48:59Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I have always thought that having flexible deadlines in MOOCs is important,
despite not having used them too much. Until last night, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course in question is Stanford&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://statlearning.class.stanford.edu&quot;&gt;Statistical Learning&lt;/a&gt; and they
adopted a policy of letting the students complete all the assignments of the
10 week course until the last day of the course, in March 21. Then, they
graciously extended the deadline to April 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were it not for such an extension, I would not have completed the course. I
sent them a message on the course forums this morning to thank them for
this, as this, in my experience, is not so common with MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reproduce below the message that I posted on the forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Thank you also for the EXTENSION of the deadlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Dear professors and staff,&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;I would like to thank you (of course) for the course, as many others have
  already. Despite not liking edX platform too much (preferring the UI of,
  say, Coursera), your course was an exception, interesting enough (and funny
  enough) that I sticked to it until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;But I would like to bring attention here to a point that many may not have
  appreciated (or, perhaps, not expressed as clearly as I thought that it
  deserved), namely, the extension of the deadlines (and a uniform deadline
  for all homeworks).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;In particular, due to some unfortunate facts of my personal life, I could
  not work on the course at all in the past few weeks. In fact, I completed
  units 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 in the last 3 or 4 days and submitted my
  last quiz a few hours before today&#39;s midnight (at my local time, UTC-0300),
  and I still got a passing grade(!).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Even with my desire to finish the course, this would not have been
  possible if you had not graciously allowed for the deadline extension. I am
  sure that I may not be alone here in appreciating this extension (even
  though I think that I may be many standard deviations from the mean, doing
  the homework and R programs of 7 weeks in only 4 days).&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Thank you so very much for everything (including this extension!),&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Rogério Brito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/"/>






	<category term="android" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="mooc" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2014-03-03T05:35:23Z</updated>
	<published>2014-03-03T05:35:11Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-12-14</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-14/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-12-14/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2013-04-18T21:09:53Z</updated>
	<published>2005-12-14T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Ich bin müde.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-06-20</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-20/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-20/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:08:07Z</updated>
	<published>2005-06-20T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Ugh! Just having the thought of having to teach Object-Oriented
Databases gives me headaches---I haven&#39;t dealt with Databases for
quite some time and seeing yet another paradigm would just be
insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I finally got the chance to (successfully) use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fuse.sf.net&quot;&gt;FUSE&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/&quot;&gt;Andrew Morton&#39;s Linux Tree&lt;/a&gt; so that I
could finally use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.jones.name/google-hacks/gmail-filesystem/gmail-filesystem.html&quot;&gt;gmailfs&lt;/a&gt;
with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing/&quot;&gt;testing&lt;/a&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes a real mess on your account. So, I would advise you o
create a dummy account if you intend to use it &quot;seriously&quot; (and
don&#39;t forget to encrypt what you think is sensitive information).
But it is a damn nice hack.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-06-19</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-19/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-19/"/>






	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="latex" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:07:11Z</updated>
	<published>2005-06-19T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Feelling extremely bad today. I have an enormous headache. I think
that I will work a little bit on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;, but I don&#39;t know if I
will be able to commit anything today. I can&#39;t really concentrate
and I don&#39;t want to release something that I am not proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, BTW, been swamped by e-mail. Please, stop the madness! I
can understand why Donald Knuth quit this 15 years ago. I
understand that he must be a happier man without Internet annoying
him (especially since he is such a precious celebrity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funnier thing is that people rarely realize how they are doing
things backwards today: they are working more for the computer than
the computer is working for them. They don&#39;t care about things
being automated, which is one thing where computers shine at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I think that such things are the way they are due to the
ignorance of the potential of a computer. Indeed, there are tasks
that a computer can&#39;t embrace (the halting problem, the tiling
problem etc already told us this), but for other mundane things,
computers are useful. Just not the way people seem to be using
them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this, BTW, includes people with high education (like many
Ph.D.&#39;s that I know): they simply don&#39;t make their life easier. One
example of this in action: using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latex-project.org/&quot;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; is a way of producing
high-quality documents. But some people that are actually convinced
that LaTeX is the way to go rarely take the time to use this tool
in all its usefulness. What a pity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I see people doing wrong things, I tell them a better way.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~lymber/&quot;&gt;Very few&lt;/a&gt; seem to understand that,
but others don&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, Linus released a new
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org&quot;&gt;kernel&lt;/a&gt;, 2.6.12.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-06-11</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-11/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-11/"/>






	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:05:18Z</updated>
	<published>2005-06-11T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I think that I need a person who can be a confident. I think that I
need a loyal company. I think that I need a person that can excite
me. I think that I need a person that can teach me things. I think
that I need a person to whom I can teach some new things. I think
that this perfect person would be a girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-06-10</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-10/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-10/"/>






	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:04:41Z</updated>
	<published>2005-06-10T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;This moment of the year is just hectic. Having to prepare the
finals is a bad moment, but scoring them is really terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and just as a reminder to myself, to use the subversion tree on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;BerliOS&lt;/a&gt; for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de&quot;&gt;my project/algorithms&lt;/a&gt;, I have to
use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export SVN_SSH=&quot;ssh -l myusername&quot;
svn co svn+ssh://svn.berlios.de/svnroot/repos/algorithms/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep forgetting that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I am almost complete with the syllabus of the Linux course.
There is so much that I want to cover that the course will have to
be broken in modules. Four or five modules, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-06-04</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-04/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-04/"/>






	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:02:14Z</updated>
	<published>2005-06-04T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Today I bought some books at Pearson Education. They were not that
cheap, but I think that some of their content is worth the amount
spent. During the time I was there, BTW, I met 8 colleagues (at
least, that I could count). So much for coincidence. &lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/life/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:-)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to Santa Ifigênia to get myself an used Duron
1.3GHz processor (actually, I went there to get conductive ink so
that I could overclock my Duron 600MHz processor). Unfortunately, I
can&#39;t make it work with anything higher than 1.1GHz on my
motherboard (an old classic Asus A7V). Bummer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spent the whole day trying to make my system work as it always did.
I now suspect that I need some RAM, but I am not forking the cash
for PC133 modules right now (my budget is now tight).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-05-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-30/"/>






	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:01:07Z</updated>
	<published>2005-05-30T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I think that I have fallen in love with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afterforever.com/new/pages/photos/pinkpop04/original/16.JPG&quot;&gt;Floor&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afterforever.com/new/pages/photos/pinkpop04/original/11.JPG&quot;&gt;Jansen&lt;/a&gt;.
Or would that be
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.within-temptation.com.br/info/integrantes/sharon.htm&quot;&gt;Sharon den Adel&lt;/a&gt;?
Or would that be Anneke van Giersbergen? Or would that be Liv
Kristine? Or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tarjaturunen.com/&quot;&gt;Tarja Turunen&lt;/a&gt;? I
sincerely don&#39;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, the floppy drive of my Desktop has decided to be
deceased, unfortunately. I &quot;fixed&quot; the problem by cannibalizing my
old 486 and getting its floopy drive to serve as a substitute.
Worked like a charm! It is a pain to have to open both machines and
to get the hands dirty, but at least, it seems that I am not a
Computer Scientist that doesn&#39;t even know how to fix his own
boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I wrote a little bit more regarding the Linux course that I
will teach at my local University. The program is getting huge and
I will probably be covering things that are not very well
documented (yes, I&#39;ll have to study such topics), but it will be
rewarding for the students (and among such &quot;students&quot; of mine I
will have many co-workers!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to make such a course be sufficient for certification
purposes of those that will be taking it. Of course, with a twist
and a high dose of Unix philosophy (which is good anyway, for
everybody).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Debian never ceases to amaze me! I have just discovered a
very handy packaged called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/freepops&quot;&gt;freepops&lt;/a&gt; that lets me
download my mail from my old account at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mail.com/&quot;&gt;mail.com&lt;/a&gt; via pop3. Quite nice to be able to
use that address again. And also as a bonus, it also acts as a
front-end for &lt;a href=&quot;http://mail.yahoo.com/&quot;&gt;mail.yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;, which means
that I am again able to read my mail there (again via pop3). So
nice that I can&#39;t even describe how happy I am.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-05-27</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-27/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-27/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="life" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T13:57:22Z</updated>
	<published>2005-05-27T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Went to the physician to see if I needed new glasses. Even her was
surprised when she saw the results of the tests: I will have to be
subject to more tests as what she saw wan&#39;t sufficient for a
decision: my right eye&#39;s retina may have some damage. I don&#39;t
know if I am happy about this result or not, but it finally seems
to be on track of being diagnosed.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
