<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged movies</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/movies/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/movies/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/movies/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>2005-03-26</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-26/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-03-26/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="movies" />

	<category term="music" />


	<updated>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</updated>
	<published>2005-03-26T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Had the pleasant experience of watching &quot;Constantine&quot;. The
comparisons with &quot;The Exorcist&quot; are obvious here, even though this
one is a nice movie. BTW, it seems that after the Matrix series,
Keanu Reeves is doomed to Sci-Fi movies with lots of special
effects. It&#39;s not a bad thing, nor a good thing. Just an
observation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trivia:&lt;/em&gt; It was a pleasant surprise to see (humm, hear actually)
that David Brubeck&#39;s Quarted &quot;Take Five&quot; was on the soundtrack. Oh,
and they insist on putting a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&quot;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; on the movie. That is
simply tempting. This is not the first movie that I see where
something made by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; appears on the big
screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, going to the supermarket after the movie was also quite
nice, if you know what I mean. And the pleasant company was also
highly appreciated. It couldn&#39;t be much better that this (really).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-09-16</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-09-16/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-09-16/"/>






	<category term="movies" />


	<updated>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</updated>
	<published>2001-09-16T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Got up late (3pm) and went to the shopping mall intending to see
Kubrick&#39;s &quot;AI&quot;, but got there after the session had already
started. Since we had to leave soon, we opted to see &quot;O Dom da
Premonição&quot; (&quot;The Gift&quot;) which was one of the few movies that I
have seen lately that was actually a bit scary. And it was quite
worth the price of admission.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-15</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-15/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-15/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="movies" />


	<updated>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-15T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Went to my SO&#39;s home to finish watching the unnamed movie and to
see The Matrix. Had a great time with her, her parents, her brother
and one of her sisters.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2001-07-14</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-14/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-07-14/"/>






	<category term="movies" />

	<category term="opeth" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-05-08T00:29:21Z</updated>
	<published>2001-07-14T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a day! I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; tired that I woke up at (almost) 5pm.
And, surprise: no light. Yes, a power outage. Anyway, my parents
weren&#39;t at home and I found a note that mom left on my computer&#39;s
keyboard telling me that they were shopping around. Then, I
discovered two new boxes at home: a brand new TV set and a new VCR.
The first time in 5 or 6 months that would be able to see my
amazing tape of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opeth.com&quot;&gt;Opeth&lt;/a&gt; playing at Milwaukee
Metalfest. Woohoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But without power, my main concern was to be able to &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; anything
before the day became too dark. After half an hour (or was it an
hour?) trying to find some candles and fire, my parents arrived and
two hours later, I was watching &quot;As Good As It Gets&quot;. Cool movie,
BTW. Excellent acting of both Helen Hunt and Jack Nicholson (mom
told me that I act like him most of the time -- is that
compliment?).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2000-09-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2000-09-30/"/>






	<category term="life" />

	<category term="movies" />


	<updated>2012-12-09T02:51:00Z</updated>
	<published>2000-09-30T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Today it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~lymber/&quot;&gt;Alexandre&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s birthday!
Happy birthday, pal! Too bad we&#39;re not together today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally went to catch a flick: &quot;What Lies Beneath&quot; (in Portuguese,
&quot;Premonição&quot;). It was supposed to be scary. Ok. Some parts were.
Came back home rightly after the movie was done (which means that
I&#39;d like to get home not so fast next time).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
