<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged perl</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/perl/</link>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 18:23:31 -0300</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>2002-01-01</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-01-01/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-01-01/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hardware</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>macos</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, some progress on the PPC front. I&#39;ve just configured the PMac
to use the &lt;code&gt;imstt&lt;/code&gt; driver instead of the &lt;code&gt;fbdev&lt;/code&gt;. Due to this, the
X server is now &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster. In fact, the whole computer is much
faster. Before, it spent a lot of processing power just to update
the screen. Since it is not exactly the most powerful computer in
the world, those few moments indeed were important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very fast and now it is almost able to play AVI files with
MPlayer. Almost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Mac is now very usable and I&#39;d even dare to say that it would
be a good workstation, were it not that outdated (well, if one
could find replacement hardware for it easily...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&#39;ll end summarizing all the &quot;Mac Journey&quot; in a homepage
to save future souls enduring the problems that I&#39;ve experienced
(kernel configuration file, XF86Config file etc). It seems that
Linux running on PPC is indeed a quite nice alternative to paying
huge prices just for being able to run MacOS 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also installed the superb
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mosfet.org/liquid.html&quot;&gt;Liquid Theme&lt;/a&gt; for KDE2. It&#39;s
amazingly beautiful and quite fast, despite all the eye-candy. It
makes your Linux desktop seem like you are running
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&#39;s Acqua&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the down side of things, I guess that I&#39;m just encountering many
aspects of Perl that I don&#39;t like. It&#39;s saddening that I&#39;ve spent
so much time and money (buying books) for something that I&#39;m not
really enjoying (but it&#39;s ok).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2001-12-12</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-12/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-12/</link>



	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>macos</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of things going on. I&#39;m now even more sure that I do want one
of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ibook/&quot;&gt;new and sweet iBooks&lt;/a&gt;. They
are so sweet, come with a long-lasting battery, have a 1024x768 res
LCD, a Firewire port, a 10/100 Ethernet port, a reasonably big HD
and an ATI card. In my opinion, it&#39;s only drawback: it doesn&#39;t have
a PCMCIA slot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added bonus, what could be cooler than Apple now selling its
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;new Operating System&lt;/a&gt; as the
&quot;World&#39;s Most Advanced Operating System&quot;, when, in fact, it is a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/darwin/&quot;&gt;Unix&lt;/a&gt; under the hood?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tuxppc.org/&quot;&gt;runs Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! Not only that, but
if I ever get tired of Linux and want MacOS X, I can have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fink.sf.net&quot;&gt;it with the power of Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But well, there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; another drawback. Nothing can be perfect. Of
course. These things are so damn expensive here in my country,
mostly due to the absurd exchange rates and to the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.receita.fazenda.gov.br&quot;&gt;huge taxes&lt;/a&gt;. Anything that
isn&#39;t obtained with the welcome, kind help of the &quot;gray markets&quot; is
so damn expensive (to the point of quickly becoming intangible).
Which means that I&#39;ll probably not have one iBook unless I go
travel and come back with one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learned a bit more about Perl. Became a bit scared with the amound
of things it does at run-time. Isn&#39;t there a switch for the
compiler/optimizer to tell it: &quot;perform only what I tell you and
optimize the hell out of this code&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2001-12-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2001-12-04/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>perl</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2001 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-06T21:23:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Um dia um pouco inútil. Acordei mais tarde do que o usual (17h) e
fui ler os sites de costume (&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/&quot;&gt;slashdot.org&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/daily/&quot;&gt;LWN Daily Updates&lt;/a&gt; e
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agestado.com.br/agestado/?rf&quot;&gt;Agência Estado&lt;/a&gt;). A
propósito, eu gosto tanto do Agência Estado (principalmente da
cobertura econômica, dos comentários acessíveis ao público leigo em
economia e do uso de poucos plugins nas páginas -- muito melhor do
que a &lt;a href=&quot;http://noticias.uol.com.br/ultnot/&quot;&gt;concorrência&lt;/a&gt;) que uma
das coisas que eu mais gostaria de ver seria um canal de RSS com as
notícias para eu usar em algum cliente
(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ximian.com/images/screenshots/ximian_evolution/summary.png&quot;&gt;Evolution&lt;/a&gt;,
junto com a temperatura e resumos de outros sites) e não perder
mais tempo na Web do que eu já perco. Entretanto, achar algo como
isto em algum site não é muito fácil em geral, até mesmo nos sites
que &lt;em&gt;fornecem&lt;/em&gt; os canais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solução é, portanto, fazer um script em
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perl.com&quot;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt; para transformar a página de notícias
em um canal e, daí, usar o resultado. Fiz dois scripts, um para o
UOL e outro para o Agência Estado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acho que eu tenho uma relação de amor e ódio com Perl. Hoje foi um
dia de amor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anunciei &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~rbrito/listas/bio/&quot;&gt;a lista&lt;/a&gt;,
comecei uma leitura (desordenada) de coisas sobre Alinhamentos de
Várias Seqüências e me toquei de uma coisa bem elementar mas muito
legal a respeito do algoritmo de programação dinâmica (que eu acho
que já deveria ter percebido há algum tempo -- como é bom
estudar).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
