<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged development</title>
<link>/blog/tags/development/</link>
<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<item>

	<title>First post from DebConf 10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="no">/blog/posts/first-post-from-debconf-10/</guid>

	<link>/blog/posts/first-post-from-debconf-10/</link>


	<category>/tags/debian</category>

	<category>/tags/development</category>

	<category>/tags/free-software</category>

	<category>/tags/people</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 06:09:46 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2010-11-10T09:13:35Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I am late with this post, it is nice to say that I am writing here from this year&#39;s DebConf10, in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today (well, yesterday) was the day of the Cheese and Wine party and I think that it was cool, at least for the moments that I were there. This post, though, isn&#39;t technical in any sense. I only talks shortly about my impressions of the community, as this is my first DebConf ever (despite the fact that I have been using Debian since the late nineties).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very pleased to have met Bdale Garbee. I saw him the other day arriving with Keith Packard, but I just didn&#39;t want to disturb them at that point. We only talked for, say, 2 minutes, and his was one of the nicest receptions that I had here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there were some other people that were equally easy to approach, nice to talk with and, to my surprise, knew my name after some brief moments (yes, this &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make a difference, especially when you are in a strange country, when you don&#39;t know anybody with whom you have worked for some years). Being involved in the organization stuff, one would think that Jimmy Kaplowitz would be so busy, but he was so kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had longer conversations with Tássia Camões, Tiago Vaz (as always) and some other people that I had not yet had the pleasure of meeting in person. In particular, Daniel Baumann (who apparently is now crazy about our FISL and wants to drink all Guaraná that he can get &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt;), Chris Lamb and Otávio Salvador and his mom. Those people are so cool and it is nice to discuss some legal issues among different continents in the lounge of their building at late night. &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt; Too bad that I am allocated to the other building. &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; forgetting many other people (hey, it is 2 am here in NYC), but I would feel guilty if I had not mentioned at least three people more: Martin Michlmayr, Phil Hands, and Reinhard Tartler (who is uploading lame to the debian repository, as the patents regarding it are expiring or expired already).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: I just created an account on flickr that I hope to populate with some photos that I took here. And even with a nice squirrel. &lt;code&gt;:-)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>I am going to DebConf 10</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="no">/blog/posts/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/</guid>

	<link>/blog/posts/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/</link>


	<category>/tags/debian</category>

	<category>/tags/development</category>

	<category>/tags/fonts</category>

	<category>/tags/free-software</category>

	<category>/tags/hacks</category>

	<category>/tags/powerpc</category>

	<category>/tags/web-of-trust</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 03:34:40 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2010-11-10T09:13:35Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;I just bought my tickets today to NYC and I am glady to say that I am going to Debconf 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&quot;attachment_55&quot; align=&quot;aligncenter&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; caption=&quot;I am going to DebConf10&quot;]&lt;a rel=&quot;attachment wp-att-55&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost/blog/2010/07/18/i-am-going-to-debconf-10/im_going_to_debconf10/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-55 &quot; title=&quot;im_going_to_debconf10&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/im_going_to_debconf10.png&quot; alt=&quot;I am going to DebConf10&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;101&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets have this information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRU-&amp;gt;JFK:&lt;/strong&gt; Departure: 2010-07-30, 21:25; Arrival: 2010-07-31, 6:10, Flight AA950&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JFK-&amp;gt;GRU:&lt;/strong&gt; Departure: 2010-08-09, 21:40; Arrival: 2010-08-10, 8:35, Flight AA951&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This represents a personal milestone for me, as I have many plans for the conference. In fact, this will be a trip of many &quot;firsts&quot; for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be my first international trip by airplaine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be my first DebConf ever (despite the fact that I could not apply for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://upsilon.cc/~zack/blog/posts/2010/04/the_DebConf_Newbies_initiative/&quot;&gt;DebConf Newbies initiative&lt;/a&gt;, due to my visa interview being delayed until the 7th of this month).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be the first time to see many people with whom I work together for some years now, but have not yet had the opportunity to meet in person.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a nice opportunity to work hard on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/Articles/396079/&quot;&gt;some issues that threaten the PowerPC port&lt;/a&gt; of Debian.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a nice opportunity to do some QA work with some packages that I would like to have sponsored; also to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/551955&quot;&gt;upload&lt;/a&gt; some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/580005&quot;&gt;fonts&lt;/a&gt; that I &lt;a href=&quot;http://git.debian.org/?p=pkg-fonts/ttf-paratype-sans.git&quot;&gt;already packaged&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/581839&quot;&gt;intend&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/589094&quot;&gt;take care&lt;/a&gt;) and that will be maintained under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pkg-fonts.alioth.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian Fonts Task Force umbrella&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;this will be a very nice opportunity to get myself in a &quot;big&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strongly_connected_component&quot;&gt;strongly connected component &lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_of_trust&quot;&gt;Web-of-Trust&lt;/a&gt; with as many arcs as feasible, by means of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~anibal/ksp-dc10/ksp-dc10.html&quot;&gt;key signing party.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and many, many other things that I would like to do for the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thankful for the DebConf team sponsoring both accomodation and food.  It is highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in NYC! Any hints that you may happen to have are warmly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>A version of xpdf with the poppler backend available</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="no">/blog/posts/a-version-of-xpdf-with-the-poppler-backend-available/</guid>

	<link>/blog/posts/a-version-of-xpdf-with-the-poppler-backend-available/</link>


	<category>/tags/c++</category>

	<category>/tags/debian</category>

	<category>/tags/development</category>

	<category>/tags/documents</category>

	<category>/tags/free-software</category>

	<category>/tags/hacks</category>

	<category>/tags/libraries</category>

	<category>/tags/programming</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 19:46:13 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2010-11-10T09:13:35Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&#39;s been some time since I last wrote here and things are quite hectic, due to some real-life happenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Announcement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those people that are insterested in a &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; PDF viewer, based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://poppler.freedesktop.org/&quot;&gt;an actively maintained backend&lt;/a&gt;, and that &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/blog/2010/05/27/please-let-me-zoom-my-documents/&quot;&gt;doesn&#39;t bring your computer to a halt&lt;/a&gt; when you try to zoom your documents when you need to see some details, then you might want to give &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/rbrito/xpdf-poppler&quot;&gt;this version of xpdf&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already received some reports for some bugs and fixed them, with one of them being a problem related by a kind user of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gentoo.org/&quot;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people have asked me why this even needs to exist in the first place and I agree that it would be better if it didn&#39;t: I would love to spend my time actually &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; my computers rather than &lt;em&gt;fixing&lt;/em&gt; my computers for better tasks (read: studying Mathematics, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upstream maintainer of xpdf uses it as one source of income and keeps it running across many system (even legacy ones).  I &lt;em&gt;imagine&lt;/em&gt; that this one of the reasons why he tries to keep xpdf almost self contained, with many parts that could be delegated to other libraries, and with some abstraction code that makes the code compile even in the presence of &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; broken compilers.  Of course, this means, in part, that as long as you take more duties, maintaing the code becomes more and more complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me that he doesn&#39;t offer an open development tree because he wants to give his customers some advantages over the public version and his reasons are perfectly justifiable, of course.  He also manifested the interest of possibly basing xpdf on a &quot;more modern toolkit&quot; and, when I asked him what that would be, he mentioned that, perhaps, it would be Qt. The development of xpdf will, quite probably, take newer directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, xpdf has not seen a new upstream release since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foolabs.com/xpdf/CHANGES&quot;&gt;2007-02-27&lt;/a&gt;.  It did, though, have &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl1.patch&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl2.patch&quot;&gt;patchlevel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl3.patch&quot;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl4.patch&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;. Taking care of the maintainance of the code is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/527840&quot;&gt;high concern&lt;/a&gt; for distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people, though, would like to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&quot;&gt;keep it simple&lt;/a&gt; (me included).  Unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/351279&quot;&gt;some efforts&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2010/06/msg00046.html&quot;&gt;maintain&lt;/a&gt; it had &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=289803&quot;&gt;not had&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2010/06/msg00068.html&quot;&gt;necessary coordination&lt;/a&gt; and duplication of effort has occured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am willing to become a patch aggregator for the code in xpdf with a poppler backend. I would love to give it some refactoring too, drop some of the legacy code that is not used (and only serves to make the code hard to read), and adopt some good coding style standard (I particularly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/CodingStyle&quot;&gt;like the one from the Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt;---with the proper adaptations for C++).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have already &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=323469&quot;&gt;contacted the people at Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;, and I would love to get people from Fedora, Ubuntu, and Suse involved also. Alas,  the last time I tried to mail their mailing lists, I got  messages telling me that my messages were rejected or waiting for moderation, because I was not a subscriber. I never heard back, since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate it if you could help spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
