<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged documents</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/documents/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/documents/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 22:59:01 -0200</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Packaging fonts for a Debian-based system</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/packaging-fonts-for-a-debian-based-system/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/packaging-fonts-for-a-debian-based-system/</link>



	<category>development</category>

	<category>documents</category>

	<category>fonts</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>opentype</category>

	<category>tex</category>

	<category>typography</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 11:23:55 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-15T02:23:51Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing now that the situation regarding Free fonts is much better than in
the past, I have started packaging some that are of high enough quality so
that we can have it available on our systems (be it Debian or any of the
good derivatives).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I spent some time during the past few days &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~rbrito/+archive/ppa/&quot;&gt;packaging&lt;/a&gt;
some that, I think, deserve to be mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paratype.com/public/&quot;&gt;ParaType Sans&lt;/a&gt;: this typeface family consists of a set of proportional,
sans-serif fonts that supply a lot of Cyrillic glyphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: the intention of this font is that of supporting many of the
smaller ethnic and cultural aspects present in Russia. It was even funded
by the Russian Government: in particular, by the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Agency_on_Press_and_Mass_Communications&quot;&gt;Federal Agency for Press and Mass Communications of the Russian Federation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you should care&lt;/strong&gt;: for those (like me) that use a Latin-based
alphabet, the fonts also have some nice attractives, like, besides the
usual 4 shape/weight combinations (regular, italic, bold, bold italic),
two other variants: PT Sans Narrow (with its respective bold) and PT Sans
Caption (also with bold).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, the fonts support ligatures (liga, dlig), fractions
(frac), ordinals (ordn), and glyph composition (ccmp), among &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt;
OpenType features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ms-studio.com/FontSales/anonymouspro.html&quot;&gt;Anonymous Pro&lt;/a&gt;: this typeface family consists of a set of fixed-width
fonts with the usual 4 shape/weight combinations (regular, italic, bold,
bold italic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Anonymous Pro was made with people that stare at a computer
screen, coding for long amounts of time, or people that use a terminal all
the time.  Apart from being scalable, it also features some pre-made
bitmap versions at some sizes (10, 11, 12, and 13), so that they should
look better than some automatically drawn font without proper
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Font_hinting&quot;&gt;TrueType hinting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My package still is not good enough, as I have not yet included explicit
support for the bitmapped sizes via some fontconfig configuration, but I
expect to fix those in two or three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This should just be a matter of including something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;edit name=&quot;embeddedbitmap&quot; mode=&quot;assign&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;bool&amp;gt;true&amp;lt;/bool&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/edit&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the configuration that I ship with the fonts).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scholarsfonts.net/cardofnt.html&quot;&gt;Cardo&lt;/a&gt;: this is produced by David Perry and it is a proportional,
serif, old-style typeface similar to some highly regarded fonts like
Bembo. It does not offer italic, or bold versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Cardo&#39;s target &quot;audience&quot; are scholars that need to type set
Medieval texts, it has &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; glyphs, support for many opentype features
and the author has told me that he may even provide some support for
typesetting Mathematics (and this &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a very big deal, since typesetting
Mathematics is hard enough when you decide to change your typefaces).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works quite well with Jonathan Kew&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripts.sil.org/xetex&quot;&gt;XeTeX&lt;/a&gt; and you should just try
it, especially if you are into serif fonts (like I am).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.droidfonts.com/droidfonts/&quot;&gt;Droid&lt;/a&gt;: this consists of three font families, with varying shapes and
weights, in sans-serif, sans-serif monospaced, and serif families.  It has
received a lot of press, due to it being sponsored by Google and made by
Ascender Corporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: the Droid fonts were made for Google&#39;s Android platform and
one of the main concerns was to be readable on devices with low resolution
(like computer screens). It has a very wide coverage of glyphs (as one
would expect from a font for phones) and have very high quality. A really
nice donation to the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxlibertine.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Linux Libertine&lt;/a&gt;: this has to be one of the most beautiful fonts that
I have see in a while. It has the basic four combinations of a serif font&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: to provide a beautiful, &quot;organic&quot; version of a typeface that
can substitute Times/Times New Roman. It works well both with &quot;regular&quot;
latex/pdflatex and with XeTeX (and, quite probably, with LuaTeX). It has
quite a lot of OpenType features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rbrito:~&amp;#036; otfinfo -f /usr/share/fonts/truetype/linux-libertine/LinLibertine_Re.ttf | wc -l
25
rbrito:~&amp;#036;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, I can&#39;t be impartial with this font. It is beautiful. It is a pity
that we are in a feature freeze and that a the new version
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/602845#10&quot;&gt;won&#39;t probably be included in squeeze&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/evristika/&quot;&gt;Heuristica (&quot;Эвристика&quot;)&lt;/a&gt;: since Adobe has &lt;a href=&quot;http://tug.org/fonts/utopia/LICENSE-utopia.txt&quot;&gt;donated&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utopia_%28typeface%29&quot;&gt;Utopia&lt;/a&gt;
to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tug.org/&quot;&gt;TeX Users&#39;s Group&lt;/a&gt; under a Free Software license, it was only
a matter of time that people would tweak them and generate other versions.
Then comes Andrey Panov&#39;s Heuristica, a modified version of the four basic
typefaces that Adobe donated, in OpenType format (and, to boot, some
&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/font-helpers/&quot;&gt;nice scripts for fontforge&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Heuristica improves Utopia with the primary intent of adding
Cyrillic symbols by Andrey V. Panov. Andrey has also incorporated
Vietnamese glyphs made available by Hàn Thế Thành. Heuristica is a family
that features regular and italic shapes, with both being present also in
bold weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&#39;s it for now. Stay tuned for more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>A version of xpdf with the poppler backend available</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-version-of-xpdf-with-the-poppler-backend-available/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/a-version-of-xpdf-with-the-poppler-backend-available/</link>



	<category>c++</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>development</category>

	<category>documents</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>hacks</category>

	<category>libraries</category>

	<category>programming</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 19:46:13 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-02-15T02:20:38Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it&#39;s been some time since I last wrote here and things are quite
hectic, due to some real-life happenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;announcement&quot;&gt;Announcement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those people that are insterested in a &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; PDF viewer, based on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://poppler.freedesktop.org/&quot;&gt;an actively maintained backend&lt;/a&gt;, and that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/blog/2010/05/27/please-let-me-zoom-my-documents/&quot;&gt;doesn&#39;t bring your computer to a halt&lt;/a&gt; when you try to zoom your
documents when you need to see some details, then you might want to give
&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/rbrito/xpdf-poppler&quot;&gt;this version of xpdf&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already received some reports for some bugs and fixed them, with one of
them being a problem related by a kind user of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gentoo.org/&quot;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people have asked me why this even needs to exist in the first place
and I agree that it would be better if it didn&#39;t: I would love to spend my
time actually &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; my computers rather than &lt;em&gt;fixing&lt;/em&gt; my computers for
better tasks (read: studying Mathematics, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upstream maintainer of xpdf uses it as one source of income and keeps it
running across many system (even legacy ones).  I &lt;em&gt;imagine&lt;/em&gt; that this one of
the reasons why he tries to keep xpdf almost self contained, with many parts
that could be delegated to other libraries, and with some abstraction code
that makes the code compile even in the presence of &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; broken compilers.
Of course, this means, in part, that as long as you take more duties,
maintaing the code becomes more and more complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me that he doesn&#39;t offer an open development tree because he wants
to give his customers some advantages over the public version and his
reasons are perfectly justifiable, of course.  He also manifested the
interest of possibly basing xpdf on a &quot;more modern toolkit&quot; and, when I
asked him what that would be, he mentioned that, perhaps, it would be
Qt. The development of xpdf will, quite probably, take newer directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, xpdf has not seen a new upstream release since
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foolabs.com/xpdf/CHANGES&quot;&gt;2007-02-27&lt;/a&gt;.  It did, though, have &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl1.patch&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl2.patch&quot;&gt;patchlevel&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl3.patch&quot;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;ftp://ftp.foolabs.com/pub/xpdf/xpdf-3.02pl4.patch&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;. Taking care of the maintainance of the code is a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/527840&quot;&gt;high concern&lt;/a&gt; for distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people, though, would like to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&quot;&gt;keep it simple&lt;/a&gt; (me included).
Unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.debian.org/351279&quot;&gt;some efforts&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2010/06/msg00046.html&quot;&gt;maintain&lt;/a&gt; it had &lt;a href=&quot;http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=289803&quot;&gt;not had&lt;/a&gt; the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2010/06/msg00068.html&quot;&gt;necessary coordination&lt;/a&gt; and duplication of effort has occured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am willing to become a patch aggregator for the code in xpdf with a
poppler backend. I would love to give it some refactoring too, drop some of
the legacy code that is not used (and only serves to make the code hard to
read), and adopt some good coding style standard (I particularly
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/CodingStyle&quot;&gt;like the one from the Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt;---with the proper adaptations for
C++).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have already &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/CodingStyle&quot;&gt;contacted the people at Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;, and I would love to get
people from Fedora, Ubuntu, and Suse involved also. Alas, the last time I
tried to mail their mailing lists, I got messages telling me that my
messages were rejected or waiting for moderation, because I was not a
subscriber. I never heard back, since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate it if you could help spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-10-23</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-10-23/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-10-23/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>documents</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2005 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:59:01Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today was voting day and that sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &quot;dreams&quot; of using DocBook/XML to generate my documentation
ceased to be when I read that passivetex is barely maintained. And,
actually, trying to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/xmlto&quot;&gt;xmlto&lt;/a&gt;
with a very simple document seems to generate good XHTML, but
doesn&#39;t even work when one tries to generate DVI or PS or PDF
output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I should try to use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/docbook-utils&quot;&gt;docbook-utils&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
