<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged java</title>
<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/java/</link>
<atom:link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/java/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 04:28:31 -0200</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Comparison of JDK installation of various Linux distributions</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-02_java_install_in_various_linuxes/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-02_java_install_in_various_linuxes/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 23:13:56 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2017-11-06T06:28:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I spent some time in the morning seeing how one would install the JDK
on Linux distributions. This is to create a little comparative tutorial to
teach introductory Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing the JDK is, thanks to the OpenJDK developers in Debian and Ubuntu
(Matthias Klose and helpers), a very easy task. You simply type something
like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install openjdk-8-jdk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since for a student it is better to have everything for experiments, I
install the &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/openjdk-8-jdk&quot;&gt;full version&lt;/a&gt;, not only the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/openjdk-8-jdk-headless&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;-headless&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; version. Given my familiarity with
Debian/Ubuntu, I didn&#39;t have to think about the way of installing it, of
course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as this is a tutorial meant to be as general as I can, I tried also to
include instructions on how to install Java on other distributions. The
first two that came to my mind were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfedora.org/&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both use the RPM package format for their &quot;native&quot; packages (in the same
sense that Debian uses DEB packages for &quot;native&quot; packages). But they use
different higher-level tools to install such packages: Fedora uses a tool
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/DNF&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dnf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, while openSUSE uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Zypper_usage&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;zypper&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try these distributions, I got their netinstall ISOs and used
&lt;code&gt;qemu&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;kvm&lt;/code&gt; to install on a virtual machine. I used the following to
install/run the virtual machines (the example below, is, of course, for openSUSE):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;qemu-system-x86_64 -enable-kvm -m 4096 -smp 2 -net nic,model=e1000 -net user -drive index=0,media=disk,cache=unsafe,file=suse.qcow2 -cdrom openSUSE-Leap-42.3-NET-x86_64.iso
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The names of the packages also change from one distribution to another. On
Fedora, I had to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;dnf install java-1.8.0-openjdk-devel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On openSUSE, I had to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;zypper install java-1_8_0-openjdk-devel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that one distribution uses dots in the names of the packages while the
other uses underscores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing that I noticed with &lt;code&gt;dnf&lt;/code&gt; was that, when I used it, it
automatically refreshed the package lists from the network, something which
I forgot, and it was a pleasant surprise. I don&#39;t know about &lt;code&gt;zypper&lt;/code&gt;, but I
guess that it probably had fresh indices when the installation finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both installations were effortless after I knew the names of the packages to
install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, in my 5 minute exploration with these distributions, I noticed that
if you don&#39;t want the JDK, but only the JRE, then you omit the &lt;code&gt;-devel&lt;/code&gt;
suffix.  It makes sense when you think about it, for consistency with other
packages, but Debian&#39;s conventions also make sense (JRE with &lt;code&gt;-jre&lt;/code&gt; suffix,
JDK with &lt;code&gt;-jdk&lt;/code&gt; suffix).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I failed miserably to use Fedora&#39;s prebaked, vanilla
&lt;a href=&quot;https://alt.fedoraproject.org/cloud/&quot;&gt;cloud image&lt;/a&gt;, as I couldn&#39;t login on this image and I decided
to just install the whole OS on a fresh virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have instructions on how to install on &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfedora.org/&quot;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; nor on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now see how hard it is to cover instructions/provide software for as many
distributions as you wish, given the multitude of package managers,
conventions etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>More completed MOOCs</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-03-03_more_completed_moocs/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>mooc</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 02:35:11 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-03-03T05:35:23Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I received my 17th certification (or Statement of
Accomplishment) for MOOCs. In particular, this last MOOC that I took was
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/androidapps101&quot;&gt;Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps&lt;/a&gt;, offered by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/lawrenceangrave&quot;&gt;Lawrence Angrave&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/illinois&quot;&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I certainly knew that the course was an Introduction to Programming,
the reasons I took it were twofold:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the &quot;novelty&quot; (for me, at least) of writing some Android Apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To reacquaint myself with Java, which I have not touched since 1999, when
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/old-projects&quot;&gt;I wrote a compiler&lt;/a&gt;, in the ages of JDK 1.0 being transitioned to
JDK 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the time the course took (and which I invested in) was really
well spent. In fact, I learned some nice things which I would &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have
touched otherwise. For instance, I made the conscious effort to use an IDE
(Eclipse), despite being a person that would do most of the things inside
Emacs and compile the programs with command-line tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being huge, Eclipse has some really nice features and the
auto-completion is amazing. Since Java is so strongly typed and Eclipse
knows Java pretty well, it almost completely writes your programs for you.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my interest also made me want to streamline the build process and
use the command line tools (with ant, another tool that was &quot;alien&quot; to me,
having used makefiles for everything that I needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of Eclipse (and the Android development environment in general) in
my Debian unstable computers
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/&quot;&gt;was not&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/734674&quot;&gt;without problems&lt;/a&gt;, but after spending more time trying to fix Eclipse
than really doing the homework (and pulling the little hair that I still
have left), one really helpful post &lt;a href=&quot;http://aleksz-programming.blogspot.com/2013/03/eclipse-and-webkit-on-ubuntu-64.html&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;. (Yes, I had to remove
other packages like gimp, but such is life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing with the Android side of things, I put one badly written (and
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; really &quot;android-ish&quot;) app in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/toy-android-apps&quot;&gt;a github repository&lt;/a&gt; (which I think
is aptly named &quot;Toy Android Apps&quot;), which served me the purpose of learning
some Android-specific concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the course was helpful not only to get in touch with the tools (Eclipse,
ant, running Android virtual machines with the help of kvm), but also on the
Java side. I lost a bit of the prejudice against it (even though I still
think it is a verbose language, especially when compared to, say Python),
and I, also intend to contribute to one apache project or another that have
low-hanging fruits.  Actually, I have signed their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apache.org/licenses/icla.txt&quot;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; and I even had
&lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1559792&quot;&gt;my first patch accepted&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside: Well, sadly SVN doesn&#39;t support different committer and author fields
like git does and it seems that doing many small commits may not be the
Apache way of doing things&amp;mdash;but the important part of all this is that
the code is there and there is so much more to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside #2: After a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time spent converting the repository to git
(which is, after all, what I use), I put &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/commons-graph&quot;&gt;a mirror&lt;/a&gt; of Apache&#39;s the
commons graph project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>Developing for Android with Debian</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-01-17-developing_for_android_with_debian/</link>



	<category>android</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 20:18:04 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-17T22:17:37Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have just enrolled in a MOOC to learn about programming with Android.
There are many tutorials and reports of people using Linux for the
development of the apps out there, but, unfortunately, many of them are
outdated or contain misleading information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will find bazillion instructions out there telling you to install
JDK6. (Even the instructions in the MOOCs say so, and Google says that it is
the only supported version of Java). Even more than that, some of them will
tell you that you should &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; use OpenJDK, but use Oracle&#39;s JDK instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you have a pure &lt;code&gt;amd64&lt;/code&gt; system and you try to install the x86-64
version of Google&#39;s Android Developer Tools (ADT), you are going to have a
surprise: you will have all sorts of programs telling you that you have file
not found, even though the required binaries are there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is, of course, besides install &lt;code&gt;openjdk-7-jdk&lt;/code&gt;, if you wish to use the
integrated Eclipse environment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that the so-called 64-bit ADT/SDK actually has many 32-bit
executables(!) and they aren&#39;t statically linked. Inspecting them, I needed
the following packages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    gcc-4.8-base:i386
    libc6-i686:i386
    libc6:i386
    libgcc1:i386
    libstdc++6:i386
    zlib1g:i386
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth observing that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libstdc++6:i386&lt;/code&gt; depends (transitively) on &lt;code&gt;libc6:i386&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;libgcc1:i386&lt;/code&gt;,
and &lt;code&gt;gcc-4.8-base:i386&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;zlib1g:i386&lt;/code&gt; depends (transitively) on &lt;code&gt;libc6:i386&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;libgcc1:i386&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;gcc-4.8-base:i386&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the above, and given that the version of the GCC libraries can vary a
lot, it is perhaps better to simply do something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install libstdc++6:i386 zlib1g:i386
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although not necessary, since you are using an amd64 machine, your computer
already supports many more recent instructions that will be used if you
install the package &lt;code&gt;libc6-i686:i386&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid the emulator from spitting out error messages related to &lt;code&gt;libGL.so&lt;/code&gt;,
install &lt;code&gt;libgl1-mesa-dev&lt;/code&gt; (note: &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;i386&lt;/code&gt; here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, you will be able to run the embedded QEMU with full KVM
acceleration if you pass the options &lt;code&gt;-qemu -m 1024 -enable-kvm&lt;/code&gt; on
Eclipse&#39;s &quot;Run &gt; Run Configurations... &gt; Target &gt; Additional Emulator
Command Line Options&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, you are probably good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-07-23</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-07-23/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-07-23/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:32:58Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, I forgot to say: the multithreaded applications work quite well
with the Free Java implementations available in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing&quot;&gt;testing&lt;/a&gt; distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-07-22</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-07-22/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-07-22/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:32:16Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Mom&#39;s birthday. And a nice opportunity to see some relatives here.
Quite nice to have all them together. And it wasn&#39;t free of
surprising things. Something that once would be attached to geeks
was actually the subject of conversations for a moment: the use of
Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some sense, I feel that being the pioneer of the family to have
used Internet was interesting. But, then, motivated by the recent
surgery that I &quot;survived&quot;, made me see things in a quite different
fashion: using the Internet and computers like there&#39;s no tomorrow
is a pure waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the Internet is slowly turning into the new TV. There
are obvious differences, because you are in command of (some)
things, but, to be honest, I am not exactly sure that people are
that much in control as they think that they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I have started playing with Java&#39;s multithreaded
abilities. A nice way to play with them, but the book that I have
here requires a lot of patience on my part: it is a translation of
&quot;The Java Programming Language&quot;, 1st edition. The catch is that the
stupid person that tranlated it also translated &lt;em&gt;commands&lt;/em&gt; of the
language and names of classes! Is this a contest of foolness or
what?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2005-06-28</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-28/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-06-28/</link>



	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>study</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2005 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2015-01-18T00:30:31Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I have discovered that while Linus&#39; 2.6.12 kernel seems OK with my
IDE HD in the Firewire enclosure, both of Andrew Morton&#39;s &lt;code&gt;-mm1&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;-mm2&lt;/code&gt; trees are broken regarding the device. I posted to the lkml
and got some nice responses. That&#39;s one of the reasons why Open
Source Software is good: you can actually get in touch with people
responsible for fixing things without &quot;the middle man&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have been chaotically reading about &lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;,
since I am excited by all the progress that the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kaffe.org/&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sablevm.org/&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gcc.gnu.org/java/&quot;&gt;Implementations&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jikes.sf.net/&quot;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; Java have shown recently. It seems that
the major milestone now is to improve the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/classpath/&quot;&gt;Classpath&lt;/a&gt; project. Every
other JVM would benefit from a bigger implementation of the Java
API from GNU Classpath, if I understand things correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I said that I was chaotically reading about Java, I meant the
first edition of James Gosling&#39;s book (that&#39;s the only one that I
have here). Unfortunately, the translation that I have is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; full
of &lt;strong&gt;atrocious&lt;/strong&gt; errors that it is a disservice to an otherwise
fine book (even if somewhat outdated).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and by chaotically reading things, I also meant reading about
how &lt;a href=&quot;http://subversion.tigris.org/&quot;&gt;Subversion&lt;/a&gt; 1.1 works, so that
I can better manage &lt;a href=&quot;http://algorithms.berlios.de/&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-11-09</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-09/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-09/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>life</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2004 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-24T06:56:59Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;What a strange year this one has been. I was almost killed today in
a car accident. Modulo some pain and the lack of a car, everything
is fine right now. But I wished that everything were slightly
different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the good news front,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&quot;&gt;Firefox 1.0&lt;/a&gt; was
released today, which is one of the most anticipated software
releases of the year. Nice to counter-balance the other bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/latex/index.html&quot;&gt;my mini-tour&lt;/a&gt; for making
presentations in LaTeX with PPower4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2004-11-03</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/</link>



	<category>apple</category>

	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>latex</category>

	<category>phd</category>

	<category>studies</category>

	<category>toefl</category>

	<category>ubuntu</category>


	<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2004 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2014-01-24T06:55:36Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been quite a long time since I last wrote anything here. In
the mean time, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orkut.com/&quot;&gt;orkut&lt;/a&gt; has changed my life
(for the worse) and it seems that I&#39;m now &quot;up for adoption&quot; again.
Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.newcastle.edu.au/~nbi/&quot;&gt;Oz&lt;/a&gt; isn&#39;t that far
away. Or maybe it is. I still don&#39;t know. The last missing piece
(the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toefl.org/&quot;&gt;Test of English as a Foreign Language&lt;/a&gt;) was
completed and the only problem now is the competition for
scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2004/10/msg00325.html&quot;&gt;packaged&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-sp.iti.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de/software/ppower4/&quot;&gt;PPower4&lt;/a&gt;,
which works perfectly now with all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kaffe.org/&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sablevm.org/&quot;&gt;JVMs&lt;/a&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing/&quot;&gt;Debian&#39;s testing&lt;/a&gt;, which
means that one can depend on even less non-free software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the very reason that Free JVMs entered testing were the
reason for me to pick up &lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;. It seems to
be a nice language and the fact that it doesn&#39;t present a problem
to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; makes it a plausible
addition in my book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also patched iTunes 4.7 to work with iPod Download. The
hard-coded blacklist that Apple put in iTunes isn&#39;t nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt;, on the contrary &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;
nice. Also nice is the fact that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://texcatalogue.sarovar.org/entries/algorithms.html&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;
is now Free (and soon will be back into
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tug.org/tetex/&quot;&gt;teTeX&lt;/a&gt;, which is what ships with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;). I am happy, because this means
that my local home directory will get a tiny bit smaller, with less
cruft. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;The Global Operating System&lt;/a&gt;
even more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/faac/&quot;&gt;faac&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s package made by
Christian Marillat now works with the MP4 wrapper, which means that
now I can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://nostatic.org/grip/&quot;&gt;grip&lt;/a&gt; with AAC files for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipod/&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; and use its space in a slighlyt
more efficient manner (well, at least I hope so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, I hate daylight savings time and it seems that now I&#39;m
back in love with Elementary Number Theory. If only Elementary
Number Theory liked me...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-04-08</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-04-08/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-04-08/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>harware</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>python</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:33:23Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Basically did nothing. But my blood went to analysis and a partial
result is now available. I think that I&#39;ll have to start a diet,
cut a bit of the chocolate and start doing (physical) exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also played a tiny bit with Python. It&#39;s starting to grow on me.
I&#39;m a newbie right now, but I already found some problems where the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/doc/current/tut/tut.html&quot;&gt;Standard Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
is not entirely clear. And I also found differences of behavior
between &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;CPython&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jython.org/&quot;&gt;Jython&lt;/a&gt; regarding the &lt;code&gt;readlines()&lt;/code&gt; method
of a file object when called with an argument. Is that a bug,
perhaps? If it is, then I&#39;m surprised that nobody found it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribed to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;Tutor&lt;/a&gt; mailing list to
see if I am missing something. Cancelled some of my Yahoo!
accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sent an e-mail to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bb.com.br/&quot;&gt;my bank&lt;/a&gt; telling them
that they suck, because their site doesn&#39;t work with any of the
Linux browsers that I tried (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com/&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konqueror.org/&quot;&gt;Konqueror&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>2002-04-04</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-04-04/</guid>

	<link>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-04-04/</link>



	<category>debian</category>

	<category>free-software</category>

	<category>harware</category>

	<category>java</category>

	<category>life</category>

	<category>linux</category>

	<category>music</category>

	<category>powerpc</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2002 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-10-11T06:33:23Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;How can life change so quickly from bad to good? Amazing, ain&#39;t it?
Had a great time at my SO&#39;s place. It was nice to see her get
happier, which made &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to talk to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ime.usp.br/~jose/&quot;&gt;my advisor&lt;/a&gt;
and see that he (mostly) likes my work. Oh, how I needed those
positive, encouraging comments from him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dreamtheater.net/&quot;&gt;Dream Theater&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s bootleg at
Beacon, with the full version of &quot;Six Degrees of Inner Turbulence&quot;,
on my usual FTP server. New music. Good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE 3.0&lt;/a&gt; is finally launched. It looks
so amazing that I can&#39;t believe my eyes (err, the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://kde.org/screenshots/kde300shots.html&quot;&gt;screenshots&lt;/a&gt;). A big
plus for me is the built-in support for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webdav.org/&quot;&gt;WebDAV&lt;/a&gt;, which is used by
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mac.com/&quot;&gt;iTools&#39; iDisk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, it seems that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megadeth.com/&quot;&gt;Megadeth&lt;/a&gt;
is no more. Quite sad, as I like(d) them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openoffice.org/&quot;&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt; 641d, the last version
before the 1.0 release, is
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists2.suse.com/archive/suse-ppc/2002-Mar/0079.html&quot;&gt;already available&lt;/a&gt;
for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/ports/powerpc/&quot;&gt;PPC/Linux&lt;/a&gt;. By the way,
OpenOffice is a Free and free alternative for Microsoft&#39;s Office.
It is also available for Microsoft Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackdown.org/&quot;&gt;Blackdown&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Java
is available for Linux, including PPC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
