<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged macosx</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/macosx/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/macosx/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/macosx/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2018-04-18T11:21:46Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>2009-09-11</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-09-11/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-09-11/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="boot" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2018-04-18T11:21:14Z</updated>
	<published>2009-09-11T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Since I maintain a Darwin partition on my system, I use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/grub/grub-legacy.en.html&quot;&gt;GRUB legacy&lt;/a&gt;
to choose which OS I want to play with. But, then, due some of my
tweaking, it stopped working. Ouch. Even if I selected it, it
wouldn&#39;t boot and would return to GRUB&#39;s menu. Irritating, to say
the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being disappointed with that, I eventually,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/grub/manual/html_node/&quot;&gt;RTFM of GRUB&lt;/a&gt;
and learned a bit more about something that seems to give
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insanelymac.com/forum/index.php?showtopic=107391&quot;&gt;hackintosh&lt;/a&gt;
users some headaches: the partition bootloader being foobared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solutions presented there are bizantine from a Unix P-o-V. The
necessary steps to fix it are just to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the &lt;strong&gt;hard disk&lt;/strong&gt; bootloader (that is, the MBR
of your HD) contains GRUB&#39;s &lt;code&gt;stage 1&lt;/code&gt; loader.
&lt;em&gt;Warning:&lt;/em&gt; don&#39;t just &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; it to your HD&#39;s file, so that your
system can &quot;forget&quot; the partitions that you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the &lt;strong&gt;partition&lt;/strong&gt; bootloader (something that is
peculiar to the x86 arches and which, I as a user of other
platforms, didn&#39;t know that existed) is set to Apple&#39;s &lt;code&gt;boot1h&lt;/code&gt;.
This time, you can just &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; it to the first sector of the
partition where Darwin/MacOS X resides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach GRUB to set its snippet to run Darwin with
&lt;code&gt;root (hd0,0)&lt;/code&gt; (or whatever partition contains Darwin), tell it
to make the partition active with &lt;code&gt;makeactive&lt;/code&gt;, and tell it to load
the &lt;strong&gt;partition&lt;/strong&gt; bootloader with &lt;code&gt;chainloader +1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Edit
&lt;code&gt;/Library/Preferences/SystemConfiguration/com.apple.Boot.plist&lt;/code&gt; to
contain the elements &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;key&amp;gt;Kernel&amp;lt;/key&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;mach_kernel.foo&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to point to whatever is your
kernel of choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Optional) If you make changes under Linux, with the &lt;code&gt;hfsplus&lt;/code&gt;
module, it is highly recommended that you unmount your filesystem
and run the &lt;code&gt;fsck.hfsplus&lt;/code&gt; from the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/hfsplus&quot;&gt;hfsplus&lt;/a&gt; package that I
maintain in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; (and which is mirrored
by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, but Debian&#39;s is more
up-to-date, as I have uploads rights there).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Optional)
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hermann-uwe.de/blog/testing-stuff-with-qemu-part-3-debian-gnu-kfreebsd&quot;&gt;Test it with QEMU&lt;/a&gt;,
to see if it will work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a nice learning exercise, to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2009-09-05</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-09-05/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-09-05/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="macosx" />


	<updated>2018-04-18T11:21:46Z</updated>
	<published>2009-09-05T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Much to my delight, I received today some nice people for my
birthday. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.binoklo.com/&quot;&gt;Adriano&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s presence was nice
(and I even had the opportunity to play with his last generation
iBook G4, and fix his keyboard), my Grandma, Jacob, Mom, Dad, Rose,
and Sa made a nice birthday party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, being with Adriano is always illuminating: I
learned about a book, about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089457/&quot;&gt;a movie&lt;/a&gt;, about some MacOS X
programs that he runs, about some other concepts, about an
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldofgoo.com/&quot;&gt;independent game&lt;/a&gt; that he supported
for MacOS X and so on. Always a pleasure to talk with him.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2009-03-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-03-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2009-03-03/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="audio" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="health" />

	<category term="ipod" />

	<category term="kernel" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="mp3" />

	<category term="multimedia" />

	<category term="music" />

	<category term="perl" />

	<category term="programming" />

	<category term="study" />

	<category term="video" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T11:53:39Z</updated>
	<published>2009-03-03T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the &lt;code&gt;m3s.pl&lt;/code&gt; script made by Scott Lawrence, and given
the fact that he doesn&#39;t care anymore about it, I decided to see
what I could do so that I could generate MP3 CDs that will play
well with iTunes (like if they were regular audio CDs, but with
huge capacity and without connecting to the network to fetch
metadata).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the script could really gain some improvements
and that having it up to date has forced me to remember some Perl.
I made a lot of successful, incremental improvements by
encapsulating the code and making it reasonably readable (even with
a language that people say that is only &quot;writeable&quot;, but not
&quot;readable&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I implemented things inserting data into a hash and then using the
name of the types of the fields that have to be in the
ContentsDB.xml file to write the appropriate values, but then I saw
that what I was doing was quite silly and implemented things in an
easier, cleaner way. Taking care to have things encoded in utf-8
and escaping the &amp;amp; character when writing the XML file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original program used the &lt;code&gt;MP3::Info&lt;/code&gt; module to gather
information about the songs. This module isn&#39;t as rich as the
&lt;code&gt;MP3::Tag&lt;/code&gt; module (which is able to get track numbers, track
counts, disc numbers, and disc counts, just off the top of my
head). This &quot;new&quot; module is quite good and more flexible and that&#39;s
what I adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, to traverse the directory tree, I am using &lt;code&gt;File::Find&lt;/code&gt;,
instead of a home-brew solution to the problem. There is only one
thing left for the script to be finished: having it write correctly
the &quot;numerical path&quot;, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; likes to
call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, remembering things about references, compound data
structures, object orientation, the use of modules etc. has made me
gain some interest in Perl again. I think that I will make some
effort and learn it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I just submitted my third patch for the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/&quot;&gt;Linux kernel&lt;/a&gt;: it fixes the compilation
(and recognition) of the MTD device of the Kurobox HD that I have.
Now, I am running a brand new 2.6.29-rc6 kernel (yes, yes, it is
brand new right now, but at the breakneck pace with which the
kernel is moving, it will soon be quite outdated; I will try to
keep the powerpc part of things in shape, though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last, but not least, was the fact that I was submitted to a
biopsy (the original idea was for it to be just a colonoscopy, but
I had some inflammatory process in my elbows and some material had
to be removed for analysis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t really think that I am finished with all these health
things, but I surely made some improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I lied when I said that the biopsy thing was the last one that
I would write about. I am in the process of compressing movies with
the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://divxenc.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;divxenc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xvidenc.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;xvidenc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://h264enc.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;h264enc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; scripts to generate
videos that are appropriate for playing in some set top boxes
&lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; getting smaller files (which means that I will make my
small NAS last a little bit longer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since I discovered how to register myself on the iTunes music
store, I am downloading some German Podcasts. Will I be able to
learn some German? Well, I dearly hope so. My only grief is that I
am desperately running out of space and I will have to rethink my
backup strategy to leave some room for things to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I also played a little with MacOS X Tiger on Intel and the fact
that my e100 card didn&#39;t work with Tiger out-of-the box. I had to
use a special kernel extension for this very purpose. The only
thing that annoys me a lot is that I can trigger kernel panics with
the JaS kernel 10.4.8 in a deterministic manner. Upgrading the
kernel to 10.4.10 made my system not mount some disk images (and
even &quot;real&quot; disks, like my iPod video). I should, perhaps, try
Leopard here to see how things are structured and to see the
changes that Apple has provided to the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding some cutting-edge programs, I saw that some programs were
removed from Debian after the release of lenny, since upstream is
inactive or dead. Too bad. But the nice side of things is that
snapshot.debian.net is a terrific service to the community and I&#39;ve
compiled things from there and got excellent results. I think that
I may even create a non-official repository with some multimedia
programs (and this includes, say, a newer, multithreaded version of
mplayer and newer libraries). I think that I will submit some more
bugreports (like the Real Video files from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aduni.org/&quot;&gt;ArsDigita University&lt;/a&gt; that
can&#39;t be played).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And one last thing: (this one is really the last thing that I will
comment now) is that I finally will re-record my audio (and video)
things on digital media, so that I can preserve it without the loss
of magnetic media. This is a time-consuming activity, but I think
that it is worth the effort, especially if I use an automated setup
like Audacity&#39;s noise removal tool. Or is it better to use sox for
this task? I guess that I will have to experiment a little.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-05-20</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-20/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-05-20/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="macosx" />


	<updated>2018-04-17T09:28:48Z</updated>
	<published>2008-05-20T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Got myself a leaner
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20system&quot;&gt;operating system&lt;/a&gt;
without a heavy graphics interface: just fluxbox. This means that I
am able now to see how slow Iceweasel is, especially when switching
virtual desktops. &lt;code&gt;:-(&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also was happy to see that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/hfsprogs&quot;&gt;hfsprogs&lt;/a&gt; version 334.14-3
migrated to testing (and I wasn&#39;t expecting that---I completely
forgot about this since I&#39;m using unstable exclusively).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepared a new version of &lt;code&gt;hfsprogs&lt;/code&gt; with more support for 32-bit
architectures supported by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; and
with initial support for &lt;code&gt;amd64&lt;/code&gt;. Rhonda has been helping me a lot
understanding the infra-structure behind Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, discovered what it takes to make an Apple &quot;Universal&quot; binary:
just compile &lt;code&gt;program.c&lt;/code&gt; with the options
&lt;code&gt;-arch i386 -arch ppc -arch ppc64&lt;/code&gt; like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gcc -arch i386 -arch ppc -arch ppc64 program.c -o program
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-05-28</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-28/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-05-28/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-06-11T14:08:45Z</updated>
	<published>2005-05-28T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I have now, with the help of an oooold
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atitech.ca/&quot;&gt;ATI Mach 64 GX&lt;/a&gt; card (with only 2MB of
VRAM) gotten &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X 10.3.9&lt;/a&gt; to work
on the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everymac.com/systems/apple/powermac/stats/powermac_9500_180mp.html&quot;&gt;PowerMac&lt;/a&gt;.
I then substituted the card with an IMS Twin Turbo card that has
4MB of VRAM. It seems to work well, considering that this machine
has almost 10 years (a PeeCee normally doesn&#39;t last this much). If
I were to upgrade this machine, I would start by the following two
items (perhaps not in this order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Substitude its HD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more RAM to it. MacOS X likes a lot of RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I may get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonnettech.com/&quot;&gt;Sonnet Tech&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonnettech.com/product/tempo_trio.html&quot;&gt;Tempo Trio&lt;/a&gt;
card, which features an IDE controller, a Firewire controller and a
USB 2.0 controller in just one card. Seems like a good deal,
especially for using (faster, modern) IDE HDs, all this being able
to just use a single slot of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-04-12</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-12/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-04-12/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2014-02-19T05:52:41Z</updated>
	<published>2005-04-12T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;After installing the NewerTech G3 upgrade card into the PowerMac 9500/180MP,
I had some problems, when I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the sarge floppies would work and I eventually decided to get rid of
any traces of MacOS and installed using the woody floppies. The problem is
that the kernel 2.2.20 that comes with woody ins&#39;t able to see both PCI
buses, especially the one where the video card is sitting on. I had to grab
a kernel from testing&#39;s repository, but I don&#39;t like distribution kernels,
for they are way too bloated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note to self: when replacing the &lt;code&gt;zImage&lt;/code&gt; on the HFS boot floppy, one
has to use the vmlinux image compressed with &lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt;, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gzip -9 vmlinux
hmount /dev/fd0
hcopy vmlinux.gz :zImage
humount /dev/fd0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other image that I tried worked. But it was nice to (re)-discover how one
makes a boot floppy for an OldWorld Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; announced the next upgrade of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&lt;/a&gt;, code named &quot;Tiger&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-12-29</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-12-29/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-12-29/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="fink" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="study" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:43:13Z</updated>
	<published>2002-12-29T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been quite a while since I last updated my diary. Many things
preventing me from updating it, which is good (well, at least part
of the things are good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been working towards finishing my M.Sc. degree. It seems that the
end never comes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve also been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X&lt;/a&gt;
(Jaguar) a lot lately. In some ways, it is a nice operating system.
But the lack of a real package management system is a bad thing. I
think that I&#39;ve been spoiled by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
incredible (and clean) service. Unfortunately,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fink.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Fink&lt;/a&gt; isn&#39;t as good as Debian. And there are
quite few programs in binary form from Fink. And they don&#39;t have a
menu system like Debian&#39;s &lt;code&gt;menu&lt;/code&gt;. And they don&#39;t even have
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.windowmaker.org/&quot;&gt;Windowmaker&lt;/a&gt; available! And AUCTeX.
etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saw that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.limewire.com/&quot;&gt;Limewire&lt;/a&gt; is uploaded to
Debian&#39;s incoming repository, which is cool. Also discovered this
&lt;a href=&quot;http://muttprint.sf.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;muttprint&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package, which sounds
promising. Packaged for Debian also, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-07-17</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-17/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-17/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="portuguese" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:33:23Z</updated>
	<published>2002-07-17T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Maldita &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;! Eu os odeio! Odeio $teve
Job$. Vão começar a cobrar um rio de dinheiro pelo iTools, quero
dizer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mac.com/&quot;&gt;.Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-07-07</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-07/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hacks" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:33:23Z</updated>
	<published>2002-07-07T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Woke up quite early with that kernel panic bugging me. I read the
documentation and the fix for it was to reboot MacOS 9 (which
wasn&#39;t as simple as it should, since MacOS X apparently de-blessed
MacOS 9&#39;s System Folder). Anyway, after reusing XPostFacto, the
PowerMac booted with MacOS X! Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, seeing this OS booting on this old computer is quite cool.
Well,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=33385&amp;amp;cid=3607384&quot;&gt;apart from some severe usability problems&lt;/a&gt;
and slowness, MacOS X is an amazing operating system. The problem
is: it &lt;strong&gt;is slow&lt;/strong&gt;. It is slow with a G3 600MHz (100MHz of bus)
with 128MB of RAM and, obviously, much more so with a dual 604e
180MHz with only 64MB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, MacOS X isn&#39;t able to use both processors when it is booted
with XPostFacto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW#2, XFree86&#39;s native driver for Mach64 doesn&#39;t include support
for the XVideo extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also used the client-side of NFS and SMB on MacOS X, which is quite
easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2002-07-06</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2002-07-06/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hacks" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="macosx" />

	<category term="powerpc" />


	<updated>2013-10-11T06:33:23Z</updated>
	<published>2002-07-06T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Took the day to see how things regarding the old PowerMac
9500/180MP were with a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.debian.org/~branden/&quot;&gt;newer XFree86&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xfree86.org/&quot;&gt;XFree86 4.2&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t support the XVideo
extension for the &lt;code&gt;imst&lt;/code&gt;t adapter, which is quite a pity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that I am not able to use
&lt;a href=&quot;http://xine.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Xine&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mplayerhq.hu/&quot;&gt;Mplayer&lt;/a&gt;
to efficiently play videos on this computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see some things that make this computer slow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a modest amount of RAM for today&#39;s standards (64MB,
which is particularly little for PowerPC);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s RAM chips are in an interleaved
configuration or not;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it had a faster/better supported video card (say, like a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com/&quot;&gt;ATI&lt;/a&gt; Mach64), things would perhaps be better,
but this is just a guess. I don&#39;t know if the Mach64 sports XVideo
support under PowerPC, but perhaps the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://gatos.sf.net/&quot;&gt;Gatos&lt;/a&gt; project might help here;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea why this computer, while having a SCSI interface
and drive, is so slow while it is using the disk. I see two things:
it freezes most things the user (that&#39;s me!) whenever it is writing
(reading?) anything to (from?) the disk and the transfer speeds are
quite sloooow. I wonder if this is a problem of the Linux SCSI
infra-structure, if it is a problem of the hardware or if it is a
problem of configuration. It probably isn&#39;t a problem with Linux,
since I also see the slowness with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/&quot;&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt;
Classic (8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, just for fun, I tried to install
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&quot;&gt;MacOS X 10.1&lt;/a&gt; on this old computer.
The catch is that MacOS X can&#39;t be installed on anything this old.
Well, at least, that&#39;s what Apple says. I had to grab a copy of
MacOS 9 (in German!) just to bootstrap the system. Then, using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://eshop.macsales.com/OSXCenter/XPostFacto/&quot;&gt;XPostFacto&lt;/a&gt;, the
installation was quite smooth (and slow). But with one gotcha at
the first reboot: a kernel panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
