<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged ubuntu</title>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/ubuntu/"/>
<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/ubuntu/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Rogério Brito's Digital Junkyard</name>

</author>




<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//tags/ubuntu/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Rogério Brito&#39;s Digital Junkyard</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2017-11-06T07:16:54Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Comparison of JDK installation of various Linux distributions</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-02_java_install_in_various_linuxes/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2017-11-02_java_install_in_various_linuxes/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T06:28:31Z</updated>
	<published>2017-11-03T01:13:56Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Today I spent some time in the morning seeing how one would install the JDK
on Linux distributions. This is to create a little comparative tutorial to
teach introductory Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing the JDK is, thanks to the OpenJDK developers in Debian and Ubuntu
(Matthias Klose and helpers), a very easy task. You simply type something
like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install openjdk-8-jdk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since for a student it is better to have everything for experiments, I
install the &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/openjdk-8-jdk&quot;&gt;full version&lt;/a&gt;, not only the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/openjdk-8-jdk-headless&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;-headless&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; version. Given my familiarity with
Debian/Ubuntu, I didn&#39;t have to think about the way of installing it, of
course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as this is a tutorial meant to be as general as I can, I tried also to
include instructions on how to install Java on other distributions. The
first two that came to my mind were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfedora.org/&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both use the RPM package format for their &quot;native&quot; packages (in the same
sense that Debian uses DEB packages for &quot;native&quot; packages). But they use
different higher-level tools to install such packages: Fedora uses a tool
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/DNF&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dnf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, while openSUSE uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Zypper_usage&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;zypper&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To try these distributions, I got their netinstall ISOs and used
&lt;code&gt;qemu&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;kvm&lt;/code&gt; to install on a virtual machine. I used the following to
install/run the virtual machines (the example below, is, of course, for openSUSE):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;qemu-system-x86_64 -enable-kvm -m 4096 -smp 2 -net nic,model=e1000 -net user -drive index=0,media=disk,cache=unsafe,file=suse.qcow2 -cdrom openSUSE-Leap-42.3-NET-x86_64.iso
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The names of the packages also change from one distribution to another. On
Fedora, I had to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;dnf install java-1.8.0-openjdk-devel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On openSUSE, I had to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;zypper install java-1_8_0-openjdk-devel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that one distribution uses dots in the names of the packages while the
other uses underscores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing that I noticed with &lt;code&gt;dnf&lt;/code&gt; was that, when I used it, it
automatically refreshed the package lists from the network, something which
I forgot, and it was a pleasant surprise. I don&#39;t know about &lt;code&gt;zypper&lt;/code&gt;, but I
guess that it probably had fresh indices when the installation finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both installations were effortless after I knew the names of the packages to
install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, in my 5 minute exploration with these distributions, I noticed that
if you don&#39;t want the JDK, but only the JRE, then you omit the &lt;code&gt;-devel&lt;/code&gt;
suffix.  It makes sense when you think about it, for consistency with other
packages, but Debian&#39;s conventions also make sense (JRE with &lt;code&gt;-jre&lt;/code&gt; suffix,
JDK with &lt;code&gt;-jdk&lt;/code&gt; suffix).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I failed miserably to use Fedora&#39;s prebaked, vanilla
&lt;a href=&quot;https://alt.fedoraproject.org/cloud/&quot;&gt;cloud image&lt;/a&gt;, as I couldn&#39;t login on this image and I decided
to just install the whole OS on a fresh virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have instructions on how to install on &lt;a href=&quot;https://getfedora.org/&quot;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt; nor on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now see how hard it is to cover instructions/provide software for as many
distributions as you wish, given the multitude of package managers,
conventions etc.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Miscellanea</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-14_miscellanea/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2014-02-14_miscellanea/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="ffmpeg" />

	<category term="libav" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2014-02-19T05:52:57Z</updated>
	<published>2014-02-15T02:59:22Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;h1 id=&quot;initsystem&quot;&gt;Init system&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy that Debian&#39;s Technical Committee was able to reach a very good
decision with the choice of systemd as the default init system for the Linux
ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I was very pleasantly surprised by the lucidity of Russ
Allbery&#39;s analyses and, above all, his &lt;em&gt;patience&lt;/em&gt; even with people that, in
my understanding, were just being trolls or trying to cause confusion and
disrupt a process that was already chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russ, thank you for your exemplary role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also, you type fast or what? You fill whole e-mails seemingly faster than I
can read!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unexpectedunionofforces&quot;&gt;Unexpected union of forces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that Mark Shutterworth&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/1316&quot;&gt;decision&lt;/a&gt; of (perhaps?)
embracing Debian&#39;s decision in the init system is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that one way where Ubuntu did a great thing with respect to Debian
was their initial attitude towards cherry-picking the best of breed of Free
Software from Debian&#39;s archive and polishing that to create a really &quot;for
human beings&quot; operating system.  I hope that this means that, at least in
part, money (Mark&#39;s?) can be channeled in the best of the interests so that
we all gain from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And, to be honest, I see no problem in making money with Free Software and
I welcome a well done integration job).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;morepolarizingthings&quot;&gt;More polarizing things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that, now, I may even have some hope of sending another
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.debian.org/729203&quot;&gt;potentially polarizing&lt;/a&gt; bug to the Tech Ctte (that is ffmpeg vs. libav)
and have faith that some rational decision would be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not even aware of it, but the ffmpeg folks even
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ffmpeg.org/&quot;&gt;featured a news item in their page&lt;/a&gt; of me having filed the RFP bug
mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;debconf14&quot;&gt;DebConf 14&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes as expected, I hope to attend this year&#39;s DebConf.  In
fact, I am anticipating this, since I would love to, e.g., talk with Joey
Hess and discuss a better way of having &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/parallel/&quot;&gt;GNU parallel&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;parallel&lt;/code&gt;
program in &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/moreutils&quot;&gt;moreutils&lt;/a&gt; have amicable co-installability among many,
many other things with respect to my packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, quite probably, work on packaging ffmpeg with other interested people
(which seem to be numerous).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Fix markdown link pointing twice to the ffmpeg site. Thanks
Marius Gedminas for pointing this out.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Lack of cooperation from Ubuntu?</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/lack_of_cooperation_from_ubuntu/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/lack_of_cooperation_from_ubuntu/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="kfreebsd" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2013-06-05T08:25:51Z</updated>
	<published>2013-04-20T01:46:26Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/117659222649141007981/posts/C2vY4nD4CD6&quot;&gt;posted the following on Google+&lt;/a&gt;, but it is important enough to be
reproduced on Planet. I&#39;m editing it a bit, as it is a followup to my
previous post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;http://cynic.cc/blog/posts/debian_activities/&quot;&gt;improving the packaging of MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;, there was one thing that
caught my attention: that Ubuntu
&lt;a href=&quot;http://changelogs.ubuntu.com/changelogs/pool/universe/m/mongodb/mongodb_2.0.4-1ubuntu2.1/changelog&quot;&gt;had already done some of the embedded/convenience libraries work&lt;/a&gt;, but
they had &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; pushed that work to Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, discovered this only after I started working on the improvements
of the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What gives, Ubuntu people?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I saw is that
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/mongodb/1:2.2.4-0ubuntu1/+build/4470136&quot;&gt;they have patches enabling mongodb working on armhf&lt;/a&gt;. Again, they did
&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; push those to Debian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why this lack of cooperation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I saw is that they had packages for version 2.2 (more
precisely, &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.ubuntu.com/raring/mongodb&quot;&gt;raring has 1:2.2.4-0ubuntu1&lt;/a&gt;), while Debian sid
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/changelogs/pool/main/m/mongodb/mongodb_2.4.1-2/changelog.html&quot;&gt;just had 2.0&lt;/a&gt; until very recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why not push this work and avoid duplication of work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By being a good downstream, I intend to push some of the patches to MongoDB
upstream (if they want it), so that we (Debian) have a smaller delta. This
will benefit you Ubuntu guys. Why not join forces and help have a
world-class set of packages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, be good netizens and share the work that you have.  I firmly believe
that the armhf people will be happy to have one of the fancy &quot;cloud&quot;
software available on ARM, especially since the prospects of having ARM
machines on datacenters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, just for the record, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rbrito/mongo-debian/pull/2&quot;&gt;kFreeBSD people have sent their contribution&lt;/a&gt; and I would love to see
(if possible) this running on the HURD.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>My problems with Chromium</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/problems_with_chromium/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/problems_with_chromium/"/>






	<category term="browsers" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="extensions" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="launchpad" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2014-02-15T02:21:28Z</updated>
	<published>2011-02-26T14:55:06Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Given that Chromium/Chrome is used more and more (as became apparent
&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.debian.org/debian-release/2010/09/msg00610.html&quot;&gt;with the discussion of including it in Debian&#39;s squeeze&lt;/a&gt;), I decided to
give it some tries, mainly Giuseppe Iuculano&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.qa.debian.org/c/chromium-browser.html&quot;&gt;version&lt;/a&gt;. I occasionally
install Chromium from Fabien Tassin&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~chromium-daily/+archive/ppa&quot;&gt;daily builds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, to be honest, I have also contributed a good amount (about 400) of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~rbrito/+karma&quot;&gt;translated strings&lt;/a&gt; to the Brazilian Portuguese part of Chromium. As a
matter of fact, I have even done some &quot;activism&quot; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~savanabifulco&quot;&gt;incentivated&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~bifulcojunior&quot;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/~victor.westmann/+karma&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; to create their accounts on Launchpad and help with
the projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I always come back to Iceweasel/Firefox, especially with Mike Hommey&#39;s
frequently updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://mozilla.debian.net/&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are my reasons for staying with Iceweasel, and not with Chromium?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can disable full zoom in Iceweasel (i.e., I only want to zoom the text,
not the images). According to Chromium&#39;s project BTS, it seems that this
will be a &lt;code&gt;WONTFIX&lt;/code&gt; bug, despite many people asking for it (and it having
a lot of duplicates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can, in Iceweasel, set my preferred fonts without resorting to hacks on
the system level, like say, having to lie with fontconfig or other stuff.
And I really want Deja Vu Sans, not a serifed font.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, a middle mouse click on &quot;an inactive portion&quot; of the page
makes me go to the URL that is the system clipboard, just like pasting
stuff in X, in general, works.  I guess that there may be some way to
enable this in Chromium, but, so far, I have not found it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I have a way (without resorting to many extensions or
hackish solutions) to use the equivalent of Firefox&#39;s &quot;View &gt; Page Style &gt;
No Style&quot; (i.e., to ignore any CSS sheet that the document author may have
specified on the page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, my personal data is encrypted before being synced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Iceweasel, I can press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Q&lt;/code&gt; and make the damn browser quit, instead
of me having to use the mouse/trackpad/pointing device. This is probably a
lack of my understanding on how to associate key bindings to Chromium, but
the problem still stands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, when there is only one tab open, pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+W&lt;/code&gt; in Chromium
does not close the tab (say, presenting me a blank tab or the list of most
visited sites), nor it closes the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be satisfied if any of the above were fixed or better documented,
but it seems that some of those are, at best, going to wait a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2008-04-30</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-30/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2008-04-30/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="hardware" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="powerpc" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2017-11-06T07:16:54Z</updated>
	<published>2008-04-30T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Upgraded my parent&#39;s computer from
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s Feisty (7.10) to Hardy (8.04).
Now, some of the things that I&#39;m used to when using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s sid are available on their
computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, I can&#39;t avoid to use this opportunity to complain once more
about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flash.net.br/&quot;&gt;ISP&lt;/a&gt;. If I weren&#39;t doing the
upgrade &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; early in the morning, I wouldn&#39;t have success,
as I am (right now), without signal from them. These outages are
getting on my nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some math related news, I finally saw a proof of the intuitive
fact the determinant of a 2x2 matrix is the signed area of the
parallelogram with vectors given by the column vectors of the
matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my D-Link G122 (I think that that&#39;s the model) doesn&#39;t work
with the &lt;code&gt;rt2500usb&lt;/code&gt; driver that ships with the distribution: I can
see that &lt;code&gt;iwconfig&lt;/code&gt; lists &lt;code&gt;wlan0&lt;/code&gt; as having wireless extensions, I
can set the device, it can see the access point, I can enter the
WEP key, but it doesn&#39;t seem to get a DHCP lease from the router.
&lt;code&gt;:-(&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Debian Switching to EGLIBC</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/debian-switching-to-eglibc/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/debian-switching-to-eglibc/"/>






	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="embedded" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2007-05-08T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Having been playing with some new things in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, like the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/magicfilter&quot;&gt;magicfilter&lt;/a&gt; package, which is a superb, lightweight solution to
all my printing problems: to use a PCL 3 printer. I think that I will also
&quot;manufacture&quot; a solution with a metapackage of a live CD that includes the
environment that I use frequently, with the packages that I use (this is
probably quite leaner than what &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; has done with their
distribution, since I will mainly use some lighter packages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, talking about lighter packages, I see that Debian has adopted a new C
library, namely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eglibc.org/&quot;&gt;EGLIBC&lt;/a&gt;, which stands for Embedded LIBC. Finally, it
seems that Debian will focus a bit more on smaller systems (which is a good
thing, because computing resources are limited).&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Playing with Package Proxies</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/playing-with-package-proxies/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/playing-with-package-proxies/"/>






	<category term="approx" />

	<category term="apt-move" />

	<category term="computers" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="embedded" />

	<category term="linux" />

	<category term="proxy" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2012-09-07T06:54:06Z</updated>
	<published>2007-03-16T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Have been playing with the great idea of &lt;a
href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2009/03/msg00210.html&quot;&gt;caching&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/Articles/318658/&quot;&gt;deb&lt;/a&gt; packages. I finally
settled for the option of using &lt;code&gt;&lt;a
href=&quot;http://git.debian.org/?p=pkg-ocaml-maint/packages/approx.git&quot;&gt;approx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;,
which does a really nice job of caching packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it fullfils quite a lot of requirements and even surpasses some of my expectations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It supports multiple architectures (in fact, this is important for me, as
I use &lt;code&gt;i386&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;amd64&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;powerpc&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can support multiple distributions (both different versions of the same
distribution and completely different distributions, as long as they use a
repository like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s, as is the
case of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It keeps its directory hierarchy neatly organized, like that of Debian, in
a package pool, which saves space and makes everything easier and faster
to find (and has the advantage of being fast with filesystems that don&#39;t
cope well with many entries in one directory).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition wasn&#39;t painless from &lt;a href=&quot;http://packages.debian.org/apt%2Dmove&quot;&gt;apt-move&lt;/a&gt;, since apt-move
moves the files, but renames them in a way that they don&#39;t keep epochs in
their names, which makes &lt;code&gt;approx-import&lt;/code&gt; moan about the packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For places where I am too lazy to import the packages, I just filled the
cache redownloading the packages with something approximately like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  apt-get -d --reinstall install &amp;#036;(dpkg -l | grep &quot;^ii&quot; | cut -d &quot; &quot; -f 3)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I hope that this experience happens to be useful for other people, so
that they can benefit from it. Rebuilding packages with a package cacher is
much more pleasant, especially if the package has a lot of
build-dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2006-03-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2006-03-03/"/>






	<category term="data-structures" />

	<category term="life" />

	<category term="math" />

	<category term="teaching" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2017-07-14T18:26:00Z</updated>
	<published>2006-03-03T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;One good thing to have in mind is that when one is minimally
serious about data structures, then on covering the topic of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table&quot;&gt;hash tables&lt;/a&gt;, it is a
quite good chance to talk about the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birthday_paradox&quot;&gt;&quot;birthday paradox&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.
In the analogy, each day would correspond to a slot in the hash
table and each person would correspond to an item to be inserted
into the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one takes this into account, the analysis of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birthday_paradox#Collision_counting&quot;&gt;collisions&lt;/a&gt;
is meaninful from a probabilistic point of view, which matters a
lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the subject a little, in a replacement that lasted, say,
15 minutes (tops), the cable modem is back again working, which
means that playing with &lt;a href=&quot;http://lartc.org/&quot;&gt;tunneling&lt;/a&gt; under
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kernel.org/&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; (especially, using the IPSec
interface) is back again a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it seems that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntulinux.org&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/releases&quot;&gt;dapper&lt;/a&gt; is &quot;mom proof&quot;.
Well, at least, she has been learning to use it with some hiccups,
but, then, personal computers aren&#39;t things with which she plays
everyday. She was surprised to know about
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikipedia.org/&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and its broad coverage. And,
indeed, it is superb.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2005-10-13</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-10-13/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2005-10-13/"/>






	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2015-01-18T00:40:53Z</updated>
	<published>2005-10-13T03:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/download/&quot;&gt;breezy&lt;/a&gt; was released today!
Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2004-11-03</title>

	<id>http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/</id>

	<link href="http://cynic.cc/blog//posts/2004-11-03/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="debian" />

	<category term="free-software" />

	<category term="java" />

	<category term="latex" />

	<category term="phd" />

	<category term="studies" />

	<category term="toefl" />

	<category term="ubuntu" />


	<updated>2014-01-24T06:55:36Z</updated>
	<published>2004-11-03T02:00:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been quite a long time since I last wrote anything here. In
the mean time, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orkut.com/&quot;&gt;orkut&lt;/a&gt; has changed my life
(for the worse) and it seems that I&#39;m now &quot;up for adoption&quot; again.
Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.newcastle.edu.au/~nbi/&quot;&gt;Oz&lt;/a&gt; isn&#39;t that far
away. Or maybe it is. I still don&#39;t know. The last missing piece
(the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toefl.org/&quot;&gt;Test of English as a Foreign Language&lt;/a&gt;) was
completed and the only problem now is the competition for
scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.debian.org/debian-mentors/2004/10/msg00325.html&quot;&gt;packaged&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-sp.iti.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de/software/ppower4/&quot;&gt;PPower4&lt;/a&gt;,
which works perfectly now with all the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kaffe.org/&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sablevm.org/&quot;&gt;JVMs&lt;/a&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/releases/testing/&quot;&gt;Debian&#39;s testing&lt;/a&gt;, which
means that one can depend on even less non-free software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the very reason that Free JVMs entered testing were the
reason for me to pick up &lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;. It seems to
be a nice language and the fact that it doesn&#39;t present a problem
to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;Free Software&lt;/a&gt; makes it a plausible
addition in my book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also patched iTunes 4.7 to work with iPod Download. The
hard-coded blacklist that Apple put in iTunes isn&#39;t nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt;, on the contrary &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;
nice. Also nice is the fact that
&lt;a href=&quot;http://texcatalogue.sarovar.org/entries/algorithms.html&quot;&gt;algorithms&lt;/a&gt;
is now Free (and soon will be back into
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tug.org/tetex/&quot;&gt;teTeX&lt;/a&gt;, which is what ships with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;). I am happy, because this means
that my local home directory will get a tiny bit smaller, with less
cruft. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;The Global Operating System&lt;/a&gt;
even more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://sf.net/projects/faac/&quot;&gt;faac&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s package made by
Christian Marillat now works with the MP4 wrapper, which means that
now I can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://nostatic.org/grip/&quot;&gt;grip&lt;/a&gt; with AAC files for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ipod/&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; and use its space in a slighlyt
more efficient manner (well, at least I hope so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, BTW, I hate daylight savings time and it seems that now I&#39;m
back in love with Elementary Number Theory. If only Elementary
Number Theory liked me...&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
